<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1539" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">THE <lb/>CONSTITUTION <lb/>OF <lb/>CONFEDERATE STATES OF AMERICA</head>
<byline>MARCH 11, 1861.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1861</byline>
<pb n="1540" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="1541" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">CONSTITUTION <lb/>OF THE <lb/>CONFEDERATE STATES OF AMERICA.</head>
<p>We, the People of the Confederate States, each State acting in its sovereign and independent character, in order to form a perma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent Federal Government, establish justice, insure domestic tran<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quility, and secure the blessings of Liberty to ourselves and our posterity&#8212;invoking the favor and guidance of Almighty God&#8212;do ordain and establish this Constitution for the Confederate States of America:</p>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE I.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>All legislative powers herein delegated shall be vested in a Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress of the Confederate States, which shall consist of a Senate and House of Representatives.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION II.</head>
<p>1. The House of Representatives shall be composed of members chosen every second year by the people of the several States; and the electors in each State shall be citizens of the Confederate States, and have the qualifications requisite for electors of the most numer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous branch of the State Legislature; but no person of foreign birth, not a citizen of the Confederate States, shall be allowed to vote for any officer, civil or political, State or Federal.</p>
<p>2. No person shall be a Representative, who shall not have attained the age of twenty-five years, and be a citizen of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, and who shall not, when elected, be an inhabitant of that State in which he shall be chosen.</p>
<p>3. Representatives and direct taxes shall be apportioned among the several States which may be included within this Confederacy, according to their respective numbers, which shall be determined by adding to the whole number of free persons, including those bound to service for a term of years, and excluding Indians not taxed, three-fifths of all slaves. The actual enumeration shall be made <pb n="1542" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>within three years after the first meeting of the Congress of the Confederate States, and within every subsequent term of ten years, in such manner as they shall, by law, direct. The number of Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives shall not exceed one for every fifty thousand, but each State shall have, at least, one Representative; and until such enum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eration shall be made, the State of South Carolina shall be entitled to choose six; the State of Georgia ten; the State of Alabama nine; the State of Florida two; the State of Mississippi seven; the State of Louisiana six, and the State of Texas six.</p>
<p>When vacancies happen in the representation from any State, the Executive authority thereof shall issue writs of election to fill such vacancies.</p>
<p>5. The House of Representatives shall choose their Speaker and other officers; and shall have the sole power of impeachment; ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept that any judicial or other federal officer resident and acting solely within the limits of any State, may be impeached by a vote of two-thirds of both branches of the Legislature thereof.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION III.</head>
<p>1. The Senate of the Confederate States shall be composed of two Senators from each State, chosen for six years, by the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature thereof, at the regular session next immediately preceding the commencement of the term of service; and each Senator shall have one vote.</p>
<p>2. Immediately after they shall be asembled in consequence of the first election, they shall be divided, as equally as may be, into three classes. The seats of the Senators of the first class shall be vacated at the expiration of the second year, of the second class at the expiration of the fourth, and of the third class at the expiration of the sixth year, so that one-third may be chosen every second year; and if vacancies happen, by resignation or otherwise, during the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess of the Legislature of any State, the Executive thereof may make temporary appointments until the next meeting of the Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, which shall then fill such vacancies.</p>
<p>3. No person shall be a Senator who shall not have attained the age of thirty years, and be a citizen of the Confederate States, and who shall not, when elected, be an inhabitant of the State for which he shall be chosen.</p>
<p>4. The Vice-President of the Confederate States shall be Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent of the Senate, but shall have no vote, unless they be equally divided.</p>
<p>5. The Senate shall choose their other officers, and also a Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent pro tempore, in the absence of the Vice-President, or when he shall exercise the office of President of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>6. The Senate shall have the sole power to try all impeach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments. When sitting for that purpose, they shall be on oath or <pb n="1543" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>affirmation. When the President of the Confederate States is tried, the Chief Justice shall preside; and no person shall be convicted without the concurrence of two-thirds of the members present.</p>
<p>7. Judgment, in cases of impeachment, shall not extend further than to removal from office, and disqualification to hold and enjoy any office of honor, trust, or profit under the Confederate States; but the party convicted shall nevertheless be liable and subject to indictment, trial, judgment, and punishment, according to law.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION IV.</head>
<p>1. The times, places, and manner of holding elections for Sena<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors and Representatives shall be prescribed in each State by the Legislature thereof, subject to the provisions of this Constitution; but the Congress may, at any time by law, make or alter such regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lations, except as to the times and places of choosing Senators.</p>
<p>2. The Congress shall assemble at least once in every year, and such meeting shall be on the first Monday in December, unless they shall by law appoint a different day.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION V.</head>
<p>1. Each House shall be the judge of the elections, returns, and qualifications of its own members, and a majority of each shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a quorum to do business; but a smaller number may adjourn from day to day, and may be authorized to compel the attendance of absent members, in such manner and under such penalties as each House may provide.</p>
<p>2. Each House may determine the rules of its proceedings, pun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ish its members for disorderly behavior, and, with the concurrence of two-thirds of the whole number, expel a member.</p>
<p>3. Each House shall keep a journal of its proceedings, and from time to time publish the same, excepting such parts as may, in their judgment, require secrecy; and the yeas and nays of the members of either House on any question shall, at the desire of one-fifth of those present, be entered on the journal.</p>
<p>4. Neither House, during the session of Congress, shall, without the consent of the other, adjourn for more than three days, nor to any other place than that in which the two Houses may be sitting.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION VI.</head>
<p>1. The Senators and Representatives shall receive a compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for their services, to be ascertained by law, and paid out of the Treasury of the Confederate States. They shall in all cases, except treason, felony, and breach of the peace, be privileged from ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rest during their attendance at the session of their respective <pb n="1544" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>Houses, and in going to and returning from the same; and for any speech or debate in either House, they shall not be questioned in any other place.</p>
<p>2. No Senator or Representative shall, during the time for which he was elected, be appointed to any civil office under the authority of the Confederate States, which shall have been created, or the emoluments whereof shall have been increased, during such time; and no person holding any office under the Confederate States shall be a member of either House during his continuance in office; but Congress may by law grant to the principal officer in each of the Executive Departments a seat upon the floor of either House, with the privilege of discussing any measures appertaining to his department.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION VII.</head>
<p>1. All bids for raising revenue shall originate in the House of Representatives; but the Senate may propose or concur with amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, as on other bills.</p>
<p>2. Every bill which shall have passed both Houses, shall, before it becomes a law, be presented to the President of the Confederate States; if he approve, he shall sign it; but if not, he shall return it, with his objections, to that House in which it shall have originated, who shall enter the objections at large on their journal, and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to reconsider it. If, after such reconsideration, two-thirds of that House shall agree to pass the bill, it shall be sent, together with the objections, to the other House, by which it shall likewise be reconsidered, and if approved by two-thirds of that House, it shall become a law. But in all such cases the votes of both Houses shall be determined by yeas and nays, and the names of the persons voting for and against the bill shall be entered on the journal of each House respectively. If any bill shall not be returned by the President within ten days (Sundays excepted) after it shall have been presented to him, the same shall be a law in like manner as if he had signed it, unless the Congress by their adjournment prevent its return, in which case it shall not be a law. The President may approve any appropriation and disapprove any other appropriation in the same bill. In such case he shall, in signing the bill, desig<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate the appropriations disapproved; and shall return a copy of such appropriations, with his objections, to the House in which the bill shall have originated; and the same proceedings shall then be had as in case of other bills disapproved by the President.</p>
<p>3. Every order, resolution, or vote, to which the concurrence of both Houses may be necessary, (except on a question of adjourn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment,) shall be presented to the President of the Confederate States; and before the same shall take effect, shall be approved by <pb n="1545" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>him, or, being disapproved by him, shall be re-passed by two-thirds of both Houses, according to the rules and limitations prescribed in the case of a bill.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION VIII.</head>
<p>The Congress shall have power&#8212;</p>
<p>1. To lay and collect taxes, duties, imposts, and excises, for reve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nue necessary to pay the debts, provide for the common defence and carry on the Government of the Confederate States; but no bounties shall be granted from the Treasury, nor shall any duties or taxes on importations from foreign nations be laid to promote or foster any branch of industry; and all duties, imposts and excises shall be uniform throughout the Confederate States.</p>
<p>2. To borrow money on the credit of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>3. To regulate commerce with foreign nations, and among the several States, and with the Indain tribes; but neither this nor any other clause contained in the Constitution shall ever be construed to delegate the power to Congress to appropriate money for any internal improvement, intended to facilitate commerce, except for the purpose of furnishing lights, beacons and buoys, and other aids to navigation upon the coasts, and the improvement of harbors and the removing of obstructions in river navigation; in all which cases such duties shall be laid on the navigation facilitated thereby, as may be necessary to pay the costs and expenses thereof.</p>
<p>4. To establish uniform laws of naturalization, and uniform laws on the subject of bankruptcies, throughout the Confederate States; but no law of Congress shall discharge any debt contracted before the passage of the same.</p>
<p>5. To coin money, regulate the value thereof, and of foreign coin, and fix the standard of weights and measures.</p>
<p>6. To provide for the punishment of counterfeiting the securi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties and current coin of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>7. To establish post-offices and post-roads; but the expenses of the Post-Office Department, after the first day of March, in the year of our Lord eighteen hundred and sixty-three, shall be paid out of its own revenues.</p>
<p>8. To promote the progress of science and useful arts, by secur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing for limited times to authors and inventors, the exclusive right to their respective writings and discoveries.</p>
<p>9. To constitute tribunals inferior to the Supreme Court.</p>
<p>10. To define and punish piracies and felonies committed on the high seas, and offences against the law of nations.</p>
<p>11. To declare war, grant letters of marque and reprisal, and make rules concerning captures on land and water.</p>
<p>12. To raise and support armies; but no appropriation of money to that use shall be for a longer term than two years.</p>
<p>13. To provide and maintain a navy.</p>
<pb n="1546" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>
<p>14. To make rules for the government and regulation of the land and naval forces.</p>
<p>15. To provide for calling forth the militia to execute the laws of the Confederate States, suppress insurrections and repel inva<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions.</p>
<p>16. To provide for organizing, arming, and disciplining the militia, and for governing such part of them as may be employed in the service of the Confederate States, reserving to the States re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spectively the appointment of the officers and the authority of train<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the militia according to the discipline prescribed by Congress.</p>
<p>17. To exercise exclusive legislation, in all cases whatsoever, over such district (not exceeding ten miles square) as may, by ces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of one or more States and the acceptance of Congress, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come the seat of Government of the Confederate States; and to exercise like authority over all places purchased, by the consent of the Legislature of the State in which the same shall be, for the erection of forts, magazines, arsenals, dockyards, and other needful buildings: and,</p>
<p>18. To make all laws which shall be necessary and proper for carrying into execution the foregoing powers, and all other powers vested by this Constitution in the Government of the Confederate States, or in any department or officer thereof.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION IX.</head>
<p>1. The importation of negroes of the African race from any foreign country other than the slaveholding States or Territories of the United States of America, is hereby forbidden, and Congress is required to pass such laws as shall effectually prevent the same.</p>
<p>2. Congress shall also have power to prohibit the introduction of slaves from any State not a member of, or Territory not be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing to, this Confederacy.</p>
<p>3. The privilege of the writ of habeas corpus shall not be sus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pended, unless, when in cases of rebellion or invasion, the public safety may require it.</p>
<p>4. No bill of attainder, ex post facto law, or law denying or im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pairing the right of property in negro slaves, shall be passed.</p>
<p>5. No capitation or other direct tax shall be laid, unless in proportion to the census or enumeration hereinbefore directed to be taken.</p>
<p>6. No tax or duty shall be laid on articles exported from any State except by a vote of two-thirds of both Houses.</p>
<p>7. No preference shall be given by any regulation of commerce or revenue to the ports of one State over those of another.</p>
<p>8. No money shall be drawn from the treasury, but in conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quence of appropriations made by law; and a regular statement and <pb n="1547" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>account of the receipts and expenditures of all public money shall be published from time to time.</p>
<p>9. Congress shall appropriate no money from the Treasury ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept by a vote of two-thirds of both Houses, taken by yeas and nays, unless it be asked and estimated for by some one of the Heads of Department and submitted to Congress by the President; or for the purpose of paying its Own expenses and contingencies; or for the payment of claims against the Confederate States, the justice of which shall have been judicially declared by a tribunal for the investigation of claims against the Government, which it is hereby made the duty of Congress to establish.</p>
<p>10. All bills appropriating money, shall specify, in Federal cur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rency, the exact amount of each appropriation, and the purposes for which it is made, and Congress shall grant no extra compensation to any public contractor, officer, agent or servant after such con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract shall have been made, or such service rendered.</p>
<p>11. No title of nobility shall be granted by the Confederate States; and no person holding any office of profit or trust under them, shall, without the consent of the Congress, accept of any present, emolument, office, or title of any kind whatever, from any king, prince, or foreign State.</p>
<p>12. Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or the press; or the right of the people peaceably to assemble and petition the Government for a redress of grievances.</p>
<p>13. A well regulated militia being necessary to the security of a free State, the right of the people to keep and bear arms shall not be infringed.</p>
<p>14. No soldier shall, in time of peace, be quartered in any house, without the consent of the owner; nor in time of war, but in a man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner to be prescribed by law.</p>
<p>15. The right of the people to be secure in their persons, houses, papers and effects, against unreasonable searches and seizures, shall not be violated, and no warrant shall issue, but upon probable cause, supported by oath or affirmation, and particularly describing the place to be searched, and the persons or things to be seized.</p>
<p>16. No person shall be held to answer for a capital or other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise infamous crime, unless on a presentment or indictment of a grand jury, except in cases arising in the land or naval forces, or in the militia, when in actual service in time of war or public danger; nor shall any person be subject for the same offence to be twice put in jeopardy of life or limb; nor be compelled in any criminal case to be a witness against himself, nor be deprived of life, liberty or property without due process of law; nor shall private property be taken for public use, without just compensation.</p>
<pb n="1548" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>
<p>17. In all criminal prosecutions, the accused shall enjoy the right to a speedy and public trial, by an impartial jury of the State and district wherein the crime shall have been committed, which district shall have been previously ascertained by law, and to be in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />formed of the nature and cause of the accusation; to be confronted with the witness against him; to have compulsory process for ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />taining witnesses in his favor, and to have the assistance of counsel for his defence.</p>
<p>18. In suits at common law, where the value in controversy shall exceed twenty dollars, the right of trial by jury shall be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />served, and no fact so tried by a jury shall be otherwise re-examined in any court of the Confederacy than according to the rules of the common law.</p>
<p>19. Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed, nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted.</p>
<p>20. Every law, or resolution having the force of law, shall relate to but one subject, and that shall be expressed in the title.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION X.</head>
<p>1. No State shall enter into any treaty, alliance or confedera<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion; grant letters of marque and reprisal; coinmoney; make any<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thing but gold and silver coin a tender in payment of debts; pass any bill of attainder, ex post facto law, or law impairing the obli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gation of contracts; or grant any title of nobility.</p>
<p>2. No State shall, without the consent of Congress, lay any imposts or duties on imports or exports, except what may be abso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lutely necessary for executing its inspection laws; and the net pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duce of all duties and imposts, laid by any State on imposts or ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ports, shall be for the use of the Treasury of the Confederate States; and all such laws shall be subject to the revision and control of Congress.</p>
<p>3. No State shall, without the consent of Congress, lay any duty on tonnage, except on sea-going vessels, for the improvement of its rivers and harbors, navigated by the said vessels; but such duties shall not conflict with any treaties of the Confederate States with foreign nations; and any surplus revenue thus derived shall, after making such improvement, be paid into the common treasury; nor shall any State keep troops or ships of war in time of peace, enter into any agreement or compact with another State or with a foreign power, or engage in war unless actually invaded, or in such immi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nent danger as will not admit of delay; but when any river divides or flows through two or more States, they may enter into compacts with each other to improve the navigation thereof.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1549" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE II.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>1. The Executive power shall be vested in a President of the Confederate States of America. He and the Vice-President shall hold their offices for the term of six years; but the President shall not be re-eligible. The President and Vice-President shall be elected as follows:</p>
<p>2. Each State shall appoint, in such manner as the Legislature thereof may direct, a number of electors, equal to the whole number of Senators and Representatives to which the State may be entitled in the Congress; but no Senator or Representative, or person holding an office of trust or profit under the Confederate States, shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed an elector.</p>
<p>3. The electors shall meet in their respective States and vote by ballot for President and Vive-President, one of whom at least shall not be an inhabitant of the same State with themselves. They shall name in their ballots the person voted for as President, and in dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinct ballots the person voted for as Vice-President, and they shall make distinct lists of all persons voted for as President, and of all persons voted for as Vice-President, and of the number of votes for each, which lists they shall sign and certify and transmit, sealed, to the seat of Government of the Confederate States, directed to the President of the Senate. The President of the Senate shall, in the presence of the Senate and House of Representatives, open all the certificates, and the votes shall then be counted; the person having the greatest number of votes for President shall be the President, if such number be a majority of the whole number of electors ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed, and if no person have such majority, then from the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons having the highest numbers not exceeding three on the list of those voted for as President, the House of Representatives shall choose immediately by ballot the President. But in choosing the President the votes shall be taken by States, the representation from each State having one vote. A quorum for this purpose shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sist of a member or members from two-thirds of the States, and a majority of all the States shall be necessary to a choice; and if the House of Representatives shall not choose a President, whenever the right of choice shall devolve upon them, before, the fourth day of March next following, then the Vice-President shall act as Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent as in case of the death or other constitutional disability of the President.</p>
<p>4. The person having the greatest number of votes as Vice<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />President shall be the Vice-President, if such number be a majority of the whole number of electors appointed; and if no person have a majority, then from the two highest numbers on the list the Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1550" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>ate shall choose the Vice-President. A quorum for the purpose shall consist of two-thirds of the whole number of Senators, and a majority of the whole number shall be necessary to a choice.</p>
<p>5. But no person constitutionally ineligible to the office of Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident shall be eligible to that of Vice-President of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>6. The Congress may determine the time of choosing the elect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors, and the day on which they shall give their votes, which day shall be the same throughout the Confederate States.</p>
<p>7. No person, except a uatural born citizen of the Confederate States, or a citizen thereof at the time of the adoption of this Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, or a citizen thereof born in the United States prior to the twentieth of December, 1860, shall be eligible to the office of Pres<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ident; neither shall any person be eligible to that office who shall not have attained the age of thirty-five years, and been fourteen years a resident within the limits of the Confederate States, as they may exist at the time of his election.</p>
<p>8. In case of the removal of the President from office, or of his death, resignation, or inability to discharge the powers and duties of said office, the same shall devolve on the Vice-President, and the Congress may by law provide for the case of removal, death, resigna<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, or inability, both of the President and Vice-President, declar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing what officer shall then act as President; and such officer shall act accordingly until the disability be removed or a President shall be elected.</p>
<p>9. The President shall, at stated times, receive for his services a compensation, which shall be neither increased nor diminished dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the period for which he shall have been elected, and he shall not receive within that period any other emolument from the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, or any of them.</p>
<p>10. Before he enters on the execution of his office, he shall take the following oath or affirmation:</p>
<p>&#8220;I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will faithfully execute the office of President of the Confederate States, and will, to the best of my ability, preserve, protect, and defend the Constitution thereof.&#8221;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION II.</head>
<p>1. The President shall be Commander-in-chief of the army and navy of the Confederate States, and of the militia of the several States, when called into the actual service of the Confederate States; he may require the opinion, in writing, of the principal officer in each of the Executive Departments, upon any subject relating to the duties of their respective offices; and he shall have the power to grant reprieves and pardons for offences against the Confederate States, except in cases of impeachment.</p>
<p>2. He shall have power, by and with the advice and consent of <pb n="1551" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>the Senate, to make treaties, provided two-thirds of the Senators present concur; and he shall nominate, and by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint Ambassadors, other public Ministers and Consuls, Judges of the Supreme Court, and all other officers of the Confederate States, whose appointments are not here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in otherwise provided for, and which shall be established by law; but the Congress may by law vest the appointment of such inferior officers as they think proper, in the President alone, in the courts of law, or in the Heads of Departments.</p>
<p>3. The principal officer in each of the Excutive Departments, and all persons connected with the diplomatic service, may be removed from office at the pleasure of the President. All other civil officers, of the Executive Department, may be removed at any time by the President, or other appointing power, when their services are unnecesssary, or for dishonesty, incapacity, inefficiency, miscon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duct, or neglect of duty; and when so removed the removal shall be reported to the Senate, together with the reasons therefor.</p>
<p>4. The President shall have power to fill all vacancies that may happen during the recess of the Senate, by granting commissions which shall expire at the end of their next session; but no person rejected by the Senate shall be re-appointed to the same office dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing their ensuing recess.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION III.</head>
<p>1. The President shall from time to time give to the Congress information of the state of the Confederacy, and recommend to their consideration such measures as he shall judge necessary and expedient; he may, on extraordinary occasions, convene both Houses, or either of them; and in case of disagreement between them, with respect to the time of adjournment, he may adjourn them to such time as he shall think proper; he shall receive Ambas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sadors and other public Ministers; he shall take care that the laws be faithfully executed, and shall commission all the officers of the Confederate States.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION IV.</head>
<p>The President, Vice-President, and all civil officers of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, shall be removed from office on impeachment for, and conviction of treason, bribery, or other high crimes and mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanors.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1552" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE III.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>1. The Judicial power of the Confederate States shall be vested in one Supreme Court, and in such inferior courts as the Congress may from time to time ordain and establish. The Judges, both of the supreme and inferior courts, shall hold their offices during good behavior; and shall, at stated times, receive for their services a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation which shall not be diminished during their continuance in office.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION II.</head>
<p>1. The Judicial power shall extend to all cases arising under this Constitution, the laws of the Confederate States, and treaties made, or which shall be made, under their authority; to all cases affecting Ambassadors, other public Ministers, and consuls; to all cases of admiralty and maritime jurisdiction; to controversies to which the Confederate States shall be a party; to controversies be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween two or more States; between a State and citizen of another State, where the State is plaintiff; between citizens claiming lands under grants of different States; and between a State, or the citizens thereof, and foreign States, citizens, or subjects; but no State shall be sued by a citizen or subject of any foreign State.</p>
<p>2. In all cases affecting Ambassadors, other public Ministers, and Consuls, and those in which a State shall be a party, the Su<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />preme Court shall have original jurisdiction. In all the other cases before mentioned, the Supreme Court shall have appellate juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction, both as to law and fact, with such exceptions and under such regulations as the Congress shall make.</p>
<p>3. The trial of all crimes, except in cases of impeachment, shall be by jury; and such trial shall be held in the State where the said crimes shall have been committed; but when not committed within any State, the trial shall be at such place or places as the Congress may by law have directed.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION III.</head>
<p>1. Treason against the Confederate States shall consist only in levying war against them, or in adhering to their enemies, giving them aid and comfort. No person shall be convicted of treason un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less on the testimony of two witnesses to the same overt act, or on confession in open court.</p>
<p>2. The Congress shall have power to declare the punishment of treason, but no attainder of treason shall work corruption of blood, or forfeiture, except during the life of the person attainted.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1553" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE IV.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>1. Full faith and credit shall be given in each State to the public acts, records, and judicial proceedings of every other State. And the Congress may by general laws prescribe the manner in which such acts, records, and proceedings shall be proved, and the effect thereof.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION II.</head>
<p>1. The citizens of each State shall be entitled to all the privil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eges and immunities of citizens in the several States, and shall have the right of transit and sojourn in any State of this Confederacy, with their slaves and other property; and the right of property in said slaves shall not be thereby impaired.</p>
<p>2. A person charged in any State with treason, felony or other crime, against the laws of such State, who shall flee from justice, and be found in another State, shall, on demand of the Executive authority of the State from which he fled, be delivered up, to be removed to the State having jurisdiction of the crime.</p>
<p>3. No slave or other person held to service or labor in any State or Territory of the Confederate States, under the laws thereof, escaping, or lawfully carried into another, shall, in consequence of any law or regulation therein, be discharged from such service or labor; but shall be delivered up on claim of the party to whom such slave belongs, or to whom such service or labor may be due.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION III.</head>
<p>1. Other States may be admitted into this Confederacy by a vote of two-thirds of the whole House of Representatives, and two<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thirds of the Senate&#8212;the Senate voting by States; but no new State shall be formed or erected within the jurisdiction of any other State; nor any State be formed by the junction of two or more States or parts of States, without the consent of the Legislatures of the States concerned, as well as of the Congress.</p>
<p>2. The Congress shall have power to dispose of and make all needful rules and regulations concerning the property of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States, including the lands thereof.</p>
<p>3. The Confederate States may acquire new territory, and Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress shall have power to legislate and provide governments for the inhabitants of all territory belonging to the Confederate States ly<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing without the limits of the several States, and may permit them, at such times and in such manner as it may by law provide, to form States to be admitted into the Confederacy. In all such territory, <pb n="1554" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the</fw>the institution of negro slavery, as it now exists in the Confederate States, shall be recognized and protected by Congress, and by the Territorial Government; and the inhabitants of the several Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States and Territories shall have the right to take to such Territory any slaves lawfully held by them, in any of the States or Territories of the Confederate States.</p>
<p>4. The Confederate States shall guarantee to every State that now is, or hereafter may become, a member of this Confederacy, a republican form of government, and shall protect each of them against invasion; and on application of the Legislature, or of the Executive when the Legislature is not in session, against domestic violence.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE V.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>1. Upon the demand of any three States, legally assembled in their several Conventions, the Congress shall summon a Convention of all the States to take into consideration such amendments to the Constitution as the said States shall concur in suggesting at the time when the demand is made; and should any of the proposed amendments to the Constitution be agreed on by the said Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, voting by States, and the same be ratified by the Legislatures of two-thirds of the several States, or by Conventions in two-thirds thereof, as the one or the other mode of ratification may be pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed by the General Convention, they shall thenceforward form a part of this Constitution. But no State shall, without its consent, be deprived of its equal representation in the Senate.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VI.</head>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION I.</head>
<p>The Government established by this Constitution is the successor of the Provisional Government of the Confederate States of Amer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ica, and all the laws passed by the latter shall continue in force un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />til the same shall be repealed or modified; and all the officers ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by the same shall remain in office until their successors are appointed and qualified, or the offices abolished.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION II.</head>
<p>All debts contracted and engagements entered into before the adoption of this Constitution, shall be as valid against the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States, under this Constitution, as under the Provisional Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment.</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1555" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Confederate States of America.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION III.</head>
<p>This Constitution and the laws of the Confederate States, made in pursuance thereof, and all treaties made, or which shall be made under the authority of the Confederate States, shall be the supreme law of the land; and the Judges in every State shall be bound there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by, anything in the Constitution or laws of any State to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary notwithstanding.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION IV.</head>
<p>The Senators and Representatives before mentioned, and the members of the several State Legislatures, and all executive and ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial officers, both of the Confederate States and of the several States, shall be bound by oath or affirmation to support this Consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution; but no religious test shall ever be required as a qualification to any office or public trust under the Confederate States.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION V.</head>
<p>The enumeration in the Constitution of certain rights shall not be construed to deny or disparage others retained by the people of the several States.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SECTION VI.</head>
<p>The powers not delegated to the Confederate States by the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, nor prohibited by it to the States, are reserved to the States respectively, or to the people thereof.</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">ARTICLE VII.</head>
<p>1. The ratification of the Conventions of five States shall be suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient for the establishment of this Constitution between the States so ratifying the same.</p>
<p>2. When five States shall have ratified this Constitution, in the manner before specified, the Congress, under the Provisional Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution, shall prescribe the time for holding the election of Presi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent and Vice-President, and for the meeting of the electoral col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lege, and for counting the votes, and inaugurating the President. They shall also prescribe the time for holding the first election of members of Congress under this Constitution, and the time for as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sembling the same. Until the assembling of such Congress, the Congress under the Provisional Constitution shall continue to ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ercise the legislative powers granted them, not extending beyond the time limited by the Constitution of the Provisional Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1556" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Constitution of the Confederate Sates of America.</fw>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">EXTEACT FROM THE JOURNAL OF THE CONGRESS.</head>
<p>Congress, March 11, 1861.</p>
<p>On the question of the adoption of the Constitution of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America, the vote was taken by yeas and nays; and the Constitution was unanimously adopted, as follows:</p>
<p>Those who voted in the affirmative being Messrs. Walker, Smith, Curry, Hale, McRae, Shorter and Fern, of Alabama, (Messrs. Chil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton and Lewis being absent;) Messrs. Morton, Anderson and Owens, of Florida; Messrs. Toombs, Howell Cobb, Bartow, Nisbet, Hill, Wright, Thomas R. R. Cobb and Stephens of Georgia, (Messrs. Crawford and Kenan being absent;) Messrs. Perkins, de Clouet, Conrad, Kenner, Sparrow and Marshall, of Louisiana; Mesrs. Har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ris, Brooke, Wilson, Clayton, Barry and Harrison, of Mississippi, (Mr. Campbell being absent;) Messrs. Rhett, Barnwell, Keitt, Ches<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nut, Memminger, Miles, Withers and Boyce, of South Carolina; Messrs. Reagan, Hemphill, Waul, Gregg, Oldham and Ochiltree, of Texas, (Mr. Wigfall being absent.)</p>
<p>A true copy.</p>
<closer>
<signed>J. J. HOOPER <lb/>Secretary of the Congress.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Congress, March 11, 1861.</p>
<p>I do hereby certify that the foregoing are, respectively, true and correct copies of &#8220;The Constitute a of the Confederate States of America,&#8221; unanimously adopted this day, and of the yeas and nays, on the question of the adoption thereof.</p>
<closer>
<signed>HOWELL COBB, <lb/>President of the Congress.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
