<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="531" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="113" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution asking the establishment of a direct Mail Route from Brownsville to Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, There is great and urgent necessity that the rapidly iMproving valley of the Rio Grande should have a more direct com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munication with the capital of the State than the present tor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuous route, therefore,</p>
<p>1st, Be it resolved by the Legislatue of the State of Texas, That our Senators be instructed, and our Representatives requested to use all proper exertions consistent with their official duties, to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure the establishment of a Mail Route between the cities of Brownsville and Austin, via Port Merril and San Antonio.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 20th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution instructing our Senators, and requesting our Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives to use their influence to procure the incorporation of the Officers of the late Navy of Texas into the Navy of the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, There were connected with the great measure of an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nexation to the Confederacy of which we are now a member, various reciprocal rights and conditions, prescribed by <pb n="532" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="114" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>the terms thereof, as well as others clearly implied and fairly deducible from the same, all of which Texas has on her part fully and completely redeemed;</p>
<p>And whereas, It is the opinion of this Legislature that Commodore E. W. Moore, and the officers of our late Navy under his com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mand, by a liberal and just construction of the terms of annexa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, should have been incorporated into the Navy of the United States, in their several ranks, immediately after the consumma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of that measure, and that they are justly entitled to the same, as well from the construction here claimed as from their high characters, personal and professional, and from the zeal, fidelity, patriotism and valor with which they sustained the cause of their country during her struggle for independence; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1, Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators are hereby instructed, and our Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives in Congress requested to use their influence to procure the passage of a law by the Congress of the United States, incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porating the officers of the late Navy of Texas into the Navy of the United States, in the rank which they severally held in the late Navy of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, Be it further resolved, That the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to cause copies of this Joint Resolution to be for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />warded to the President of the United States, and to each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 20th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution relative to Corpus Christi becoming a port of entry.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators be instructed, and our Representatives in Congress be requested to call the attention of the Government of the United States to the necessity of malting Corpus Christi a port of entry.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a copy of these resolutions be forwarded to each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 23d, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="533" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="115" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in the Congress of the United States, be instructed, and our Representatives be requested, to use every effort to secure the repeal or modification of a law passed by the Congress of the United States, entitled &#8220;An Act to establish a Collection District in Texas and New Mexico,&#8221; approved August 2d, 1854, and that a copy of this resolution be transmitted by the Secretary of State to each Delegate from this State now in the Congress of the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 28th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following be proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the State of Texas, which, when ratified, as provided for by the thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seventh section of the seventh article of said Constitution, shall be valid to all intents and purposes, as a part of said Constitution, to wit:</p>
<p>In case a vacancy shall from any cause occur in the office of Judge of the Supreme Court, Judge of the District Court, Attorney-Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral, District Attorney, Comptroller of Public Accounts, Treasurer of the State or Commissioner of the General Land Office, the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor shall appoint some suitable person to fill such vacancy, who shall continue to discharge the ditties of such office, until the time of the next general election established by law for the election of State or county officers, and until his successor shall have been dected and qualified.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="534" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="116" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1st. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Legislature concurs entirely in the views presented by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor of the State in his message to the Legislature on the 27th inst., in reference to the recent act of Congress on the Public Debt of Texas.</p>
<p>2nd. Be it resolved, That the said act of Congress proposing to distribute the balance in the Treasury of the United States, after paying all the claims filed against the State of Texas, under the act of Congress of the 28th of February, 1855, without the concurrence or assent of Texas, is unauthorized and illegal, and in no degree jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified by the contemporaneous construction of that act, when Texas accepted the same.</p>
<p>3rd. Be it resolved, That those creditors who have filed their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />leases, and received their money, under the pro rata distribution of that act, have no claim on the surplus in the Treasury of the United States, which Congress proposes to pay them. Such a payment can only be deemed a gift on the part of the Government of the United States, for which that government is responsible for every cent it pays over to the creditors, entitled to the fund or to the State of Texas.</p>
<p>4th. Be it resolved, That the act in question having been enacted without the least notice to Texas, or waiting for her concurrence or assent; we regard it as nothing short of a violation of that comity which ought to subsist between Independent States, involving a manifest act of public disrespect, whilst the indiscreet haste with which the act was passed, in no small degree aggravates its offensive character.</p>
<p>5th. Be it resolved, That in reference to the ulterior distribu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the surplus remaining in the Treasury of the United States after the payment of the Public Debt of Texas, in accordance with the proclamation of the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, Texas has a much higher authority to speak than any other government on the earth, and she will speak hereafter with a proper regard to her own sense of Justice and Honor, and the interests of that people over whose character and fortune she is called on to preside.</p>
<p>6th. Be it, in conclusion, resolved, That our Senators in Congress be instructed, and our Representatives be requested <pb n="535" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="117" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>to employ all and every effort in their power to procure at the next session of Congress, a repeal of the act in question. An act as of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fensive to our pride, as it is invasive of our interests.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution instructing our Senators and requesting our Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives in Congress to ask the President of the United States to review and re-examine the proceedings of the Court-Martial, in the case of Chas. E. Travis, late a Captain in the United States Army, and to lay the same before the Senate of the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>1st. Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators be instructed and our Representatives requested to use all honorable means to induce the President of the United States to review and re-examine the proceedings of the Court Martial that sat in judgment upon Capt. Chas. E. Travis, late a Captain of the United States army, and if the same can be done, to reverse said finding of the Court, and to reinstate the said Travis.</p>
<p>2nd. Resolved, That our Senators and Representatives be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to lay the subject referred to, in the above resolution, before the Senate and ask an investigation of the proceedings had upon the trial of the said Capt. Chas. E. Travis, and urge upon the Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate such action as the nature of the ease may require. Resolved, That from an examination of a certified copy of the evidence given before the Court-Martial in this case, which is now before the Legislature, we are of opinion that the sentence of the Court was not sustained by the testimony, and is therefore unjust.</p>
<p>3rd. That the Secretary of State is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to transmit under the great seal of the State, a copy of these Joint Resolutions to the President of the United States and to our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<p>4th. That these resolutions take effect and be in force from and after their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="536" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="118" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State be instructed to have printed immediately, five hundred copies of the captions of all the acts and Joint Resolutions passed at the present adjourned session of the 6th Legislature, and that he shall immediately mail three copies of said list, to each mem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of the present Legislature. The remainder to be disposed of as the said Secretary may think best. The expense of the same to be paid out of the appropriation for the public printing.</p>
<p>And that this resolution take effect and be in force from and af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Governor to institute certain suits, if necessary, in relation to the erection and furnishing of the new Capitol.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and be is hereby authorized to fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nish the Attorney General with a copy of all the testimony and evidence reported by the Select Committee appointed at this ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion, to investigate all matters relating to the expenditure of the money appropriated for the Construction of the Capitol, and the purchase of furniture for the same, and also to furnish the Attorney General with a copy of all bonds entered into by the Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers for the erection of the new Capitol, all bonds entered into by the Superintendent of the same, and by the Contractors for the build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the same; which said bonds were entered into under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of &#8220;An Act to provide for the erection of a Capitol for the State of Texas,&#8221; approved February 14th, 1853. And also such bonds as were entered into, under the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An Act supplementary to an act entitled an act to provide for the erection of State Capitol, approved February 14th, 1853,&#8221; approved February 7th, 1853.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, Be it resolved, That at shall be the duty of the At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="537" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="119" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>torney General to examine said evidence and said bonds, and also to examine the law with reference to said evidence and said bonds, and also in reference to the manner in which the agent&#8212;Eli Kirk&#8212;for the purchase of furniture for the new Capitol, discharged his duties. It shall be the duty of the Attorney General, after examining the evidence, the bonds, and the law upon the subject, to furnish the Governor with a written opinion as to the remedy (if any) that the State may have upon the facts and law, on the bonds above enum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erated, or otherwise, and also if there is any remedy at law against the agent, Eli Kirk, appointed for the purchase of the furniture for the new Capitol, under the law above stated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, Be it resolved, That upon the reception of the written opinion of the Attorney General, it shall be the duty of the Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />or to instruct the Attorney General to commence a suit against all persons against whom the State may have a legal remedy, under the provisions of the acts cited in the first section of these Resolutions. Said suit to be instituted in the District Court of Travis County, and to be conducted by the Attorney General on the part of the State, and to be subject to all rules, pleas, and defence that all other suits, either equitable or legal in this State, are subject to under the laws of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, Be it resolved, That in case the Attorney General shall be necessarily absent during the session of the said District Court, it shall be the duty of the Governor to instruct the District Attorney of the 2d Judicial District to represent the State in said suits. Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that should the Attorney General be satisfied, after a full and fair investigation of the subject, that the Commissioners have acted in good faith, or that there is no ground of action against them, he shall certify the same to the Comptroller, who shall thereupon issue a warrant upon the Treasurer for the amount of undrawn salaries due them, which shall be paid by said Treasurer. And provided fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ther, that should suit be brought against said Commissioners, and a verdict be returned in their favor, a certificate of the Clerk of the Court showing that fact, shall be sufficient authority for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of balance due them on account of salaries.</p>
<p>Resolved, 5th, That these Resolutions take effect from their pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="538" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="120" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, Edward Clark, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the adjourned session of the Sixth Legislature of said State commenced, at the city of Austin, on Monday the seventh, day of July, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-six, and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed on Monday the first day of September, in the year one thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand eight hundred and fifty-six.</p>
<p>And I further certify, That the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this volume are true copies, with the exception of the words embraced in brackets, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and official seal, the 22d day of <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L.S.]</p></body></floatingText>November, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-six.</p>
<closer>
<signed>EDWARD CLARK.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="addendum">
<p>Note.&#8212;The words embraced in brackets were inserted by the Sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />retary of State in comparing the laws, supposing them to be omis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions in enrolling the bills.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="539" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A.</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Angelina County.&#8212;Act to locate permanently the seat of Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of.............................. <ref>28</ref></p>
<p>Appropriations.&#8212;For improving the navigation of rivers, bayous, &#38;c.................................. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To pay per diem and mileage of members and officers of Legislature.............................. <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To pay for arms lost at Goliad............................ <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To establish an Institution for the education of the blind................................ <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To defray the expenses of the Penitentiary......... <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To pay a certain judgment against Jas. H. Cock, late Custom&#8217;s Collector, &#38;c.......................... <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; For improvement of Capitol grounds............. <ref>54</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To establish an Institution for the education of the deaf and dumb................................. <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; For erection and support of a lunatic Asylum..... <ref>60</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; To pay volunteers commanded by Captains Tom, English and Tobin......................... <ref>78</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act supplemental to act making, for use and support of Government for the years 1856-1857......... <ref>97</ref></p>
<p>Archives.&#8212;The better security of, of the State Department provided for........................... <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; The translation and transfer of a portion of, of Bexar county, provided for.......................... <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>Assessors and Collectors.&#8212;Act relating to duties of........ <ref>83</ref></p>
<p>Asylums.&#8212;Act setting aside and appropriating land for the benefit of.............................. <ref>76</ref></p>
<pb n="540" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Attachments.&#8212;The 4th section of act of 1848, regulating, amended..................................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Austin.&#8212;Certain real estate granted to city of.................... <ref>103</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B.</head>
<p>Bastrop County.&#8212;The Eastern boundary line of, particularly defined.................................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Blind.-Act establishing an Institution for the education of the............................ <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Bonds.&#8212;The special school fund to be invested in the, of Railroad Companies.................................. <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; A part of, of the United States, now in the Treasury to be sold.............................. <ref>65</ref></p>
<p>Bounty Warrants.&#8212;The act anthorizing the issuance of, repealed........................ <ref>82</ref></p>
<p>Brazoria County.&#8212;The act concerning roads, &#38;c., in, amended 30 &#8220; &#8220; A special tax authorized in, for purposes of internal improvements <ref>95</ref></p>
<p>Brown County.&#8212;Act creating....................... <ref>66</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C.</head>
<p>Capitol.-Act to provide for improving the grounds of......... 54 &#8220; Certain suits concerning the building of, authorized.. <ref>118</ref></p>
<p>Claims.&#8212;An act to ascertain the legal, tor money and land, against the State........................ <ref>14</ref></p>
<p>Cock, Jas. H.&#8212;Appropriation to pay a certain judgment against.............................. <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Colony.&#8212;Certain surveys in Peters&#39;, to be patented......... <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act supplemental to act for relief of citizens of Mer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cer&#8217;s........................................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Comanche County.&#8212;The act creating, amended........... <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Commissioner of Claims.&#8212;May employ an additional clerk.... <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Comptroller.&#8212;Required to perform certain duties heretofore performed by Auditor and.............. <ref>70</ref></p>
<p>Constitution.&#8212;Joint resolution proposing an amendment of.. <ref>115</ref></p>
<p>Coshattee Indians.&#8212;Act for the relief of............... <ref>85</ref></p>
<p>Corpus Christi.&#8212;Joint resolution requesting that, be made a port of entry.................................. <ref>114</ref></p>
<p>Cotton.&#8212;Act fixing compensation, for saving, &#38;c.......... <ref>76</ref></p>
<pb n="541" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Counties Created.&#8212;Brown............................. <ref>66</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Jack............................... <ref>62</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; McCulloch.................................. <ref>69</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Palo Pinto................................... <ref>65</ref></p>
<p>Court of Claims.&#8212;Act to provide an office for............. <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Court, District&#8212;Time of holding, in the First Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, defined............................. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Eighteenth Judicial District, defined............................. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Tenth and Fourteenth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial Districts, changed................... <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Tenth and Fourteenth Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial Districts, again changed.................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Twelfth Judicial District, defined............................... <ref>68</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Third Judicial District, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined.............................. <ref>94</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Fifth Judicial District, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fined................................... <ref>70</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; The causes on the docket of, in Harrison and Rusk counties, to be apportioned........................... <ref>102</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Seventeenth and Second Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial Districts, defined........................ <ref>105</ref></p>
<p>Court, Justices&#8212;The Spanish language may be used in, when and where....................... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>Court, Supreme&#8212;The 1st section of act amending the act to organize, amended......................... <ref>61</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D.</head>
<p>Deaf and Dumb&#8212;An Institution for the education of, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for................................ <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>District, Collection&#8212;The act of Congress establishing a, in Texas and New Mexico, to be repealed or modified. <ref>115</ref></p>
<p>District, Judicial&#8212;Act defining the First.............. <ref>3</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act to create the Eighteenth.................... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding Courts in the Tenth and Fourteenth, changed.............................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding, in the Tenth and Fourteenth, again changed.................................. <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act changing the Sixth and Ninth, amended...... <ref>54</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act changing the Sixth and Ninth, again amended.. <ref>64</ref></p>
<pb n="542" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>District Judicial.&#8212;Time of holding Courts in the Twelfth, defined............................. <ref>68</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Time of holding Courts in the Third, defined...... <ref>94</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act fixing the time of holding Courts in the Fifth, amended..................... <ref>70</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Act to organize the seventeenth, and re-organize the Second............................... <ref>105</ref></p>
<p>Donation Warrants.&#8212;Act authorizing the issuance of, repealed <ref>82</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E.</head>
<p>Education.&#8212;Act to protect lands granted for purposes of.... <ref>85</ref></p>
<p>Erath County.&#8212;The act creating, amended................ <ref>96</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F.</head>
<p>Falls County.&#8212;A portion of, added to Bell............ <ref>89</ref></p>
<p>Fearris, David P.&#8212;Acts of, as Notary Public, legalized...... <ref>85</ref></p>
<p>Free Negroes.&#8212;The 9th sec. of act concerning amended...... <ref>48</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G.</head>
<p>Goliad.&#8212;Appropriation to pay for arms lost at............ <ref>26</ref></p>
<p>Gonzales and Lavaca.&#8212;Act to change the lines between the counties of...................... <ref>43</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H.</head>
<p>Hall, Bolling.&#8212;Estate of, may be administered in Rusk county <ref>93</ref></p>
<p>Henderson County.&#8212;Certain Surveys legalized............. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>Houston County.&#8212;The book of marks and brands of, to be transcribed........................ <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Hunt County.&#8212;Certain surveys in, made valid.......... <ref>42</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I.</head>
<p>Indian Reserves.&#8212;The sale of Intoxicating liquors fieax, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibited............................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Islands.&#8212;Certain surveys on Mustang and other, to be pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented............................. <ref>91</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">J.</head>
<p>Jack County.&#8212;Act creating...................................... <ref>62</ref></p>
<p>Judges.&#8212;Act supplemental to act fixing the salaries of.......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<pb n="543" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K.</head>
<p>Karnes County.&#8212;Territory in, made a land district.......... <ref>27</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L.</head>
<p>Land.&#8212;The act granting 160 acres of, to actual sellers, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed....................... <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Act to protect, granted fox purposes of education... <ref>85</ref></p>
<p>Land Certificates.&#8212;Act supplemental to act authorizing pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents on, issued by Commissioners of Robertson county........................... <ref>59</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Manner of entering, prescribed, and lifting and float<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing, prohibited........................ <ref>74</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Unconditional, required to be returned to General Land Office.............................. <ref>81</ref></p>
<p>Land District.&#8212;Territory in Karnes county created into...... <ref>27</ref></p>
<p>Land Titles.&#8212;Act to quiet............................. <ref>59</ref></p>
<p>Language.&#8212;The Spanish may be used in Justices Courts, when and where....................... <ref>45</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Certain general laws to be translated and printed in the Spanish and German......................... <ref>94</ref></p>
<p>Laws.&#8212;Captions of, and Joint Resolutions to be printed..... <ref>118</ref></p>
<p>Lavaca and Gonzales.&#8212;Act to change the line between the counties of....................... <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>Liquors.&#8212;Sale of, near Jamestown and Starrville in Smith county, prohibited....................... <ref>93</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Sale of, within limits of league of land granted to Franklin Lewis in Fayette county prohibited...... <ref>101</ref></p>
<p>Lunatics.&#8212;Act to provide an Asylum for....................... <ref>60</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M.</head>
<p>Mail Route.&#8212;A direct from Brownsville to Austin, desired... <ref>113</ref></p>
<p>Marital Rights.&#8212;The act of 1848 concerning, amended..... <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Marshal.&#8212;The United States, for the District of Texas may use the Jails and Penitentiary of State............ <ref>88</ref></p>
<p>McClennan County.&#8212;The County Count of, may levy a special tax.................................. <ref>29</ref></p>
<pb n="544" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>McCulloch County.&#8212;Act creating..................... <ref>69</ref></p>
<p>McMicken, Levi S.Acts of, as Deputy County Clerk of Polk county made valid...................... <ref>41</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N.</head>
<p>Navarro County.&#8212;Act concerning certain School lands of... <ref>81</ref></p>
<p>Navy.&#8212;Joint Resolution requesting the incorporation of the late Texas Naval officers into the, of the United States..................................... <ref>113</ref></p>
<p>Newton County.&#8212;Act to locate permanently the seat of justice of.................................. <ref>25</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P.</head>
<p>Palo Pinto County.&#8212;Act creating....................... <ref>65</ref></p>
<p>Pre-emption Claimants.&#8212;Act for the relief of............... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Pre-emption Settlers.&#8212;Act for relief of certain, within Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Land District................................... <ref>80</ref></p>
<p>Penitentiary.&#8212;Appropriation to defray expenses of............ <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; The use of, granted to the United States Marshal for the District of Texas....................... <ref>88</ref></p>
<p>Public Buddings.&#8212;Act to punish persons for defacing the walls of, &#38;c.............................. <ref>24</ref></p>
<p>Public Debt.&#8212;The money due upon certain certificates of, to be collected by Treasurer............... <ref>82</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; Recent action of Congress as to, protested against... <ref>116</ref></p>
<p>Public Printing.&#8212;Act concerning....................... <ref>92</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R.</head>
<p>Rail-Roads.&#8212;The 8th sec. of act of 1850 to encourage the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of, amended........................... <ref>105</ref></p>
<p>Reserve.&#8212;The Mississippi and Pacific Railroad opened to loca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion................................ <ref>56</ref></p>
<p>Rivers.&#8212;Appropriation to improve the navigation of......... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Act prodding for improvement of &#38;c., amended.... <ref>46</ref></p>
<p>Robertson County.&#8212;The league of school land belonging to, in Ellis county to be patented....................... <ref>89</ref></p>
<p>Rogers, Jas. H.&#8212;Appropriation to pay, as special Judge of the Supreme Court.......................... <ref>40</ref></p>
<pb n="545" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S.</head>
<p>Schools.&#8212;Act providing for the support of.............. <ref>107</ref></p>
<p>School Fund.&#8212;Act to provide for the investment of, in bonds of railroad companies............................ <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; &#8220; The 3rd sec. of act to invest, in bonds of railroad companies, amended........................... <ref>57</ref></p>
<p>Scrip.&#8212;Manner of entering prescribed, and lifting and floating, prohibited........................ <ref>74</ref></p>
<p>Slaves.&#8212;Act prohibiting to carry guns or other dangerous wea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pons..................................... <ref>81</ref></p>
<p>Surveys.&#8212;Certain, in Henderson county legalized............. <ref>37</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Certain, in Hunt county, by John Grainger, legal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized.................................. <ref>42</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Certain, in Peters Colony, to be patented........... <ref>50</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Certain, on Mustang and other Islands, to be pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ented............................ <ref>91</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T.</head>
<p>Tarrant County.&#8212;Act providing for location of seat of justice of................................ <ref>49</ref></p>
<p>Taxes.&#8212;Of the State for the years 1856 and 1857, relinquished to the counties...................... <ref>43</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; Acts concerning Assessors and Collectors of........ <ref>83</ref></p>
<p>Travis, Capt. Chas. E.&#8212;Joint Resolution requesting a review of the proceedings of the Court Martial in case of.. <ref>117</ref></p>
<p>Treasurer.&#8212;Required to collect from the United States the money due upon certain Public Debt certificates.. <ref>82</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">U.</head>
<p>University.&#8212;Act authorizing the sale of the lands of............ <ref>71</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; The unlocated balance of lands of, to be surveyed.... <ref>84</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V.</head>
<p>Volunteers.&#8212;Appropriation to pay companies of, commanded by Captains Tom, English and Tobin............ <ref>78</ref></p>
<pb n="546" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W.</head>
<p>Weigher of Cotton.&#8212;Act creating the office of............ <ref>90</ref></p>
<p>Wills.&#8212;The act of 1840 concerning, amended......... <ref>5</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Y.</head>
<p>Young County.&#8212;The act creating amended............... <ref>41</ref></p>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>