<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1517" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">THE <lb/>ORDINANCES AND RESOLUTIONS <lb/>OF THE <lb/>CONTENTION</head>
<byline>Held in the City of Austin 28th of January, 1861, February 24th, 1861.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1861</byline>
<pb n="1518" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="1519" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">ORDINANCES <lb/>PASSED BY THE <lb/>STATE CONVENTION.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. l.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To dissolve the union between the State of Texas and the other States, united under the compact styled &#8220;The Constitution of the United States of America.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Federal Government has failed to accomplish the purposes of the compact of union between the States, in giving protection either to the persons of our people upon an exposed frontier, or to the property of our citizens; and, whereas, the act<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ion of the Northern States of the Union is violative of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pact between the States and the guarantees of the Constitution; and, whereas, the recent developments in Federal affairs, make it evident that the power of the Federal Government is sought to be made a weapon with which to strike down the interest and pros<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />perity of the people of Texas and her sister slaveholding States, instead of permitting it to be, as was intended, our shield against outrage and aggression: therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. We, the People of the State of Texas, by delegates in Convention assembled, Do declare and ordain, that the ordinance adopted by our convention of delegates, on the 4th day of July, A. D. 1845, and afterwards ratified by us, under which the Republic of Texas was admitted into union with other States and became a party to the compact styled &#8220;The Constitution of the United States of America,&#8221; be, and is hereby repealed and annulled; that all the powers, which by said compact were delegated by Texas to the Federal Government, are revoked and resumed; that Texas is of right absolved from all restraints and obligations incurred by said compact, and is a separate sovereign State, and that her citizens and people are absolved from all allegiance to the United States, or the Government thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. This ordinance shall be submitted to the people of Texas for their ratification or rejection by the qualified voters thereof, on the 23d day of February, 1861, and, unless rejected by a majority of the votes cast, shall take effect and be in force on and after the 2d <pb n="1520_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>day of March, A. D. 1861. Provided, that in the Representative district of El Paso, said election may be held on the 18th day of February, 1861.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin City, <date>the first day of February, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 2.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Prescribing the mode of election to be held for the rejection or ratification of the Ordinance of Separation of the State of Texas from the United States of America.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. The people of Texas in Convention assembled, Do declare and ordain, and it is hereby declared and ordained, that a general election shall be held on the 23d day of February, A. D. 1861, for the purpose of rejecting or ratifying the ordinance of se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession of the State of Texas from the United States of America, passed by this Convention on the first day of February, A. D. 1861.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The said election shall be held in the usual manner, ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cept that each county shall be an electoral district, and the vote returned by the proper officer of such county to the President or Secretary of this Convention, at Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The election shall be held at each precinct by the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />siding officer of such precinct, either with or without an order of election from the Chief Justice of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The returns from the precincts shall be made on or before the 26th day of February, 1861, either to the Chief Justice, County Clerk, or any one of the County Commissioners of the respective counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The manner of making returns to the Chief Justice, County Clerk, or Commissioner, shall be the same as that used in the ordinary elections, and the returns made to the President or Secretary of the Convention, shall be made in the manner now pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by law for making returns of elections to the office of Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It shall be the duty of the officer to whom the returns of his county shall be made, to count the votes and certify the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sult, and transmit the same to the President or Secretary of the Convention, in duplicate, at different times, by mail, or by some discreet person, on the 26th day of February, or sooner, if complete returns of the county shall have been sooner made; and also de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posite a copy of said returns in the County Clerk&#8217;s office.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The aggregate vote shall be counted, by the President and Secretary of the Convention, on or after the 2d day of March, A. D. <pb n="1521_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>1861, as the Convention may determine; and the result of the vote of the State shall be then proclaimed by the President and Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of the Convention, or either of them.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The manner of voting shall be by ballot, &#8220;For Seces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion,&#8221; or &#8220;Against Secession,&#34; and each qualified elector shall be permitted to vote in any county of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The citizens of the county of El Paso may hold the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, for the purpose herein specified, on the 18th day of February, A. D. 1861.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin, on this <date>the first day of Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 3.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To secure the friendship and co-operation of the people of the Ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritories of Arizona and New Mexico, and also of the Choctaw, Chickasaw, Cherokee, Creek, and Seminole nations of Indians.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Convention assembled, That Simeon Hart and P. T. Herbert be appointed Commissioners, to proceed at once to the territories of Arizona and New Mexico, with instructions to invite the co-operation of the people of said ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritories in the formation of a Southern Confederacy.</p>
<p>And be it further ordained, That James E. Harrison, James Bourland, and Charles A. Hamilton be and they are hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poined Commissioners to proceed, at once, to the Choctaw, Chicka<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />saw, Cherokee, Seminole, and Creek nations, with instructions to invite the speedy and prompt co-operation of the people of said na<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions in the formation of a Southern Confederacy.</p>
<p>Be it further ordained, That said Commissioners are hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized and empowered to act separately or jointly, as may be best, and that each one of said Commissioners be commissioned by the President of this Convention, attested by the Secretary; and that they also be furnished with an attested copy of the ordinance of se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cession, and that they be instructed to lay the same before the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple of said territories and nations; and the President of this Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention be instructed to correspond immediately with the proper authorities of the States of Mississippi and Arkansas, requesting them to appoint Commissioners from said States to co-operate with the Texas Commissioners in their mission to the Indian nations.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin, on the <date>4th day of February, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1522_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 4.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to the removal of the United States Troops from the limits of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the terms of an agreement between the Commissioners of this Convention and Brevet Maj.-Gen. Twiggs, Commander of the Military Department of Texas, require that the troops now within the jurisdiction of Texas shall be removed from the State, by way of the coast, as soon as possible; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Convention assembled, That all monies, transports, vessels, or other supplies sent to Texas, after the 18th of February, 1861, by the government or authorities of the United States of America, necessary and intended in good faith to facilitate the removal of troops from this State, shall not be seized or otherwise interfered with by the authorities or citizens of the State of Texas.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Done at the City of Austin, Texas, on the <date>4th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 5.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>In relation to a union of the State of Texas with the Confederate States of America.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Convention of this State has received information that the Congress of the Confederate States of America, now in session at the city of Montgomery, in the State of Alabama, has adopted a Constitution for a Provisional Government, which Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution is modelled on that of the United States of America, and, whereas, as a seceded State, it becomes expedient and proper that Texas should Join said Confederacy and share its destinies; and, whereas, a delegation, consisting of seven members, has al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ready been elected by the Convention to the Congress of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federacy aforesaid; therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. The People of Texas, in Convention assembled, Have ordained and declared, and do hereby ordain and declare, that the delegation aforesaid, to the Congress aforesaid, be, and they are hereby instructed, and we do accordingly instruct them, in behalf of the State, and as representing its sovereign authority, to apply for the admission of this State into said Confederacy; and to that end and for that purpose, to give in the adhesion of Texas to the provisional Constitution of said Confederate States; and which said <pb n="1523_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>Constitution, this Convention hereby approves, ratifies, and accepts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained, That the delegation appointed by this Convention to the Congress of the Confederate States, be and they are hereby authorized to act in said Congress as the duly accred<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ited representatives of the State of Texas: Provided, however, that any permanent Constitution which may be formed by said Congress shall not become abigatory on this State until approved by the peo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ple in such way as shall be determined upon.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further ordained, That the President of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention immediately transmit, through such channel as he may elect, a copy or copies of this ordinance to the Congress at Mont<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gomery, and the members of Congress from this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Done at Austin City, <date>March 5th, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 6.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>In relation to Custom House Officers, and Customs Revenue.</salute>
</opener>
<p>The People of Texas, in Convention assembled, Have ordained and declared, and do ordain and declare as follows, to-wit:</p>
<p>First. All Custom House officers and Light House keepers in office in this State (including all such as may have resigned in con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequence of the anticipated secession of this State from the Federal Union) on the 2d day of March, 1861, by appointment from the United States of America, shall remain in office and continue to per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form the duties of the same, till superseded by either the govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of this State, or that of the Confederate States of America: Provided, however, they shall respectively enter into bonds payable to the State, in an amount not less than that of the bonds given by them respectively to the United States of America; the condition being the same, with good and sufficient security, to be approved by any District Judge of the State, and also by taking the official oath prescribed by this Convention.</p>
<p>Second. That the collectors of the customs aforesaid, shall close their accounts of customs, and also their accounts as disbursing offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers, up to the second day of March, 1861, showing the balance for or against said officers, which balance, if in favor of the United State of America, together with all revenue which had been received since said 2d day of March, 1861, and all hereafter collected&#8212;after deducting the necessary expenses for disbursement, shall be deemed and taken to be the property of the State, and accounted for to the Comptroller of the State, and paid into the Treasury of the State, to the credit of the Convention, and by the Treasurer to be disbursed in such way as the Convention may hereafter point out.</p>
<p>Third. That the tariff laws of the Confederate States of America, assessing duties, fixing the fees of office and regulating the registra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1524_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>tion of vessels, shall be observed and followed by the several collec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tors of Customs of the State: Provided, however, that duties shall not be imposed or collected upon goods, wares, and merchandise imported into the State from the Confederate States of America.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Done at the City of Austin, Texas, <date>March 8th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 7.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To authorize the purchase of Arms for the use of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>We, the people of the State of Texas, in Convention assembled, Do declare and ordain, and it is hereby declared and ordained, that Major Ben McCulloch be, and is hereby appointed Commissioner to purchase, or otherwise obtain for the State of Texas, one thousand Colt&#8217;s revolvers, and one thousand Morse&#8217;s rifles, with the necessary cartridges and accoutrements; or a like number of such other weap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ons of similar character as he may approve, and as can be obtained. And he is hereby authorized and empowered to pledge the faith of the State of Texas for the fulfilment of any contract or contracts he may enter into in pursuance to this ordinance: Provided, however, that the purchase money for said arms shall not be made payable until the first of August, A. D. 1861: And further provided, that the amount to be paid shall be no more than the market value, with interest, for these weapons.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, the <date>9th day of March, in the year of our Lord, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 8.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the enrollment, publication, and preservation of the Ordinances of the Convention.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. We, the People of the State of Texas, in Convention assembled, Do ordain and declare, and it is hereby ordained and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clared, that the ordinances of this Convention shall be correctly and duly enrolled and signed by the President and Secretary of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention, and deposited in the office of the Secretary of State, and there remain as part and parcel of the archives of the State. And the Secretary of State is hereby authorized and required to furnish certified copies thereof in the manner now prescribed by law in relation to other certified copies from said office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. And be it further ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Secretary of State to superintend the printing of the ordinances of the Convention, and he shall keep a register <pb n="1525_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>thereof, and cause them to be printed in the order in which they are enrolled and signed by the President and Secretary of the Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion. And he shall also prepare and have printed a minute and comprehensive index to the same, and shall certify at the end thereof, that the ordinances, as printed, are true copies of the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rolled ordinances filed in his office; and he shall deliver the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />grossed ordinances to the Public Printer within the time prescribed by law for the printing of the laws and journals of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, and the said Public Printer be, and is hereby required to have printed, five hundred copies of the ordinances, and to deliver the same to the Secretary of State within sixty days from the adjourn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the Convention; under the same restrictions and liabilities imposed by law in relation to public printing.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. And be it further ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Secretary of State, Treasurer, and Comptroller, or a majority of them, to advertise that sealed proposals will be received at the office of the Secretary of State for twenty days from the commencement of such advertisement, to do the printing con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated in the foregoing section,together with such other printing as may be ordered by the Convention under like limitations, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strictions, and liabilities imposed by the act of the 8th Legislature of this State; and the contract for the same shall be closed and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />firmed acordingly.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. And be it further ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Secretary of State to mail one copy of the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances of the Convention, immediately upon their reception from the Public Printer, to the Clerk of the county court in each of the organized counties in this State, and one copy to the President and Vice-President of the Confederate States of America, and one copy to each of the Executive Departments of the Confederate States, and one copy to each of the Governors of the seceded States, and one copy to each of our Representatives in the Congress of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States, and it shall also be the duty of the Secretary of State to send by the carrier of the laws and journals of the extraordinary session of the Legislature of this State, one copy to each of the members and officers of the Convention, and one copy to each Clerk of the district courts in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. And be it further ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Secretary of this Convention, to record the jour<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nals of the proceedings of this Convention in a well bound book to be kept for that purpose, and by him, to be deposited in the office of Secretary of State for safe preservation.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. And be it further ordained and declared, That it shall be the duty of the Secretary of this Convention to furnish the editor of the State Gazette with correct copies of the ordinances of the Convention for publication in the columns of that journal.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin City, on the <date>9th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1526_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 9.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Respecting Public Property.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section. 1. Be it ordained by the People of the State of Texas, in Convention assembled, That from and after the passage of this ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nance, all interest in, or title to, any property, real or personal, here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore belonging to or now held for the late government of the United States, in Texas, other than that allowed the federal troops by the stipulations entered into between the Commissioners on behalf of the Convention and Brevet Major-General David E. Twiggs, U. S. A., late commanding the Department of Texas, be, and the same is hereby declared vested in the State of Texas; sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ject, however, to such equitable arrangement as may be hereafter entered into with the Government of the United States.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it ordained, That any person or persons, who shall, upon demand made in the name of the State of Texas, by any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son authorized by this Convention, fail or refuse to deliver up any personal property belonging to this State, by virtue of the preceding section of this ordinance, may be proceeded against by indictment or otherwise; and upon conviction, shall be fined in a sum not less than twice, or more than four times the value of the property so withheld.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin City, the <date>9th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 10.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning the Arms, Qaurtermaster&#8217;s, Ordnance and Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />saries&#8217; Stores, recently surrendered to the State of Texas by the stipulations between the Commissioners of the State and Brevet Major-General David E. Twigg.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Convention assembled, That Sackfield Maclin be, and he is hereby authorized and commissioned to act as Adjutant and, Inspector General and Chief of Ordnance, with the rank of Colonel of Cavalry; and he shall keep his head-quarters at San Antonio until otherwise ordered, and shall discharge such duties as may be required of him in this ordinance.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained, That before entering upon the discharge of the duties of his office, he shall take the oath of alle<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />giance to this State, as required by the Constitution as amended by the Convention now in session, before the Chief Justice or any Notary Public of Bexar county, and shall file in the office of the <pb n="1527_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>clerk of the District Court of said county, his bond with such sure<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties as may be approved by S. A. Maverick, T. J. Devine and P. N. Luckett, Commissioners, under whose control said property is now held; conditioned that he will faithfully and impartially discharge the duties of his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further ordained, That upon the compliance with the requirements of the second section of this ordinance, by said officer, the Commissioners, S. A. Maverick, T. J. Devine and P. N. Luckett, shall deliver to him all arms of every description, ammuni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and everything belonging to the ordnance department, as the same was surrendered to said Commissioners by Gen. Twiggs, taking his receipt for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further ordained, That said officer shall have the power and authority to appoint such number of assistant ordnance officers, not to rank in any case above a first Lieutenant, as may be necessary to take proper care of said property at the different posts or points where such officers may be needed to preserve the public property: Provided, that in all such cases he shall require of the person or persons so appointed, before entering upon the duties of his office, the oath named in the second section of this ordinance, and require of them such bond with such surety as may be satisfac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory to him, payable to the State of Texas. Said oath may be administered by any officer of the State authorized to administer oaths; said bonds may be filed in any District Clerk&#8217;s office in any county in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Be it further ordained, That said officer shall have au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority to do everything necessary to preserve, protect and keep in good order said public property, and he shall deliver the same upon the requisition of the proper officer or agent of the State, as may be authorized to receive it, and in such quantities and numbers as the same may be authorized to demand, taking receipts for the same: Provided, that nothing contained in this ordinance shall be so con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued as to interfere with the fulfilment of the stipulations made between heretofore named Commissioners and Brevet Major-Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Twiggs.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Be it further ordained, That the officers created by this ordinance shall be governed by the rules and receive the same pay and allowances for their services, allowed and provided in the rules and regulations of the United States army, as published in 1857; and the duration of their offices, duty and authority, and also the compensation for the same, shall be subject to and controlled by the Legislature of this State, and that of the Congress of the Confed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erate States.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Be it further ordained, That said officer shall discharge the duties of Adjutant and Inspector General, and he shall require <pb n="1528_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>all officers in his department to report to him under said rules and regulations of 1857; but he shall not receive more pay than what is allowed to one officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. Be it further ordained, That Philip N. Luckett be and he is hereby appointed and commissioned a Quartermaster and Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missary General, with the rank of Lieutenant Colonel, who shall, before entering upon the discharge of his duties, take the oath re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired in the second section of this ordinance, and file his bond in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, payable to the State of Texas, for the faithful discharge of his duties as Quartermaster; and upon his satisfying Commissioners S. A. Maverick and T. J. Devine, that he has complied herewith, they shall turn over the property of the Quartermaster&#8217;s and Commissary&#8217;s department to him, taking his re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt for the same; and he shall hold and manage said property by the laws, rules and regulations above alluded to, of 1857, and shall be governed in all respects by the fifth section of this ordinance; and that a copy of this ordinance, properly certified, shall be given to said officers.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>12th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 12.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide for the continuance of the existing State Government.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Conven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion assembled, That all the existing laws of the State, not inconsist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent with the Ordinance of Secession and other ordinances of this Convention, shall be and remain in full force until repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained, That all officers of the exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing State Government, upon taking the oath of affirmation pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by an ordinance entitled &#8220;An Ordinance to amend the 1st section of the 7th article of the Constitution of the State of Texas,&#8221; adopted by this Convention on the 14th day of March, A. D. 1861, shall continue in office for and during their respective terms. Should any officer of the. Government refuse to take said oath or affirmation in the manner and within the time hereinafter pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed, then and in that case his office shall be deemed and held vacant, and the same filled, and the duties thereof discharged as though he were dead or had resigned.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further ordained, That the Governor of this State, the Lieutenant-Governor, Secretary of State, Comptroller, Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, Attorney General and Commissioner of the General Land Office, be required, at such hour as shall be designated to them, by notice given them by the President of the Convention, (said hour <pb n="1529_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>to be within three days, Sundays excepted, from and after the adop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this ordinance,) to appear in open Convention, and take the oath aforesaid, which shall be administered by any Justice of the Supreme Court or Judge of the District Court of this State; and members of this Convention who are now here and hold office under this state, shall take the oath prescribed, at 12 o&#8217;clock M., on the day after the adoption of this ordinance.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Be it further ordained, That all the officers of this State, not named in the next preceding section of this ordinance, are re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to take the oath aforesaid, before such officers as are author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to administer official oaths, and in the manner prescribed by existing laws&#8212;the members of the Legislature, upon their re-assem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bling, and all others within forty days from the date of the adop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this ordinance; and the President of this Convention is hereby required to cause to be forwarded, a copy of this ordinance to the Chief Justice of each county of this State, and the Chief Justice of each county, on receipt of the same, shall forthwith notify the several officers of their respective counties, of the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istence of this ordinance.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>14th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 13.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>In furtherance of an Ordinance to provide for the continuance of the existing State Government.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, an ordinance was adopted by the people of the State of Texas, in Convention assembled, at the city of Austin, on Thurs<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day, the 14th day of March, A. D. 1861, entitled &#8220;An Ordinance to provide for the continuance of the existing State Government,&#8221; by the provisions of which it was made incumbent upon the Governor, Lieutenant-Governor, Secretary of State, Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller, Treasurer, Attorney General and Commissioner of the General Land Office, to take an official oath, prescribed by &#8220;An Ordinance to amend the 1st section of the 7th article (general provisions) of the Constitution of the State of Texas,&#8221; adopted March 14, A. D. 1861, at such time as the President should ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point, within three days from the date of the passage of said ordinance; and, whereas, the President of said Convention, in obedience to the provisions of said first named ordinance, did appoint the hour of 12 o&#8217;clock M., of Saturday, the 16th day of March, 1861, as the hour at which said official oath should be taken, by said officers, and did cause to be given to said officers due and timely notice of the same; and, whereas, at the hour <pb n="1530_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>of 12 M., of Saturday, the 16th day of March, 1861, the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention being in session and the resident thereof having an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nounced that the officer appointed therefor was prepared to ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minister the prescribed oath of office to said officers; and, whereas Sam. Houston, Governor, and E. W. Cave, Secretary of State, failed and refused to appear and take the said oath, as Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor and Secretary of State; and, whereas, Edward Clark, Lieut.<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Governor of the State of Texas, did at that hour take and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the oath aforesaid, as Lieut.-Governor of the State; there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of Texas, in Convention assembled, That the office of Governor of the State of Texas, by rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son of the refusal of the late Governor, Sam. Houston, to take the official oath, is vacant, and that the Lieut.-Governor, Edward Clark, is hereby required and authorized to exercise the powers and author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ity appertaining to the office of Governor, until another be chosen at the periodical election, and be duly qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further ordained That the office of Secretary of State, by reason of the said E. W. Cave having failed and refused to take the oath of office, prescribed in the above named ordinance, at the time appointed, is hereby declared vacant; and that the said E. W. Cave be and is hereby required to turn over and deliver to his successor in office, the great seal of State, all papers, archives, or other property belonging or in any wise appertaining to the State Department of State, upon demand made by said officer.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it ordained, That the President of this Convention be and he is hereby required to transmit a copy of this ordinance to Sam. Houston, late Governor, and E. W. Cave, late Secretary of State, of the State of Texas; and Edward Clark, Lieut.-Governor; and also to the presiding officers of the two Houses of the State Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin, the <date>16th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 14.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To provide in part for the Military Defence of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of the State of Texas in Convention assembled, That there shall be immediately raised and mustered into the service of the State of Texas, a regiment of mounted volunteers, consisting of ten companies, and each com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany shall consist of one hundred men, rank and file, to be enrolled for twelve months, unless sooner discharged by the Governor. The <pb n="1531_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>commissioned officers of each company to be elected by the men, the non-commissioned officers to be appointed by the Captains.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That for the command of said regiment there shall be elected by this Convention a Colonel, a Lieutenant-Colonel, and a Major, and appointed by said Colonel an Adjutant, a Quartermas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter, a Commissary, a Regimental Surgeon, each with the rank of Captain, and such other officers and employees as the service may require, and as may be allowed by the laws, rules and regulations governing the army of the Confederate States of America; and for each of said companies there shall be elected as aforesaid, a Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain, a first Lieutenant, a second Lieutenant, and a Surgeon; and appointed by the Captains four Sergeants, four Corporals and a Bugler.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That there shall be appointed by the Governor an enroll<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing officer for each of said companies, who shall enroll the men and assist at their organization; and, after said organization, the rolls shall be delivered to the Captains, who shall immediately return certified muster rolls to the Colonel. The companies shall be mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered into the service under the dirctions and by such officers as may be appointed by the Colonel for that purpose, and it shall be the special duty of the Colonel to superintend the arming and equipment of the men, in order that they may be brought into active service with as litle delay as possible.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the officers and men shall provide themselves with suitable horses and accoutrements, and if any soldier prefers to fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nish his own arms he shall be permitted to do so, provided the arms furnished are adapted to the service, of which the mustering<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in officer shall determine; and there shall be allowed to each soldier who furnishes his own arms, one dollar per month additional pay, said officers and men shall be furnished, armed and equipped at the expense of the State, except their horses, accoutrements and clothing, and shall receive for their services the same pay that is allowed for service of the same character by the Confederate States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That said regiment shall be employed for the defence of the frontier of Texas, and in the prosecution of active campaigns into the Indian country; and should the Confederate States adopt and accept said regiment as a part of their military force, then and in that case said regiment shall be subject to its orders and laws; and while said force remains in the service of Texas it shall be gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erned hy the laws, rules and regulations governing the army of the Confederate States of America.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That while said regiment remains in the service of the State of Texas, the officer commanding the same shall report to the Governor of the State of Texas; but if accepted by the Confederate States of America, the commanding officer shall report as may be required by the laws of the Confederate States.</p>
<pb n="1532_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. That such portion of the public property now belonging to the State of Texas, whether the same may consist of arms, muni<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions of war, army stores, transportation, or any other thing which may be needful or necessary to the service, shall be and is hereby appropriated for the use of said force, and shall be delivered to such officers or persons as may be authorized to demand and receive the same, upon the requisition of the proper officer for the purpose aforesaid.</p>
<p>See. 8. That the volunteer force now in the service of the State of Texas, shall be received as a part of the force hereby provided, upon their compliance with the provisions of this ordinance.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Governor of the State of Texas shall commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion all the officers created by this ordinance, who are by law re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to be commissioned; and each of said officersshall, before entering upon the duties of his office, take the oath of office pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed by this Convention for all State officers; and every disburs<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing officer herein provided for shall enter into bond payable to the State of Texas in such sums as may be required by the Treasurer and Comptroller of the State of Texas, and to be approved by them.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Be it further ordained, That this ordinance shall be and remain in full force and effect until otherwise provided by act of the Legislature of Texas, or by act of the Congress of the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin, on the <date>18th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 15.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Delating to the Expenses, Debts, and Liabilities of this Convention.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of the State of Texas in Convention assembled, That the Legislature be and it is hereby authorized and empowered to make provision for the payment of the mileage and per diem of the members of this Convention, and to make the necessary appropriations to meet the expenses, debts, and liabilities incurred by authority of said Convention.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at Austin, on the <date>19th day of march, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 16.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<p>To confer jurisdiction over the Forts, Navy Yards, Arsenals, and Light-houses in the State of Texas, upon the Confederate States of America.</p>
<pb n="1533_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Section 1. Be it ordained by the People of the State of Texas in Convention assembled, That the Government of the Confederate States is hereby authorized to use, occupy, and hold possession of all Forts, Navy Yards, Arsenals, and Light-houses and their appurte<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nances, in this State, and shall repair and rebuild said Forts, Navy Yards, Arsenals, and Light-houses, and construct others in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance with existing laws of this State, while this State shall continue a member of said Confederacy.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>20th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 18.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>To ratify the Constitution of the Confederate States of America.</salute>
</opener>
<p>The people of the State of Texas assembled by delegates in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention, ordain, That the Constitution of the Confederate States of America, adopted March 11th, 1861, by the Congress of the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sional. Government of said Confederacy, for the permanent gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment thereof, subject to ratification by the respective States, is hereby ratified, accepted, and adopted for the purposes therein ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pressed on the part of this State, acting in its sovereign and inde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pendent character.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>23d day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
<dateline>[The above ordinance passed by a vote of 128 yeas, to 2 nays.]</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 19.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning certain Commissioners and Officers appointed by au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority of this Convention.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. The People of Texas in Convention assembled, do ordain and declare that James E. Harrison, Charles A. Hamilton, and James Bourland, Commissioners accredited by this Convention to the Indian Nations; and Simeon Hart and P. T. Herbert, Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners to Arizona and New Mexico, shall make a full report of their acts and doings on said missions, to the Governor of this State, who shall transmit the same to the President of the Confederate States of America, retaining a copy of the same in the State De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partment.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Legislature of the State of Texas are hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized by law to provide for the compensation of said commissioners and their secretary, for their services on said mission.</p>
<pb n="1534_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That Col. John S. Ford, Col. Henry E. McCulloch, and E. B. Nichols, Hiram B. Waller, and the Commissioners to San Antonio, report their accounts to the Governor, which have not been passed upon by this Convention, and that the Governor, Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, and Comptroller audit the same, and give certificates for the amount due each of them, if anything; for the payment of which the faith of the State is hereby pledged: Provided, no accounts shall be allowed except such as were created in obtaining and pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serving the Federal property for the State, and defending the country.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Col. John S. Ford shall discharge the troops under his command on the Rio Grande, so soon as the regiment over which he has been called to command (excepting such of them as may be retained in the service under the provisions of the ordinance raising the regiment) shall be mustered into service. That H. E. McCulloch shall discharge the troops under his command so soon as the regiment called out by the Confederate States shall be mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered into service.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Done in Convention, at Austin, this <date>23d day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 20.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Relating to the Laws of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the People of Texas in Convention assembled, That all the laws of the State of Texas now in force in which the words &#8220;United States,&#8221; or &#8220;United States of America&#8221; occur, the words &#8220;Confederate State of America&#8221; shall be substituted in their stead, wherever it is necessary to adapt the laws to the present state of things; and hereafter the laws shall be printed and published in accordance with this ordinance, as if the Legislature had so amended them.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>23d day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 22.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Concerning the Suits, Records, and Papers, which pertained to the Federal Courts, in Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>The People of the State of Texas, assembled by delegates in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention, ordain, That the Legislature of this State may provide, in its discretion, for jurisdiction and disposal of the suits, records, and <pb n="1535_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Ordinances.</fw>papers, which were in the Courts of the United States of America, in Texas, preceding and on the second day of March, eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and sixty-one.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the <date>25th day of March, A. D. 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">No. 23.&#8212;AN ORDINANCE</head>
<opener>
<salute>Specifying the Ordinances of the Convention which shall be subject to Legislative action.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it ordained by the People of Texas in Convention, That the several ordinances hereinafter specified by title and date, shall be subject to such action in relation thereto, by the Legislature of this State, as may be necessary and proper, to wit:</p>
<p>1. &#8220;Respecting public property,&#34; Adopted March 9th, 1861.</p>
<p>2. &#34;In relation to Custom House Officers and Customs Revenue.&#8221; Adopted March 8th, 1861.</p>
<p>3. &#8220;To authorize the purchase of Arms for the use of the State.&#34; Adopted March 9th, 1861.</p>
<p>4. &#8220;Concerning the Arms, Quartermaster, Ordnance, and Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missary Stores recently surrendered to the State of Texas by the stipulations between the Commissioners of the State and Brevet Maj.-Gen. David E. Twiggs.&#8221; Adopted March 12th, 1861.</p>
<p>5. &#8220;To provide in part for the military defence of the State of Texas.&#8221; Adopted March 18th, 1861.</p>
<p>6. &#8220;Relating to the laws of Texas.&#8221; Adopted March 23d, 1861. Adopted in Convention at the City of Austin, on the 25th day of March, A. D. 1861.</p>
</div2>
<pb n="1536_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" />
<pb n="1537_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">No. 1.&#8212;Providing for the election of Delegates.</head>
<p>Resolved, That this Convention proceed forthwith to elect, by ballot, seven delegates to represent the State of Texas in the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vention of slaveholding [seceded] States, at Montgomery, Alabama, in order that the views and interests of the people of Texas may be consulted, with reference to the Constitution and Provisional Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment that may be established by said Convention.</p>
<p>Adopted in Convention, at the City of Austin, on the 4th day of February, A. D. 1861.</p>
<p>[Under the above resolution Louis T. Wigfall, John H. Reagan, John Hemphill, Thomas N. Waul, John Gregg, Williamson S. Old<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ham and William B. Ochiltree were elected delegates on the 4th day of February.]</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">No. 2.&#8212;In relation to the Committee of Public Safety.</head>
<p>Resolved by the People of the State of Texas, by delegates in Convention assembled, That should the standing committee of Public Safety deem it essential to the public safety to appoint com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners, officers or persons, in reference to taking possession of any of the Federal property within the limits of this State, they shall have power to appoint such, and assign them their duties and give them the instructions under which they shall act; but this power shall only extend to such cases in which the committee may deem prompt action and secrecy absolutely necessary.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted, <date>February 2, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">No. 3&#8212;On the same subject.</head>
<p>Resolved, That the standing committee on Public Safety shall continue in session during the recess of this Convention; that they <pb n="1538_" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Resolutions.</fw>hold their meetings at such times and places as in their judgment the public interest requires; that said committee may grant leave of absence to its members, provided such leave of absence shall not reduce the number left to a less number than nine.</p>
<p>2. Resolved, That said committee shall keep a full and accurate journal of their acts, in a well bound book, and report the same to the Convention on the re-assembling thereof, on the 2d day of March next.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Adopted <date>February 4th, 1861</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">REMARKS.</head>
<p>The Ordinances amending the State Constitution, numbered 11, 17 and 21, are omitted, for the reason that they are incorporated, by sections, in brackets [&#34; &#34;], in the appropriate places in the body of the Constitution as now published.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>JOHN HENRY BROWN, <lb/>Chairman of Committee.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
<div3 type="addendum">
<p>DEPARTMENT OF STATE, <lb/>AUSTIN, TEXAS, April 2, 1861.</p>
<p>I, Bird Holland, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, hereby certify that the Convention of the people of Texas, by their dele<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gates, assembled in the city of Austin, on Monday, the 28th day of January, 1861;&#8212;that said Convention adjourned the 5th day of February, to meet again on the second day of March, 1861;&#8212;and that it did so re-assemble on said second day of March, and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed sine die on the 25th day of the same month.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and official seal on the day<floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText> and year first above written of the independence of Texas the twenty-sixth year, and of the &#8220;Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />federate States of America,&#8221; the first.</p>
<closer>
<signed>BIRD HOLLAND, <lb/>Secretary of State.</signed>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>