<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="181" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE SIXTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT ITS <lb/>SESSION CONVENED NOVEMBER 5, 1855</head>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1856</byline>
<pb n="182" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="183" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER I.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Parker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all of the territory comprised within the following limits, to wit: beginning at the north-west comer of Tarrant county; thence south with the western boundary line of Tarrant county 30 miles to the south-west comer of Tarrant county; thence west with the northern boundary of Johnson county 30 miles; thence north 30 miles; thence east 30 miles to the place of begin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning, be, and the same is hereby constituted a new county, by the name of the county of Parker.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief Justice of Tarrant county shall, within three months after the passage of this act, lay off the said county of Parker in suitable election pricinets in accordance with law, and shall within the said three months order an election for county officers, which election shall be advertised at three public places in the county of Parker, stating the times and places, which places shall be the different election precincts laid out by the Chief Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of Tarrant county as herein before provided, which election shall be conducted in all other respects in accordance with the gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral laws governing elections, and in accordance with, &#8220;an act to provide for organizing new counties,&#8220; approved, March 20th, 1848; and the said Chief Justice of Tarrant county shall qualify the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son elected to the office of Chief Justice of the county of Parker, who, when qualified by the Chief Justice of Tarrant county, shall qualify the other officers elected for said county of Parker.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the county court of said new county, so soon as they are duly qualified, to proceed to locate the county seat of said county, by selecting at least three eligible sites, not exceeding three miles from the center of said county, having respect for any donation of land that may be made for that purpose, as well as convenience of wood and water, and when so selected, the Chief Justice shall order an <pb n="184" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>election which shall be conducted according to the general laws governing elections for county officers, and if at the first election neither of the sites so selected shall receive a majority of all the votes cast, the place receiving the smallest number of votes shall be thrown out, and the Chief Justice shall order another election as before, and so continue to do, throwing out the site receiving the smallest number of votes, until some one of the sites selected shall receive a majority of all the votes cast, which shall be declared to be the county seat of said county and shall be called Weatherford. That all settlers 21 years old who have resided within the limits of said county sixty days prior to said election, shall be entitled to Vote for the location of the county seat.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That in case the site which shall be declared to be the county seat of said county, shall prove to be vacant and unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated domain, then the State does by this act relinquish and do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nate to the said county of Parker all her right and title to 320 acres of the same, and the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized to issue a patent in the name of the said county for the said 320 acres upon a return, according to law, of the plot and field notes of the same to the General Land Office, duly certified, and the said county court of said new county shall have the power to purchase, if necessary, land not to exceed 320 acres for the use of said county, (should the site selected as above provided prove to be appropriated land,) and shall lay off the site so selected into suitable lots, and after selecting and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary for a Court House, Jail, Clerk&#8217;s Offices, Churches, School-houses and burying grounds, they shall proceed to sell the remainder, or such portion thereof, as they may deem necessary, at public auction at such time and upon such terms as wall most conduce to the interests of the county, and shall apply the proceeds thereof to the erection of necessary public buildings for the use of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Chief Justice of Tarrant county shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to three dollars per day for every day that he is necessarily employed or detained in holding said elections and organizing said county of Parker.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all that territory west of the county hereby created and which was heretofore included within the limits of Tarrant county, shall be attached to and form a part of the territorial limits of said new county, and for all county and general purposes shall form a part of the same after the organization of said county and the location of the seat of Justice thereof.</p>
<pb n="185" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 12th, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER II.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to make valid Surveys made by the County Surveyor of Van Zandt County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all surveys made in Van Zandt county by the county surveyor thereof, be and the same are hereby declared to be as valid as if made by a legally authorized surveyor, and as if said Van Zandt county had been a legal county, having the requisite number of square miles within its territory.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to issue patents upon said surveys, certified by the said county surveyor of said Van Zandt county, provided said sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys do not conflict with surveys or locations previously made, and provided further, that no survey shall be made valid by this act, which would have been invalid, if made by a legally authorized sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor, and said county had embraced the requisite number of square miles within its territory.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 12th, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER III</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Hon. A. W. O. Hicks, Judge of the fifth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Honorable A. W. O. Hicks, Judge of the fifth Judicial District, shall have a leave of absence from the State for the term of three months, at such time as he may desire within the next two years, provided that his absence shall not prevent him from holding the sessions of the several District Courts of his district at the times required by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved. <date>December 12th, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="186" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making Appropriations to pay the expenses of Volunteers called into the service of the State, for the protection of the Frontier, and for other Volunteer service.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be, and the same are hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated to pay the expenses of the company of volunteers com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded by Capt. James H. Callahan, which was called into the ser<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vice of the State by His Excellency the Governor for the protection of the frontier, and for the volunteers who went to his aid under command of Captains Benton and Henry, viz: for pay, mileage, sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistence, forage, &#38;c., including pay of surgeon for Capt. Callahan&#8217;s Co. the sum of sixteen thousand, ninety-one dollars and twelve cents.</p>
<p>For pay, mileage, subsistences, forage, &#38;c., for Captains Benton and Henry&#8217;s companies, the sum of five thousand, seven hundred (and) fifty-five dollars and twenty-two cents.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor be and he is hereby authorized to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point some suitable person, who shall, upon giving bond and security in such sum as the Governor may require, be authorized to draw from the Treasury of the State the sums above appropriated for the pay and mileage of said companies, and shall repair at such times and to such place or places as the Governor may direct, and then pay said companies the amounts that may be due them for their respective terms of service, agreeable to existing laws regulating the pay of mounted troops in the United States service, making a proper return thereof to the Comptroller, and it shall be the duty of said, person thus appointed, to receive and receipt for all articles of public property which may be turned over to him by the officers of said companies, and to dispose of the same for the benefit of the Slate, according to such directions as may be given to him by the Governor, making a due return thereof to the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Pay-Master, so appointed, is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to examine and pay such amounts for Quarter-Master&#8217;s stores, camp and garrison equipage, ordinance stores, forage, transportation, one surgeon&#8217;s medicines, &#38;c., as may be presented in proper form, duly certified to by the respective Commanders of companies. Provided, That no amount, or any item in any amount, shall be allowed or paid, which are not allowed by the regulations of the United States army, nor shall any horses or property claimed to be lost, be paid for by said Pay-Master, unless the value thereof shall be clearly certified to by the <pb n="187" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>appraising officers according to law; and an affidavit of the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manding officer shall, in every case, be required, stating that the property claimed for was lost in battle.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sum of one hundred dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated to carry into effect the above 2nd section.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the Governor be authorized to take such steps as may be necessary to secure the payment of the sums herein appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated by the Government of the United States to the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 17th, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate the Sessions of the Supreme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the term of the Supreme Court now in Session in the City of Austin, be and the same is hereby extended until the end of the third week in January A. D. 1856, and the said Court may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in Session until that time unless the business shall be sooner disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the next term of said Supreme Court at Galveston, shall commence on the first Monday in February eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty-six, and may continue in Session ten weeks unless the business shall be sooner disposed of: but this act shall only apply to the next term of said Court, and all the future terms of said court at Galveston shall commence and be holden under the laws now in force fixing the commencement and duration of the terms of said court.</p>
<p>sec. 3. That the next term of the Supreme Court at Tyler shall commence on the fourth Monday in April 1856, and may continue in Session until the expiration of the time now fixed by law for the duration of the terms of said Court, but this Act shall apply only to the next term of said Court at Tyler; and all future terms there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of shall commence and be held under the laws now in force regulat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the Same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. All appeals and writs of error, and other writs return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able to either the Galveston or Tyler branches of said Supreme Court, shall be returnable to the terms as established by this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>18th December, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="188" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act legalizing the creation of Van Zandt County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by tlie Legislature of the State of Texas: That the county of Van Zandt be, and is hereby declared a legal county, without reference to the extent of its meets and bounds.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>the 18th of December 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the Sixth and Ninth Judicial Districts of the State of Texas and to define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following counties shall compose the sixth Judicial District viz: Wood, Upshur, Harrison, Panola and Rusk.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts of the sixth Judicial District shall be held as follows viz: In the county of Wood on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county Upshur on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion two weeks. In the county of Harrison on the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days after the first Mondays in February and August, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session six weeks. In the county of Panola on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks. In the county of Rusk on the thirteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and Aug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ust, and may continue in Session five weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the following comities shall compose the ninth Judicial District, viz: Houston, Cherokee, Anderson, Henderson, Kaufman, Van Zandt and Smith.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the District Courts of the ninth Judicial District shall be held as follows viz: In the county of Houston on the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Cherokee on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and many continue in session four weeks. In the county of Ander<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks. In the <pb n="189" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county of Henderson on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Kaufman on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Van Zandt on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Smith on the twelfth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all process returnable to, and cases triable at the regular terms of the District Courts of the sixth and ninth Judicial Districts as now provided by law, shall be returnable to and triable at the regular terms thereof respectively as herein prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all laws and parts of laws coming m conflict with this Act, he and they are hereby repealed, and that this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>18th of December 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER VIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the sixteenth Judicial District and define the times of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sixteenth Judicial District shall be composed of the following counties, to wit: Collin, Grayson, Cooke, Denton, Wise, Parker, Tarrant, Johnson, Ellis and Dallas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts shall be held in said District at the following times and places viz: In the county of Collin on the third Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Grayson on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Cooke on the seventh Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Denton on the eighth Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Wise on the ninth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Parker on the tenth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one <pb n="190" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>week. In the county of Johnson on the eleventh Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Ellis on the twelfth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks. In the county of Tarrant on the four<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Dallas on the sixteenth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and other process of every kind, that have been or may hereafter be issued from the District Courts of any of the counties named in this Act, shall be returned to the terms of said Courts as established by this Act; and all such process and writs, shall have the same force and effect as if they had originally been so returnable, and that all cases of appeals from the decisions of the District Courts in this District shall be to the branch of the Supreme Court at the City of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Governor be, and he is hereby required to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der an election to be held in said District, on the first day of Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary next, for the election of a District Judge and District Attorney, and that said election shall be conducted in all respects according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all laws and parts of laws contrary to the provisions of this Act, be, and the same so far as they conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this Act, are hereby repealed, and that this Act take effect<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>19th December 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER IX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation of Ten thousand dollars to defray the Contingent expenses of the Sixth Legislature.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of Ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary be, and the same is hereby appropriated to pay the contingent expenses of the sixth Legislature; and that this Act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>22d December 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="191" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER X.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Clerk of the District Court of Washington County to transcribe certain records therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be. it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Clerk of the District Court of Washington county, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to transcribe into a well bound book, to be furnished by the county court of Washington county, for that purpose, the minutes of the District court of said county, contained in book, &#8220;D,&#8221; and when the same shall have been examined and approved by the county court of said county, the same shall have all the force and effect in law and equity, that the original could or should have, and all certified copies taken from the same shall be as valid and have the same force and effect as if taken from the original.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said Clerk shall receive such compensation for his services as shall be allowed and paid by said county court, not to exceed fifteen cents for each hundred words so transcribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>8th January 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting the consent of the State of Texas to the United States to construct Break-Waters, Jettys, Dams, and other Im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provements on the Coast of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the United States may exercise all power, rights and privileges necessary for the erection and construction of break<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />waters, jettys, dams and other works for the improvement of har<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bors, bays, arms of the sea and mouths of the rivers in this State as the United States may deem proper, and to take from the public do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />main of the State, and from private individuals, on paying just compensation, all stones, timber and earth necessary for such pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses, and to enact all such laws, not being contrary to the Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and laws of this State, as may be found necessary and proper for the protection of such works when constructed; Provided the Governor of the State shall have notice of all such contemplated works before the same are commenced, and no work shall be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />menced unless the Governor gives his consent to the same.</p>
<pb n="192" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 8th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Harrison County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office, be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent upon field notes No. 259 for one half league of school land made for the county of Harrison; and that this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 8th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to validate an election to be held in the fourteenth Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentative District, comprised of the Counties of Cass and Titus.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an election, to be held on the fourteenth day of Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, 1856, in the fourteenth Representative District of the State, composed of the counties of Cass and Titus, under and in accordance with a Proclamation of the Governor, of the date of December 28th, 1855, to fill the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of J. C. Guy, is hereby validated and declared to be as legal in all respects, so far as the time and manner of holding such election and returning and counting the votes, and issuing the certificate of election are con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerned, as if such election were held in strict compliance with the provisions of the laws regulating election now in force.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. (That) this act shall be in force from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 9th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix the salary of the Governor.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, the annual (192) <pb n="193" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>salary of the Governor of the State of Texas, shall be three thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>December 20th, 1855</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of Dallas County to levy an additional fax for the purpose of building a Courthouse.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county count of Dallas county is hereby authorized and empowered to levy an additional tax upon real and personal property of all persons subject to taxation in said county of Dallas, for the purpose of bulling a courthouse in said county; which shall be assessed and collected as other taxes are; Provided the tax here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized to he assessed or levied, shall not exceed the amount of the State tax in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall continue in force two years from and after its passage and no longer.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 9th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to change the name of Martha R. Eppinger to Martha R. Bonner.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the name of Martha R. Eppinger be changed to Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tha E. Bonner, and that this act take effect from and after its pas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 9th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Authorize Agents and Attorneys at Law to make Affi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />davits in certain cases.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whenever in the commencement or progress of any <pb n="194" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>suit or judicial proceeding, it may be necessary or proper for any party to such, suit or proceeding to make an affidavit therein, such affidavit may be made by an Agent or Attorney at Law of the party to such suit or proceeding, and any affidavit so made by such Agent or Attorney shall have the same force and effect as if made by the principal.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>January 11th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an Appropriation for the per diem pay and mileage of the Members of the sixth Legislature, and the per diem pay of the Officers of the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of seventy-five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the per diem pay and mileage of the members, and the per diem pay of the officers of the sixth Legislature of Texas, convened at Austin, on the 5th day of November, A. D., Eighteen Hundred and Fifty-Five, and that the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate and the Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives, shall be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thority for the Comptrolller to draw on the Treasurer for the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral amounts that the members and officers are respectively entitled to, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 14th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to &#8220;An Act to change the sixth and ninth Judicial Districts, and to define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of tire State of Texas, That the provisions of an act, entitled, &#8220;An Act to change the sixth and ninth Judicial Districts, and to define the time of holding the Courts therein,&#8221; passed during the present session of the Legislature, shall not be so construed as to prevent the Judge of the sixth district from holding the Fall Terms of the District Courts for eighteen hundred and fifty-five, in the <pb n="195" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>counties of Panola and Harrison of said District, as required by law, as it aforetime was, regulating the times of holding Courts in said District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 14th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the payment of six Companies of Mounted Volunteers that were mustered into the service of the State of Texas on the first day of November, A. D., 1854, under a requi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition of Brevet Major General Persifor F. Smith, and to pay the expenses incurred by said Companies.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted Toy the Legislature of the State of Texas, That each and every commissioned, non-commissioned of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficer, farrier, blacksmith, musician and private who belonged to the six companies of mounted volunteers mustered into the service of the State of Texas, on the first day of November, A. D., 1854, shall be entitled to pay for three months service therein.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the monthly pay of the commissioned officers, non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />commissioned officers, farrier, musicians, blacksmiths and privates shall be the same as that subsequently paid by the United States to said companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. In all cases where any member of said companies shall have died since being mustered into said service, payment of the amount due him under the provisions of this act shall be made to his executors or administrators, and if the said decedent should have no administrator, payment of the amount due him shall be made to the father, or mother, or legal representatives of said de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cedent, upon certificate of the Chief Justice of the county from which said decedent volunteered, that no administration had been had upon the said estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That each and every one of the persons appointed by the Governor of the State of Texas, under his proclamation of the 18th day of August, A. D., 1854, to receive said six companies of mount<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed volunteers at the places of rendezvous designated in said procla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mation, shall be entitled to receive fifty dollars for his services.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the sum of six thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated for the payment of the balance of accounts contracted <pb n="196" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>by file said six companies, which remain unpaid out of the appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation made by the Congress of the United States for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the additional sum of fity-five thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any monies in the Treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, for the purpose of carrying the provisions of this act into effect.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the Governor of the State of Texas shall appoint some suitable person to receive said appropriations from the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer of the State, and to pay out the same to the persons entitled thereto; and the person so appointed, shall enter into bond with one or more sureties for the faithful performance of his duties, and shall be entitled to receive such compensation therefor as the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor shall think right and proper, to be paid out of said appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said disbursing agent shall be authorized to pay out of the appropriation made by the sixth section of this act, any account duly certified by the proper officers, for expenses incurred in the furnishing, camp equipage, and in the transportation of bag<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage from the several places of rendezvous to the place where said companies were mustered into the service of the United States: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that in no case shall a greater sum than six dollars per day be allowed for the service of any waggon and team engaged in said transportation.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 14th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to re-organize the Eighth. Judicial District and define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of &#8220;An Act entitled An Act to amend the eigth and ninth sections of an act to establish the Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricts of the District Courts,&#8221; approved February 26th, 1848, be amended so as to read as follows: That the counties of Red River, Bowie, Cass. Titus, Hopkins, Hunt, Fannin and Lamar, shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose the eighth Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District courts in said District shall be held in the several counties therein at the time herein specified, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="197" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>wit: In the county of Red River, on the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Bowie, on the second Mondays after the last Mondays in Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Cass, on the fourth Mondays after the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Titus, on the seventh Mondays after the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Hopkins, on the ninth Mondays after the last Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Hunt, on the tenth Mondays after the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Fannin, on the eleventh Mondays after the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Lamar, on the thirteenth Mondays af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter the last Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process that have been, or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be issued from any of the District courts mentioned herein, shall be considered as returnable, and shall be returned to the terms as established by this act, and have the same force and effect as if the same had originally been made so returnable, and that all re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cognizances and bonds entered into by any person or persons in said courts with reference to the period of their respective sessions un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the laws heretofore in force, shall be and the same are hereby made obligatory upon the parties with reference to the terms of said courts respectively, as prescribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the provisions of all laws or parts of laws conflict<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing with this act, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>14th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to remove the Land Office of the Milam Land District from Cameron in Milam County, to Belton in Bell County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the District Surveyor of the Milam Land District, to cause all the records, maps and other documents belonging to or in anywise connected with the Land <pb n="198" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Office of the Milam Land District, together with the desks, ta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bles and other furniture belonging thereto, to be removed to the town of Belton, in Bell county, as soon as practicable, and the said Land Office shall remain and be kept in said town until otherwise provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Tliat all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, be, and the same is (are) hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>16th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the time of holding the District Courts in the Thirteenth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Courts of the Thirteenth Judicial District, shall commence in the county of Brazos on the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Robertson on. the second Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Falls, on the third Mondays of March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Limestone on the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Hill on the first Mondays after the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Navarro on the second Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Freestone on the fourth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Leon on the fifth Mondays after the fourth Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That all process which has been issued and made returnable to the several Courts of said District, shall be and are (is) hereby made returnable to the said courts respectively, at the periods of their session, as speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="199" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fied in this Act, and that all recognizances and bonds entered into by any person or persons in said courts, with reference to the period of their respective sessions under the laws heretofore in force, shall be and the same are hereby made obligatory upon the parties with reference to the terms of said courts as specified by this Act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws relative to tire time of holding courts in the Thirteenth Judicial District, be and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act be in force and effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>16th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish the Western boundary line of Tyler County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Eastern boundary line of Polk county as defined in an act, entitled, an act creating the county of Polk, approved March 30th, eighteen hundred and forty-six, be, and the same is hereby declared the Western boundary line of Tyler county, and this act shall take effect and be in force immediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>16th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for a special election for Judge of the First Judi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in consequence of the vacancy in the office of Judge of the First Judicial District of the State of Texas, the Governor be requested and required to order an election for Judge of said District, by the issuance of his proclamation, at least thirty days before said election, and that the return day to the chief justices of the several counties of said district, shall be the fifth day after the election, inclusive of the day of election, and that on the twentieth day after the election, the returns shall be opened at the seat of Government, and that the Governor de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />liver a certificate of election to the person elected, and the person receiving such certificate shall thereupon, without further delay, be fully authorized and empowered to hold the District courts <pb n="200" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of said District, and to discharge all the duties of such office; That the election in other respects shall be conducted according to the laws now in force.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That after the election provided for in the first section of this act, the law in relation to the election of District Judge of said First Judicial District, shall be as it aforetime was, and that this act take effect, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>16th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the transfer of certain Stock Bonds on certain conditions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That on the production of satisfactory proof to the auditor and comptroller, that Obadiah B. Smith is the equitable and just owner of four thousand dollars of the ten per cent. funded debt of June 7th, 1837, originally issued to Isaac Bridges, &#38; Co., it shall be the duty of said Auditor and Comptroller, to cancel the certificate<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />heretofore issued by them in favor of said Bridges, &#38; Co., and in lieu thereof issue a new certificate for said amount to the aforesaid Obadiah B. Smith, notwithstanding the evidence of transfer may differ from that prescribed by statute; Provided, That such certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate shall not issue for more than the scaled value of the original claim.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That this act take effect, from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>21st January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Comptroller to issue duplicates of certain lost certificates of stock on certain conditions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, It appears that there is standing to the credit of John Birdsall on the books of the Stock Commissioners, the sum of one thousand three hundred dollars of the ten per cent. fund created by act of June 7th, 1837; and Whereas, It appears from satisfactory proof, that said stock has been lost, and that W. B. P. Gaines is now the real and just owner of the same; therefore.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts shall issue <pb n="201" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to the aforesaid W. B. P. Gaines, certificates of stock of the ten per cent, fund of June 7th, 1837, as aforesaid, for the said sum of one thousand three hundred dollars, on his indemnifying the State in a bond for double said sum, with security to the satisfaction of said Comptrolller, that the aforesaid stock shall not hereafter become a charge against the Government.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>21st January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act defining the Seventh Judicial District, and the time of Holding Courts in the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Counties of Harris, Grimes, Madison, Walker, Montgomery and Galveston, shall constitute the seventh Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts shall commence in the seventh Judicial District; in the county of Grimes on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in Session two weeks; in the county of Madison on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in Session one week; in the county of Walker, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Montgomery, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in Session two weeks; in the county of Harris, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in Session four weeks; in the county of Galveston, on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in Session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process, that may have been or may hereafter be issued from any of the District Courts of the seventh Judicial District, as defined by this Act, shall be considered as re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turnable, and shall be returned to the terms as established by this Act, from and after it goes into effect, and shall have the same force and effect, as if the same had been so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the provisions of all laws so far as they conflict with this Act, be and the same are hereby repealed: Also, that this Act take effect, and be in force from and after the first day of Aug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ust A. D. 1856.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>21st January 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="202" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the Fifteenth Judicial District, provide for the election of a Judge and District Attorney thereof, and define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: (That, the counties of Liberty, Jefferson, Orange, Tyler, Trinity and Polk, shall constitute the Fifteenth Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts in the Fifteenth Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict shall commence in the county of Liberty, on the third Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September, and may continue in Session two weeks; in the county of Polk, on the second Mondays after the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Trinity, on the fourth Mondays after the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion one week; in the county of Tyler; on the fifth Mondays after the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Orange, on the seventh Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days after the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Jefferson, on the eighth Mondays after the third Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process which have been, or may hereafter be issued from any of the District courts of the seventh Judicial District, embraced in the Fifteenth Judicial District, shall be considered as returnable and shall be returned to the terms as established by this Act, and shall have the same force and effect, as if the same had been so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That it shall be the duty of the Governor to order an election for a Judge and a District Attorney for the Fifteenth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District, which election shall be held on the first Monday in August A. D. 1856, as provided by law for special elections to fill vacancies; and the returns of said election shall be made within thirty days after the day of election and shall be counted on the thirtieth day after said election, and a certificate of election shall be immediately issued by the Governor to the persons so elected, who shall thereupon proceed to discharge all the duties of their offices respectively. Said election shall, in all other respects, be governed by the general law regulating elections.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all appeals and writs of error, from the District courts of the Fifteenth Judicial District shall be returned to, and considered, and adjudicated by the Supreme Court holding ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="203" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sions at Galveston, and that this Act take effect from and after the second Monday in June A. D. 1856.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>21st January 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the purchase of a Site and erection for a Store and Warehouse and other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the Financial agent of the Texas State Penitentiary, shall under the direction of the Board of Directors, purchase a suit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able site for the erection of a Store and Ware-room, adjacent to the Penitentiary, for the reception, of manufactured goods and ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terials and garden for the convicts.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. So soon as the purchase shall be made, the Board of Directors shall prepare a plan for said building, and submit the same to the Governor for his approval or modification, which when so approved or modified, shall be erected by the superintendent, with the labor of the convicts.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The sum of tho thousand dollars is hereby appropriated for the purposes aforesaid, and purchase of materials, and the Comptroller of Public accounts is hereby required on the requisi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of said agent to draw his warrant on the State Treasurer in favor of the agent, for the same, or so much as may be required.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>23d January 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Creating the County of Wise.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Territory embraced within the following limits, to-wit: Beginning at the South-west corner of Denton county, thence north with the west boundary line of said county thirty miles, thence west thirty miles, thence south thirty miles, thence east to the place of beginning, shall comprise the county of Wise.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be, and is hereby made the duty of the Chief Justice of the county of Denton, to organize the said county of Wise of (on) the first Monday of May next, by order<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="204" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ing an election tor county officers, and conducting the same in all respects in conformity to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That so soon as the said county of Wise has been organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized as aforesaid, and the officers of the same qualified according to law, they shall enter upon the discharge of their respective offices; and all courts in and for said county shall be held at the Store House of Daniel Howell, until the county seat of said county shall be permanently located by the citizens thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That so soon as the county shall have been organized as aforesaid, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice and at least two of the county commissioners to select two or more places within five miles of the centre of said county to be run for the county seat of said county having due reference to donations that may be of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fered.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice to order an election to be held, giving at least fifteen days notice thereof, for the election of the seat of Justice of said county, the name of which shall be Taylorsville.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That a majority of the votes polled shall determine the location, and in the event that no place receives such majority in the first election, the Chief Justice shall order a new election putting in nomination the two places having received the highest number of votes in the first election, and the place which may receive the highest number of votes in the second election shall be the lawful county seat of said county. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>23d January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Conferring Power on County Courts and Town and City Corporate Authorities to Establish Quarantine Regulations.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county courts of the respective counties of this State, be and they are hereby authorized and empowered when ever in their judgment it may be necessary, to establish quarantine regulations in their respective counties or any part or parts thereof not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of this State; and any person offending against any such regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="205" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>lations, Shall on conviction thereof before any Justice of the Peace of the county in which the offence was committed, he subject to a fine of not exceeding one hundred dollars, or to imprisonment in the common jail of the county not exceeding thirty days, and the trial of all such cases shall be had and conducted in the same manner as is provided for the trial of other offences cognizable before Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tices of the Peace.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the corporate authorities of the respective Town and City municipal corporations in this State, be and they are hereby authorized and empowered whenever in their judgment it may be necessary to establish quarantine regulations in their respective Towns and Cities, not inconsistent with the constitution and laws of the State: and any person offending against any such regulations, shall be subject therefor, before any Justice of the Peace of the county where the offence was committed, and the proceedings shall be conducted against such offender in the corporate name of the Town or City where the office (offence) was committed, and on con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viction such offender shall be subject to a fine of not more than one hundred dollars to go to the use of the City or Town where the offence was committed, or to imprisonment not more than thirty days in the Town or City prison, where the offence was committed, and the trial of all cases arising under the provisions of this section shall be conducted in the same manner as is provided for the trial of other offences cognizable before Justices of the Peace.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed the <date>24th of January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Create the County of Atascosa.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That all the Territory comprised within the following limits shall be created into a new county to be called Atascosa, beginning at a point on the east line of Medina county five miles south of the Medina river; thence south along the east line of Medina county, to the south-east corner of said county, thence west- along the south boundary line of said county to the west line of survey No, 71, in District No. 2 of Castro&#8217;s colony; thence in a direct line to the south-west corner of Survey No. 230, in the same District; thence in a direct line to a point on the north boundary line of San Patricio county, one mile west of where the San Miguel creek crosses the same; thence along <pb n="206" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the north line of San Patricio county to the south-west boundary line of Karnes county; thence along said line to the north-west corner of Karnes county; thence north 39 deg. west, fifteen miles; thence in a direct line to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The chief justice of Bexar county shall be and is hereby outhorized and required after the passage of this act, to order an election for county officers of said county of Atascosa, stating the time and place of holding said election, which election shall be ordered and conducted in accordance with an act entitled, &#8220;an act to provide for the organization of new counties,&#8220; approved March 20th, 1848, and the chief justice of Bexar caunty shall qualify the chief justice of Atascosa county when elected, who shall then qualify the other officers elected of Atascosa county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of the county court of Atascosa county so soon as they are qualified, to locate the county seat of said county, by selecting at least two eligible sites therefor having regard to any donations of land that may be made for that purpose as well as to convenience of water, and when so selected the chief justice of said county shall order an election to fix said county seat, which shall be conducted according to the general laws respecting election for county officers, and if at the first election neither of the sites so selected shall receive a majority of all the votes cast, then the chief justice shall order another election to be held for the two sites receiving the highest number of votes, and the site receiving a majority of all the votes cast at any such election shall be declared the county seat.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. The county court of Atascosa county may purchase if necessary, or receive by donation, land not exceeding three hundred and twenty acres for the use of the county, and may lay off such suitable lots as may be necessary for public buildings, and offices and for public grounds, and proceed to sell the remainder, if any, of such portion thereof as they may deem necessary at public auc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, at such times and upon such terms and conditions as will most conduce to the interest of said county, and shall apply the proceeds thereof to county purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. The chief justice of Bexar county shall be entitled to receive three dollars per day for every day that he may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sarily employed or detained in holding said election, and in organiz<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said county of Atascosa, which sum shall be paid to him out of the county Treasury of Atascosa county.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. This act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>25th of January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="207" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Create the County of Erath.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the Territory lying within these limits, beginning on the north line of Bosque county, and the limits of Johnson coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty eight miles from the Brazos river; thence south 60 deg. west thirty miles; north 30 deg. west, thirty miles; thence north 60 deg. east thirty miles; thence south 30 deg. east, thirty miles to the be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginning shall constitute a county to be called Erath.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the county seat of said county shall be located at the town of Stephensville, and shall be called by said name, pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided the owner of the land shall make the donations to said coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty which he proposed on the fourth of July, 1855, said proposals be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing signed by said owner and filed in the county clerks office of Bosque county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Chief Justice of Bosque county shall as soon as practicable, order an election to be holden in said county of Erath for the purpose of electing a Chief Justice, County Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner, Sheriff, Clerks of the District and County Courts, and all other County Officers, and shall qualify them according to law, and after the election and qualifying of said officers, the said county of Erath shall be considered as organized, and the subsequent elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and qualifying said officers shall be governed by the laws gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erally in force, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>25th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Create the County of Comanche.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory lying within these limits, to-wit: Beginning at the south corner of Bosque county on the north west line of Coryell county; thence north 30 deg. west to the west corner of &#8220; Bosque county; thence south 60 deg. west to a point thirty miles, south 60 deg. west, from the south corner of Johnson county; thence north 30 deg. west to a point lying 35 miles north 30 deg. west from the upper line of Coryell county, thence south 60 deg. west, 30 miles; thence south 30 deg. east to the north boundary line of Lam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="208" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>pasas county; thence with the north boundary line of Lampasas county to the north-west corner of Coryell county, thence with the north boundary line of Coryell county to the beginning shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute a county, to be called the county of Comanche.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Jesse Mercer, Charles Campbell and Dr. Tuggle are hereby appointed commissioners with full power to organize the said county of Comanche, and it shall be their duty as soon as practicable after giving the notice required by law, to open and hold an election for Chief Justice, and County Commissioners, Sheriff, Clerks of the District and County Courts and all other county officers, and shall have power to qualify them as the law directs.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the county Commissioners who shall be elected as above provided for, shall have power to locate the county seat of said county at any place within five miles of the centre of said county, designating the name of such county seat, laying off the town, selling lots, selecting the land and lots for the use of said county, and causing to be erected suitable public buildings for the use of said county; and that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>25th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Confirming Certain Head Right Grants of Land Lying on the Boundary Line of Austin&#8217;s Colony and Robertson&#8217;s Colony.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Headrights of land granted to Colonists before the thirteenth day (13) of November, A. D. eighteen hundred and thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-five, and lying and being intersected or crossed by the boundary lines of Austin&#8217;s Colony and Robertson&#8217;s Colony, and being part in one of said colonies and part in the other, are hereby declared to be as valid, as if such head right were lying and being wholly within the Colony, where such head right grants were issued: Provided, that nothing herein contained shall be so construed as to effect (af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect) the right of third parties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall not extend to any grant which is fic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titious, forged, or otherwise fraudulent, and that this act take ef<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>25th of January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="209" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to &#8220;An Act to define the time of holding the District Courts in the thirteenth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Judge of the thirteenth Judicial District be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to hold a term of the District Court in the county of Madi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, to commence on the sixth Monday after the fourth Monday in March next, and to hold for one week unless the business is sooner disposed of: and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 25th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to confirm the titles of certain Pre-emption Settlers within the limits of Peter&#8217;s Colony.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all persons who settled as pre-emptors within the limits of the colony granted to W. S. Peters and others prior to the twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />first day of December, 1853, shall be entitled to the amount of land granted to pre-emption settlers by the law in force at the date of their said settlement by complying with all the provisions of the same: Provided, that when the lands have been surveyed by any legally authorized surveyor, it shall not be necessary to have the same resurveyed; and provided further, that in all cases of conflict of title, whether by location or pre-emption, the oldest genuine claim shall have the preference, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of Travis County to levy and collect a special tax.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of Travis county be, and they are hereby authorized and empowered to cause to be levied and col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected upon all the citizens and taxable property of the county, a special tax upon the same, not to exceed the State tax for one year.</p>
<pb n="210" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That the County Court shall apply the money so col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected for the purpose of assisting in paying for the building of the Court House and Jail now being erected in said county of Travis, and for no other purpose whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Kerr.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following territory shall be and is hereby created a county to be called Kerr, in honor of James Kerr, deceased, the first American settler on the Guadalupe river, to wit: Beginning at the south-east corner of Gillespie county on the line of Comal county; thence with the line of Comal county to the Cibolo creek; thence down the Cibolo, to the mouth of the Balcone&#8217;s creek; thence up the Balcone&#39;s to the west line of survey No. 408, made in the name of A. Gayton; thence in a direct line to the south-west corner of survey No. 98, in the name of J. E. Bettner; thence in the same course four miles; thence west to the north corner of survey No. 157, in the name of J. R. Bowles on the head of Wallace&#8217;s creek; and thence due west to a point twenty-three miles from said point, four miles from said Bettner&#8217;s survey; thence due north twenty-six miles; thence due east to the west line of Gillespie county; thence with the west and south lines of Gillespie county, to the place of beginning, containing an area of nine hundred and six square miles.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Dr. J. C. Ridley is appointed commissioner to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize said county, whose duty it shall be to order and hold an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for all county officers and a county seat, on the fourth Saturday in March, A. D., l856, which election shall be conducted according to existing laws regulating elections. The place receiving a majority of all the votes, shall be the county seat, and shall be called Kerrs<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ville unless the site selected shall already have a name, and said Rid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ley shall issue certificates of election to all persons elected and ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minister the constitutional oath to them, and he shall also, on the organization of the county, make out and file for record in the office of the County Court Clerk, a full return of said election, which shall be recorded by said clerk; Provided that if a site can be selected on the Guadalupe and not more than five miles from the geographical centre of the county, (to be ascertained by a <pb n="211" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>plot and certificates from the General Land Office,) the said county seat shall not be fixed at a greater distance than five miles from such centre; and provided further, that in case of-the failure to act of said Ridley, it shall be lawful for the Chief Justice of Bexar county to perform the duties herein required of him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to legalize the official acts of John H. Smither, as Clerk of the District Court of Bowie County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the election of John H. Smither, on the first Monday in August, 1855, as Clerk of the District Court of Bowie county, to fill the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of O. L. Poole, be, and the same is hereby declared to be valid for the unexpired term of said Poole; that is, up to the first Monday in August, 1858, and until the successor of said Smither is elected and qualified; and all the official acts of said Smither as such Clerk, done in pursuance of law, shall be as legal and valid as if said Smither had been elected at the regular time of such District Clerks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>26th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPEER XLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Bandera.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the following territory be and is hereby created a county, to be called Bandera: beginning at the North-west corner of survey No. seventy-eight, in the name of Daniel Ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nold, on the Medina river; thence in a direct line to the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of Kerr county, on the Baleones creek on the West bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary line of A. Gayton&#8217;s survey; thence with the South bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary of Kerr county, to its South-west corner; thence due West eleven miles; thence due south, twenty-six miles; thence due east to the line of Medina county; thence with the boundary of <pb n="212" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Medina county, to the place of beginning, containing an area of nine hundred square miles.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Charles de Montal, be, and he is hereby appointed a commissioner to order and hold an election in said county, after giving ten days notice according to law, for all county officers and a seat of Justice, which shall be held according to the general law regulating elections. He shall issue certificates to all persons elected, and administer to them the constitutional oath of Office. The place receiving a majority of all the votes shall be the County Seat, and so soon as said county may be organized, he shall make out and file for record in the office of the county court clerk, a full return of said election, which shall be recorded by said clerk: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that should said named Commissioner fail to act, it shall be lawful for the Chief Justice of Medina county to perform the duties herein required of him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this Act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>26th January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the County Court of the County of Brazoria, to establish, discontinue and regulate public and pri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vate Roads in said County, and to cause public Roads and Bridges to be constructed and kept in good repair.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no road can be established, changed or discontinued in said county, except by an order of the County Court of the said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That every application for a new public road in said county, must be made by at least twelve house-holders in the Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tices precinct in which the road is desired, and must specify the place of beginning and the termination of the road proposed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That notice of the intention to make application for a new road must be given by advertisements set up at the door of the Court-house of the county, and at two other public places near which said road will pass, for at least twenty days before such ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication is made.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That when such application is made and publicly read, the Court, upon proof that notice has been given as required by the preceding section, shall, if such road be deemed necessary, appoint three disinterested and competent house<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="213" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>holders of the county, who have not applied for the establishment of such road, and who do not live in the direction of it, to review the ground over which it is proposed to be established.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That before such review shall take place, the reviewers shall be sworn faithfully and impartially to discharge the duties as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed them, and shall proceed to review the route proposed. If they deem it of public utility, they shall lay out and mark such road on the most eligible ground, but they shall not run it through any person&#8217;s enclosure, without his consent, unless a good road can not otherwise be obtained.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the reviewers may examine routes other than that proposed, and may report in favor of the route which they may deem the most expedient, giving their reasons for their preference, describing the road iaid out by courses and distances, and stating the conveniences and inconveniences which will result to the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />habitants and to the public, from the establishment of such road.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the reviewers shall also report the names of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prietors of the land over which the road proposed by them would run, and their report, when made, shall be publicly read.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. In at if twelve house-holders of the precinct in which it is proposed to establish the road, or any part thereof, shall at the term of the Court at which the report of the reviewers is submitted, object to the establishment of said road, it shall be the duty of the Court to appoint three reviewers, who shall take the same oath which reviewers are required to take, and shall then proceed in the manner prescribed by this act, for reviewing roads in the first in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stance.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That if a majority of such reviewers, report against the utility of such road, it shall not be established, and the original ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plicants therefor shall pay the costs that may have accrued.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That if such reviewers report in favor of such road, and their report is sustained by the Court, the objectors shall pay the costs of the reviewers.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That upon the report of the reviewers, recommend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the establishment of a road, if no objection has been made thereto, as prescribed by the foregoing sections of this act, or in case such objection has been made, and the re reviewers have reported in favor of the establishment of the road, unless the opinion of the Court be against the application, citations shall be issued to the owners of the land over which it is proposed the road shall be established, to show cause, if any they have, <pb n="214" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>why it should not be so established. The citations shall be served on such of them as may be in the county, and upon the agents of such as are not.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That upon the return of the process executed, the County Court may hear evidence, and fix upon the amount of com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pensation that shall seem fit to each of the proprietors over whose land the road proposed shall run, but if any proprietor be dissatis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied with the decision, he may appeal therefrom to the District Court of said county, where the case shall be tried de novo and the damages assessed by a jury.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That when a new road is established, the county shall pay to each proprietor of the land over which it may pass, the dam<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ages he may thereby sustain.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. That no road shall be ordered to be opened through a lot of land in any town, or through any orchard, or burying ground, or buildings, or through any yards without the consent of the owner.</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">CHANGE OF ROADS.</head>
<p>Sec. 15. that any proprietor wishing to cultivate land through which a road may run, may apply to the County Court for permis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion to turn the road on some other portion of his own land, or on the land of some other person consenting thereto at his own ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pense, and the court shall appoint reviewers who shall proceed to review the road, and the route proposed, and shall under oath re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />port the respective distances, and the situation of the ground of the established and proposed road.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That if in the report of the reviewers, the court shall be satisfied that the public will not be materially injured by such change, an order shall be made that it be so changed, and so much of the old road as may lie between the points of intersection shall be vacated.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">DISCONTINUANCE OF ROADS.</head>
<p>Sec. 17. That when twelve house-holders of a precinct through which any public road may pass, shall make application to the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty court to have such road discontinued as unnecessary, such ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plication shall be publicly read at the time it is presented and con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued without further proceedings, till (until) the next term of the court.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That at the next term of the court after that at which the application was presented, it shall be again publicly read on the first day of such court, and if no remonstrance is made thereto in writing, signed by twelve householders of the precinct in which the road is proposed to be discontinued, the <pb n="215" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>court shall make an order discontinuing such road or so much thereof as the applicants have asked to have discontinued with in their precinct.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That if no remonstrance be presented, the court shall appoint reviewers, who shall proceed and be governed as in other cases, and the judgment of the court in (on) their report, shall be conclusive.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. That every public road shall be at least thirty feet wide, unless the County Court order it to be less. The Court may order a road adjoining a town or village to be therefrom wider for any distance not exceeding eight hundred yards&#8212;in such case the width shall not exceed sixty feet.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">APPOINTMENT AND DUTIES OF SURVEYORS OF ROADS.</head>
<p>Sec. 21. That it shall be the duty of the county court of said county, at their first regular term in every year, to appoint for each justices precinct, a surveyor of the public roads therein, who shall serve for one year, and until another is appointed in his stead.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. That the court shall within fifteen, days, after such appointments, cause a written notice to be delivered to each person so appointed, informing him of his appointment, and designating the public roads within his precinct, which the Sheriff or any other officer shall serve by delivering a copy to each of such persons, within twenty days after they are received.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. That when such notice is served, it shall be the duty of the person appointed to inform the Sheriff whether he accepts or refuses the appointment, and the Sheriff shall make an endorse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of such acceptance or refusal on the back of the notice, and return the same to the Chief Justice within twenty days after the service thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That if the person appointed does not inform the Sher<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iff when such notice is served, that he refuses to accept of the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment. he shall be deemed to have accepted the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. That if the Sheriff or other officer fail to discharge the duty prescribed by the two preceding sections he shall be fined by the county court twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. That if any person shall refuse to accept the appoint<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of surveyor of roads, he shall be fined by the county court in any sum not less than twenty nor more than thirty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That every surveyor shall cause to be opened such new roads as the county court shall order, and shall superintend, the public roads of his precinct, and shall cause them to be kept in as good condition as the means furnished him will permit.</p>
<pb n="216" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 28. That he shall cause them to he kept clean, clear of rocks and other obstructions, of necessary width, and secure from the falling of dead timber thereon, He shall cause such causeways, ditches and culverts to be made as shall seem to be necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 29. That he shall cause to be constructed such bridges as the county court shall order, which shall be at least twelve feet wide, and shall be safe, and shall in every instance be secured by a strong railing on each side.</p>
<p>Sec. 30. That he shall cause to be erected and kept at every fork or crossing of public roads within his precinct sign boards, each pointing in the proper direction, with plain inscriptions there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />on in letters and figures, of the names and distances of the most important places to which the road leads. He shall set up at the end of each mile, neat and permanent mile-posts, marked with the number of miles to the Court House, or other noted place to which the road may lead; and all the improvements required by this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion shall be kept in good repair.</p>
<p>Sec. 31. That in case the road fund shall not be sufficient to make all the improvements required by the preceding section, such improvements shall be made in such order as the court may pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 32. That a surveyor may take from any convenient unim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved land so much wood, stone or earth as may be necessary to the construction or repair of the road, or any bridge or causeway thereon, and may for the purpose of draining the road, cause a ditch to be cut through any adjoining lands, Provided: that such wood or other articles be not taken from, and such ditch be not cut through any lot in a town or city, or without the consent of the owner.</p>
<p>Sec. 33. That if the owner of such lands, shall think himself thereby injured, and he and the surveyors can not agree upon what would be a just compensation therefor, each shall select a com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />petent person to estimate, under oath the injury sustained by rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son of anything done under the preceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 34. That in case of disagreement, the person selected, shall select an umpire, who shall be in like manner sworn to estimate the damage according to the best of his understanding. If either party be dissatisfied with their decision, the matter shall be referred to the county court, and the decision of the court shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive.</p>
<p>Sec. 35. that no contract for the construction of any bridge shall be valid, unless it was made by the order, and has received the approval of the county court.</p>
<p>Sec. 36. That the county court of said county shall have <pb n="217" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>power and is hereby required to appropriate all money levied and collected as a road fund, and all fines and forfeitures levied for any violations of the provisions of this act to the repair and opening of roads in the several precincts of said county and to order and direct the payment of such portion of the amount unappropriated to each precinct to the order of the surveyor thereof, from time to time, as necessity may seen to require.</p>
<p>Sec. 37. That each surveyor who may receive money on the or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der of the county court, under the provisions of this act, shall at the next regular term of the county court, which may be held after the expiration of three months from the time such money was re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived, make a report to the court, and submit his account of, and vouchers for all money disbursed by him in opening and repairing roads in his precinct; and every surveyor who shall neglect or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fuse to submit his account for settlement as required by this section, may be thereto compelled by the county court, by fine and attach<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment.</p>
<p>Sec. 38. That it shall be the duty of each surveyor to enquire into every offense punishable by this act, which may be com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mitted within his precinct, and to report all such as may come to his knowledge to the next county court, stating the offence the name of the offender and of the witnesses by whom it may be proved.</p>
<p>Sec. 39. That when any judgment has been rendered for any penalty for a violation of this act, it shall be the duty of the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of the precinct where the act was committed for which the penalty accrued, to cause due diligence to be used to enforce the collection of the judgment, and he shall also see that its proceeds are paid into the county treasury.</p>
<p>Sec. 40. That the county court shall have power to allow to each surveyor, a reasonable compensation for his services, which shall in no case exceed two dollars for each day he was actually and neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sarily employed in the performance of duties prescribed by this act, but no such allowance shall be made unless the account for such services is supported by affidavit, and the court is satisfied that they have been rendered; such account and the affidavit supporting it shall be filed and kept in the office of the county clerk.</p>
<p>Sec. 41. That if any surveyor of roads neglects to discharge any duty required of him by this act he may be fined by the county court, in any sum not exceeding one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 42. That the county court shall at all times have power to discharge any surveyor of roads and appoint another in his stead, and to fill any vacancy which may have happened in any precinct within the county.</p>
<pb n="218" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 43. That any person who has served as surveyor for one year, or who has paid a fine for refusing to accept an appointment to that office shall not within five years thereafter be appointed sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of roads without his consent.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">FORFEITURES FOR VIOLATING THIS ACT.</head>
<p>Sec. 44. That if any person shall wilfully fill up a ditch or cul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vert cut for draining a public road, or fill up any part thereof, or shall put any obstruction upon it, or shall wilfully deface, injure or destroy any mile post, sign-board, bridge or causeway, he shall in addition to the costs of repairing such injury, forfeit and pay for each and every such offence twenty dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 45. That if any person shall obstruct a public road for twenty-four hours by any fence, bar, or other impediment, he shall forfeit and pay twenty dollars, and two dollars for every additional twenty-four hours such fence, bar, or impediment shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued.</p>
<p>Sec. 46. That every person who shall be engaged in running any horse race upon a public road shall forfeit and pay ten dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 47. That a forfeiture incurred under any provision of this act may be recovered by suit in the name of the county before any court of competent jurisdiction; and if the offense was committed by an infant, the forfeiture shall be recovered of his parent; if by a slave, it shall be recovered of his owner; and if by an apprentice of his master.</p>
<p>Sec. 48. That it shall be the duty of the county court of said county to cause suits to be commenced and duly prosecuted for every violation of any provision of this act where it is probable the offence can he proven and the forfeiture collected.</p>
<p>Sec. 49. That when the county court shall cause any suit to be commenced to recover a forfeiture for a violation of any provision of this act, it shall be the duty of the surveyor of the precinct in which the act was violated, to cause to be issued and served all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess which may be necessary to procure the attendance of the wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses for the county, and he shall also give to the prosecution of all such suits, such personal attention as the interest of the county shall require.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ROAD FUND.</head>
<p>Sec. 50. That in addition to the State tax imposed by law, then shall be assessed and collected for each and every year, an ad valorem tax, not exceeding six cents upon each hundred dollars value of the property on which the State tax is im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed, and fifty cents upon every person upon whom a tax is imposed by law, which when collected, shall be paid into the <pb n="219" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>treasury of the said county, and shall with the fines, penalties and forfeitures collected under the act, constitute a road fund for said county, Provided: that any person upon whom, or whose prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty the tax herein provided for shall have been imposed, shall be at liberty to liquidate the amount of such tax by working upon the road in the precinct of his residence, at the rate of one dollar per day for each hand furnished; Provided: also, that the taxes levied in each precinct shall be expended upon the road within the limits of the same, if the same may be advantageously done, and provided also, that no person shall be exempt from paying a road tax, unless the work done by him, is at a time when he may be called on by the surveyor.</p>
<p>Sec. 51. That it shall be unlawful for the county court to appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priate any portion of the road fund to any purpose other than those prescribed by this act, and if any court shall violate the provisions of this section, each member thereof voting for such mis-application, shall be individually liable to the county for the amount so mis-ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plied, for the recovery of which, suit shall be brought by the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Attorney, in the proper court in the name of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 52. That it shall be the duty of said county court; to make such appropriations from time to time, in order to carry out the ob<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jects of this act, as the wants of the several precincts and the inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est and convenience of the county shall require.</p>
<p>Sec. 53. That the county court may upon the application of any person through whose land a public road may run, make an order permitting such person to erect gates across such road, but the court may at any time thereafter make an order that such gates be discontinued.</p>
<p>Sec. 54. That when the county court may order that any gate across a public road shall be discontinued, it may at the same time, make a further order, that unless such gate be removed within a rea<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sonable time therein stated it shall be removed or abated by the sheriff of the county, or the surveyor of the precinct in which it is situated.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PRIVATE ROADS.</head>
<p>Sec. 55. That any person desirous of having a private road laid out for his convenience from his home or plantation to any public road or navigable water course, or from one public road to another, shall present an application therefor to the county court of said county, setting forth the reasons for desiring such road, and describing the points between which he desires the same to pass, and shall give to the persons through whose land such road is pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed, ten days previous notice of his intended application.</p>
<pb n="220" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 56. That if when such application is made, the applicant shall deposite a sufficient sum of money, to pay the necessary costs of reviewing the proposed road, the court shall appoint three dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />interested and competent householders to review the same, and the subsequent proceedings shall be such as are prescribed for the establishment of public roads.</p>
<p>Sec. 57. That if the court shall be of opinion that the road is necessary, an order shall be made establishing the same as a private road, not exceeding twenty feet wide, and the person applying for such road, after paying or tendering to the respective owners of the land through which it is to pass, the damages which have been assessed, may proceed to open the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 58. That no private road shall be established through any town lot, orchard, burying ground, building, yard or plantation, without the consent of the owner.</p>
<p>Sec. 59. That a private road may be discontinued wherever it shall appear to the satisfaction of the court, that its longer continu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance has become unnecessary.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">NOTICE TO BE GIVEN.</head>
<p>Sec. 60. That no order shall be made for the establishment of a road, public or private, until the owner of the land over which it is proposed that the read shall be established, shall have been duly notified of the application for such order.</p>
<p>Sec. 61. That if such owner reside within this State, or have any known agent residing therein, personal service of such application shall be made on such owner or agent, for such time before the order is made, as the court deem to be reasonable; but if neither the owner or his agent resides within the State, such service may be made by a publication of the substance of the application, for at least four successive weeks, in some newspaper published in said county; if no newspaper be published in the county, then publication may be made in the newspaper published nearest to the county seat of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 62. That in cases in which personal service has not been made, if the owner does not appear, the court shall make no order establishing the road, before the expiration of four months from the time of the making of the last publication required by the pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceding section.</p>
<p>Sec. 63. That if notice of an application to establish a road, either public or private, has not been personally served on the owner of the land over which it may be subsequently established, no law of limitation shall be construed to bar the right of such owner to receive damages therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 64. That this act be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>28th, January, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
<pb n="221" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Lampasas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the territory within the following limits, to wit: Be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginning at the north east corner of Burnet county; thence north west on a direct line to the south west corner of Coryell county; thence north 30 deg. west with the west line of Coryell county 30 miles to the north west corner of Coryell county; thence west to the Colorado river; thence down the middle of said stream with its mean<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ders to the north boundary line of Burnett county; thence east with said line to the beginning; shall be and the same is hereby erected into a new county; to be known by the name and style of Lampasas county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the county seat of said county of Lampasas shall be located at the present town of Burleson, which shall be called Lampasas, on the salt fork of the Lampasas: Provided, that the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prietor or owner of the unsold lots in said town shall donate and convey to said county such lots as may be required for all the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic buildings -of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Chief Justice of Coryell county shall within three months after the passage of this Act order an election for county officers which shall be advertised at three public places in the county of Lampasas, fixing the time and place of said election, which election shall be conducted according to all the laws govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing elections in this State; the said Chief Justice of Coryell county shall qualify the officers of the said county of Lampasas when elected, and shall receive such compensation for their (his) services for organizing said county as the county court thereof may allow.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That it is hereby made the duty of the District and coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty court Clerks of the counties of Coryell and Burnett immediately after the organization of the county of Lampasas to forward the un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />finished business which may be in the District and county courts of said counties in which the citizens of the county of Lampasas are interested to the proper authorities of Lampasas county upon the payment of costs.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its Passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="222" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the Fourth Judicial District, and to prescribe the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That from and after the passage of this Act, the counties of Comal, Kerr, Gillespie and Bexar, shall constitute the Fourth Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District courts shall commence in the county of Comal on the first Mondays of March and September, of each and every year, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Kerr, on the first Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Gillespie, on the second Monday after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Bexar, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process that have been or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be issued from any of the District courts of the counties men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned in the first section of this Act, and made returnable to any of the terms of said courts under the laws now in force, and all bonds and recognizances, that have been or may hereafter be made so returnable, shall be returned to the terms established by this Act, and shall have the same force and effect as if the same had been originally so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws and parts of laws, conflicting with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this Act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require certain suits pending in the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Courts in and for the Counties of Hill and Ellis, to be trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferred to the County of Johnson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all suits or proceedings now pending and unde<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cided in the District courts in the counties of Hill and Ellis, in which the defendant, or defendants are resident citizens of the county of Johnson, or in case said suit (suits) or proceeding (pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="223" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ceedings) is (are) for the recovery of land, where the land is sit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />uated in the county of Johnson, shall be transferred to the District court in and for the county of Johnson, and the said District court in and for the county of Johnson, shall have jurisdiction to try and determine said suits in the same manner as if the same had been originally instituted in said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Clerks of the District courts in and for the counties of Hill and Ellis, are hereby authorized and required to transmit to the District court in and for the county of Johnson all the original papers, together with a transcript of the proceedings had, in the suits or proceedings mentioned in the first section of this Act, and that this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the seventh section of an act to provide for the payment of six companies of mounted volunteers that were mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tered into the service of the State of Texas on the first day of November, A. D., 1854, under a requisition of Brevet Major General Persifer P. Smith, and to pay the expenses incurred by said companies, approved 14th January, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the seventh section of an act to provide for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of six companies of mounted volunteers, that were mustered into the service of the State of Texas, on the 1st day of November, A. D. 1854, under a requisition of Brevet Major General Persifer F. Smith, and to pay the expenses incurred by said companies, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved 14th of January, 1856, shall be so amended as to read as follows, viz: That the Governor of the State of Texas shall be, and he is hereby authorized to appoint suitable persons to pay off said six companies, at or near the places where they were severally organized, in accordance with the rules and regulations of the United States, for the payment of similar troops, which persons so appointed, shall each, give a bond, with good security for the faithful performance of his duties, and Shall be entitled to receive such compensation therefor, as the Governor shall think right and proper to be paid out of said appropriation; any of said troops may apply for and receive their pay at the place designated for their payment, or may apply for and receive the same from the State Treasurer. And all claims incurred for supplies, medical services, camp equipage, and transportation, and other expenses for said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="224" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>panies not exceeding the amount appropriated by said act, shall be paid by the State Treasurer. And this act shall take effect from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Llano.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the territory hereinafter described be, and the same is hereby erected and created into a new county, to be called Llano, to wit: Beginning at a point on the West bank of the Colorado river, three miles above the mouth of Sandy creek, thence due West thirty-eight miles, thence due North twenty-five miles, thence due East to the Colorado river, thence down the said river, with its meanders, to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Clement Oatman be, and he is hereby appointed a Commissioner to organize said new county, and it is hereby made his duty to do the same by ordering an election for county officers according to the general laws regulating elections; said election to be held on a day by him to be named, and due notice of the same to be given, in accordance with the law regulating elections, the said election to he held at a point or points within the limits of said county, to be by the said Oatman named, and duly published in said county; and when the returns of said elections shall have been made to the said Oatman, he shall issue certificates of election to the persons elected, and shall administer the oath of office to them in due form. He shall also ascertain by means of a plot and cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate from the General Land Office under the seal of the same, duly authenticated, the centre of said new county, and select two or more sites not exceeding five miles from the centre of said county, having respect for any donation of land that may be made for that purpose, as well as convenience of wood and water, and shall order an election from (for) the places so se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected for a county seat, which election shall be at the time and places of the election for county officers, as herein before pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided: and when the returns shall have been made to him, he shall declare the place receiving the majority of all the votes cast at the first election, the county seat of said county; Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, That if neither of the places so selected by the said Commissioner shall receive a majority of all the votes cast at <pb n="225" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the first election, the Chief Justice when legally qualified shall or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der a second election between the two sites which shall have re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived the highest number of votes at the first election, when the place receiving the highest number of votes east, shall be declared the County Seat, and shall be called Llano.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the County Court or said county, shall have power to purchase, if necessary, land not to exceed three hundred and twenty acres, for the use of said county, and shall lay off the same into suitable lots for a town, and after selecting, and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary for a court house, jail, clerks&#8217; offices, churches, school houses, and burying grounds, they shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to sell the remainder, or such portion thereof as they may deem necessary, at public auction, at such time and upon such terms as will most conduce to the interests of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Commissioner above named shall be entitled to three dollars per diem for every day that he is necessarily em<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ployed or detained in holding said election, and organizing said County of Llano.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of San Saba.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the territory hereinafter described be, and the same is hereby erected and created into a new county, to be called San Saba, to wit: beginning at the North-East corner of the county of Llano, on the West bank of the Colorado river, thence due West thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eight miles to the North-West corner of Llano county, thence North to the Colorado river, thence down the Colorado river, with its meanders, to the place of beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief Justice of Burnet county be, and he is hereby authorized to organize said new county, and it is hereby made his duty to do the same by ordering an election for county officers, according to the general laws regulating elections, said elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to be held on a day by him to be named, and due notice of the same to be given in accordance with the law reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ulating elections, the said election to be held at a point or points within the limits of said county, to be by the said Chief Justice of Burnet County named and duly published in said <pb n="226" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county, and when the returns of said election shall have been made to him, he shall issue certificates of election to the persons elected, and shall administer the oath of office to them in due form. He shall also ascertain by means of a plot and certificate from the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office, under the seal of the same duly authenticated, the center of said new county, and select two or more sites not exceed<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing five miles from said center, having respect for any donation of land that may be made for that purpose, as well as convenience to wood and water, and shall order an election from (for) the places so selected for a county seat, which election shall be at the time and places of the election for county officers, as herein before provided, and when the returns shall have been made to him, he shall declare the place receiving a majority of all the votes cast at the first election, the county seat of said new county; Provided, That if neither of the places so selected by the said Chief Justice of Burnet County, shall receive a majority of all the votes cast at the first election, the Chief Justice of said new county when legally qualified, shall order a sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond election between the two sites which shall have received the highest number of votes at the first election, when the place receiv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the highest number of votes cast, shall be declared the county seat, and shall be called San Saba.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the County Court of said county of San Saba shall have power to purchase, if necessary, land not to exceed three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and twenty acres, for the use of said county, and shall lay off the same into suitable lots for a town, and after selecting and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary for a court house site, clerks&#8217; offices, churches, school houses, and burying grounds, they shall proceed to sell the remainder or such portion thereof, as they shall deem necessary, at public auction, at such time and upon such terms as will most conduce to the interest of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Chief Justice of Burnet County shall be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to three dollars per diem for every day that he is necessarily employed or detained in holding said election, and organizing said county of San Saba.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="227" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER L.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act giving the assent of the State of Texas to &#8220;An Act to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for the payment of such creditors of the late Republic of Texas as are comprehended in the Act of Congress of September nine, eighteen hundred and fifty,&#8221; which was passed at the sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ond session of the thirty-third. Congress of the United States, and approved February twenty-eighth, eighteen hundred and fifty-five.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, At the second session of the thirty-third Congress of the United States, an act was passed, entitled, &#8220;An Act to provide for the payment of such creditors of the late Republic of Texas as are comprehended in the Act of Congress of September nine, eighteen hundred and fifty,&#8221; which Act was approved February twenty-eighth, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, and provides, that in lieu of the sum of five millions of five per cent stock of the United States still due to Texas, under the provisions of the Act of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress of the ninth of September, eighteen hundred and fifty, the United States will pay to the creditors of the late Republic of Texas, who hold such bonds or other evidences of debt for which the rev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enues of that Republic were pledged, as were reported to be within the provisions of the said act of September the ninth, eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty, by the report of the late Secretary of the Treasury to the President of the United States, and approved by him on the thirteenth day of September, eighteen hundred and fifty-one, or which come within the provisions of said Act, according to the opinion upon the Texas compact, of the present Attorney General of the United States, addressed to the Secretary of the Treasury under date of September twenty-sixth eighteen hundred and fifty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />three, the sum of seven millions, seven hundred and fifty thousand dollars, to be apportioned among the said holders pro rata, the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest on the said debt, to be determined by the existing laws of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>And Whereas, By the terms of the said Act of the twenty-eighth of February, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, it is not to take effect until it shall be assented to by an Act of the Legislature of Texas, nor until the Legislature of said State shall pass an Act withdraw<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing and abandoning all claims and demands against the United States growing out of Indian depredations or otherwise. Now therefore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />&#8212;</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas. That the said State hereby consents and agrees, that in lieu of the five millions of five per cent, stock still due to said State, under the Act of Congress of the ninth of September, <pb n="228" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>eighteen hundred and fifty, the United States shall pay to the said described creditors, whose debts ostensibly amount, with interest thereon, according to the laws of Texas, to the sum of ten millions seventy-eight thousand and seven hundred and three dollars and twenty-one cents, of which, five millions, five hundred and two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand nine hundred and sixteen dollars and thirty-four cents, prin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cipal, and three millions two hundred and eighty-four thousand two hundred and forty-one dollars and ninety-four cents interest on said principal, are evidenced by the certificates of the Auditor and Comptroller of the State of Texas, issued under the provisions of &#8220;an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved March twentieth, eighteen hundred and forty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eight, and other acts of said State, passed subsequent thereto, ninety<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eight thousand five hundred and forty-five dollars and sixty-six cents of principal, and one hundred and three thousand two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and ninety-nine dollars and twenty-seven cents of interest on said principal are evidenced by ten per cent bonds of the Republic of Texas, issued under an act of Congress of said Republic, of the seventh of. June, eighteen hundred and thirty-seven, two hundred and eighty thousand dollars of principal, and three hundred and twenty-five thousand and five hundred dollars of interest on said principal are evidenced by a ten per cent bond issued by the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas to Frederick Dawson, for Naval Vessels, dated the thirteenth of September, eighteen hundred and thirty-eight, forty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />one thousand and one hundred dollars of principal, and forty-one thousand two hundred and seventy-one dollars and twenty-four cents of interest on said principal, are evidenced by ten per cent bonds of the Republic of Texas, issued under the provisions of an act of Congress of said Republic, entitled &#8220;An Act to provide for the redemption of the promissory notes of the Government, now in circulation, and for funding other liabilities of the Government,&#8221; approved fifth of February, eighteen hundred and forty; three hundred dollars of principal, and two hundred and thirty-six dollars of interest on said principal, are evidenced by eight per cent bonds of said Republic, issued under the provisions of the act of Congress of the said Republic, last before named, twenty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />four thousand and one hundred dollars of principal, and eight<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />een thousand three hundred and sixteen dollars of interest on said principal, are evidenced by eight per cent Treasury bonds of said Republic, issued under the provisions of an act of the Congress of said Republic, entitled &#8220;An Act for creating funds for the support of the Government for the year eighteen hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty,&#8221; approved February fifth, eighteen hundred <pb n="229" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and forty, two thousand nine hundred and thirty dollars of princi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pal, and eight hundred and ninety-one dollars and twenty-one cents of interest on said principal are evidenced by the first issue of promissory notes of said Republic, under the provisions of an act of Congress of the said Republic of the seventh of June, eighteen hundred and thirty-seven, sixteen thousand five hundred, and thir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-seven dollars of principal, and three thousand six hundred and fifty-one dollars and ninety-one cents of interest on said principal are evidenced by the second issue of the promissory notes of the said Republic, under the provisions of the act of the Congress of said Republic last before named, and three hundred and thirty-four thousand, eight hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-four cents of principal, are evidenced by the promissory notes of said Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic, without interest, issued under an act of the Congress of said Republic, of the nineteenth of June, eighteen hundred and thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nine, the sum of seven millions seven hundred and fifty, thousand dollars, to be apportioned among them pro rata; and the said State hereby assents to said Act of Congress of the twenty-eighth of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, with the foregoing declara<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the debts, that she understands to be embraced in its pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions, and among which the said sum of seven millions seven hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty thousand dollars are to be apportioned pro rata.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the State of Texas hereby withdraws and abandons all claims and demands against the United States growing out of Indian depredations or otherwise, which originated on or before the twenty-eighth day of February, eighteen hundred and fifty-five; Provided this abandonment shall not apply to claims of individuals for losses of property by the enemy.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted, that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the date of its final passage or approval.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>1st February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to better define the Western boundary line of Grayson County, and the Eastern boundary line of Cooke County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted Toy the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the southwest corner of Grayson county shall be at a point in the north boundary line of Denton county, five miles <pb n="230" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and seven eights of a mile west of the north east corner of said Denton county, and the said point to be the south east corner of Cooke county, and the division line between said counties shall be run due north to Red River from said corner.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Cooke county to cause the county surveyor of said county to make and es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablish said corner and run said division line, and it shall be the further duty of said Chief Justice to give twenty days notice to the Chief Justice of Grayson county, of the time appointed to run said division line, and it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Gray<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son county to appoint a competent surveyor, to meet the surveyor of Cooke county and assist in establishing said corner and survey said division line.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said counties of Cooke and Grayson to pay equally the cost of establishing the line aforesaid, and all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this Act, be, and the same are hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pealed, and-this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an Act entitled an Act making provisions for running and marking the boundary line between the State of Texas and the Territories of the United States of America.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the appropriation of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, appropriated by virtue of &#8220;an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled &#8220;an Act making provisions for running and marking the boundary line between the State of Texas and the Territories of the United States of America,&#8221; be, and the same is hereby renewed and continued in force.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="231" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Clerk of the County Court of Anderson County to transcribe into a bound book to be procured by him for that purpose all records hereinafter mentioned.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the clerk of the county court of Anderson county be required to transcribe book A, in a well bound book to be furnished by him for that purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. When said record is transcribed by him and approved by the county court, it shall have the same force and effect that the original record had, both in law and equity, and shall be preserved and considered the record of his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That when said record is made in accordance with the first section of this Act, and approved by the county court, said clerk shall be paid out of any money in the county of Treasury of the county of Anderson not otherwise appropriated, ten cents for every hundred words so transcribed; and this Act to be in force from and after its approval by the Governor.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the erection and furnishing a fireproof build<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to he used as a General Land Office for the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the sum of forty thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, or so much thereof as may be necessary for the erection, completion and furnishing of a tire proof building to be used as a General Land Office for the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor, Commissioner of the General Land Office, Treasurer and Comptroller shall act as Commissioners for the erection, completion and furnishing of said building; and they shall cause the same to be built in the most durable manner, and to be fire proof in its construction; the dimensions and general plan, and furnishing of the said building to be left to the judgment and discretion of said Commissioners: Provided, the whole costs of said building and of furnishing the same shall in no case exceed the sum of forty thousand dollars hereby appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further enacted: That the said Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="232" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ers shall cause the said building to be erected upon the reserved half of Block one hundred and thirty-six (136) bounded on the north by College Avenue, and on the west by Brazos street; and they shall advertise the plan of the same and let it out by contract to the lowest, best bidder, taking obligations of the contractor or contractors as the ease may be, in double the amount of his or their bid, payable to the State of Texas, to be void only upon condition of the faithful performance of his or their contract in the premises.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LV.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTION.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Granting Leave of Absence to Joel L. Ankrim, Judge of the Elev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That leave of absence from the State of Texas, is hereby granted to Joel L. Ankrim, Judge of the eleventh Judicial District, for the period of three months, at such time as may suit his con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venience: provided, that such absence shall not interfere with the holding of the courts of his district, at the regular time fixed by law.</p>
<p>This Resolution shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d of February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act, Granting Pelican Island, in Galveston Bay, to the Cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of the City of Galveston.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the State of Texas hereby relinquishes to the cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poration of the city of Galveston all her right, title and inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est in the Island known as Pelican Island, situated in Galveston Bay and north of the city of Galveston: provided, this relin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quishment on the part of the State shall not prejudice the rights of any third party.</p>
<pb n="233" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d Feb., 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to Define the time of holding the District Courts in the County of Cameron.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Court of Cameron county, being one of the counties in the twelfth Judicial District, shall hereafter be begun and held on the first Monday&#8217;s of July and January of each year, for the period of two years after this act shall take effect, and may continue in session four weeks at each term.</p>
<p>The first term of court held under the provisions of this act, shall commence and be holden on the first Monday in July, 1856; and after the expiration of said period of two years, the terms of said court shall be held in said county on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September in each year, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all process, that may have heretofore issued or that may hereafter be issued before the time herein established for the commencement of the first term of said court shall be deemed and taken as if returnable at such term whether specified in such process or not, and this act shall be in force and take effect from and after the first day of February, 1856.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d Feb., 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the purchase of a supply of the Texas Digest for the use of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to contract for three hundred copies of the Texas Digest, Provided, he can do so at twenty per cent. less in proportion to the printed matter contained therein than is paid for the Texas Reports.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a sufficient amount of money is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />printed to make said purchase, and that the Treasurer is hereby <pb n="234" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>authorized to pay over such amount to the order of the Governor, countersigned by the Comptroller, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2d, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Live Oak, and attach it to the four<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that territory Comprised within the following limits, to wit: Beginning at the junction of the East and West Aransas rivers: thence in a direct line parallel to the upper line of San Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tricio county, in a south-western direction forty-two miles; thence in a direct line to the Laredo and San Antonio crossing of the Rio Frio, on the upper line of San Patricio county; thence with said line to the line of Karnes; thence along the line of Karnes and Goliad counties to the beginning, be and the same is hereby created into a new county. to be called the county of Live Oak.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That John Powell, George W. Wright, Wm. Gambell, Henderson Waller, D. L. Wood, H. Gussett, James B. Lewis, and James M. Grover, be and they are hereby appointed commissioners to locate the county site of said county, and that they may purchase, or receive by donation, any number of acres of land not exceeding six hundred and forty, on such terms as they may arrange, for the use of said county and shall proceed to lay off two hundred acres of said land into suitable town lots, and after selecting and setting apart such lots as may be necessary for Court House, Clerks Offices, Jail, Churches, School Houses, Burying Grounds and other public purposes; they shall proceed to sell the remainder, or such portion thereof as they may deem necessary, at such time and on such terms as they may think best for the interest of said county, by offering the same at public auction after giving due notice of time and place, and they shall apply the proceeds thereof to the payment of a fair installment on the cost of the land, if said land is acquired by pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase, to the expense of surveying the town tract and to the erec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of suitable county buildings for the use of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the residue of said land shall be laid off into farm lots and, after paying for county buildings and for the land purchased by said commissioners, the proceeds of sales <pb n="235" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall be applied under the direction of the County Court to school purposes in said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That a majority of said commissioners shall be compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent to act in the duties of their appointment and they shall con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue to perform the duties of county commissioners, until the County Court is duly organized in said county when their functions shall cease.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That they shall locate said county site near the Nueces river, above the high water mark, convenient to timber and water, and as near the centre of said county as practicable, and name the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said commissioners at the next regular election shall order the polls to be opened as the law provides, at such places in said county as they may appoint, giving due notice thereof, and the election returns shall be made to said commissioners, any one of whom is authorized and empowered to administer the necessary oath of office to the county officers who may be elected, and take the bonds of office required by law as the law directs, and the offi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cers thus elected and qualified, shall proceed at once to discharge the duties of their respective offices; until such officers are elected and qualified those in authority in Nueces and San Patricio coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties shall continue their functions in the territory of said new coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty taken from their respective counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That said commissioners shall report to the Chief Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of said county at the first regular term of the County Court, all monies received by them on sales of lots at the county site and how expended, and at the same time deliver to him all papers held by them for the county, and pay over to the County. Treasurer all monies remaining in their hands for the use of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. After the requirements of the section last preceding are fully complied with, and not before, the said commissioners shall be entitled to receive for their services, estimating only the time of actual service, such compensation as the County Court shall allow, not exceeding two dollars each per day.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the Assessor and Collector of San Patricio county, and of Nueces county, shall respectively make out and transmit to the State Treasurer, on or before the first of October, 1856, that portion of the scholastic population returned for 1855 and 1856, and on or before the first of October, 1857, that portion of the scholastic population returned for 1857, which by this act becomes attached to said new county, and the apportionment of the school fund therefor shall be drawn by said county, as provided for by law.</p>
<pb n="236" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 10. That the county hereby created shall be attached to and form a part of the fourteenth Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2nd, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide a permanent and safe Building for the use of the State Department, the Executive and the Attorney General of the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That upon the completion of the new Land Office, and the vacation of the present one by the commissioner of said office, the Secretary of State be and he is hereby authorized and required to occupy one half of the building now used as a General Land Office, for the business and uses of the State Department.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted, That the Governor and the Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney General are hereby authorized and required to occupy the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />maining half of said building, upon its being vacated by the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of the General Land Office, and to use the same as a per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manent building, in which to transact the business of their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective offices.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2nd, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making appropriations for the Use and support of the State Government for the Years 1856 and 1857.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be, and the same are hereby appropriated for the support of the government of the State for the years 1856 and 1857, viz:</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT.</head>
<p>For salary of the Governor, three thousand dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Private Secretary, nine hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses, five hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For furniture for Executive office, three hundred dollars.</p>
<pb n="237" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">DEPARTMENT OF STATE.</head>
<p>For salary of Secretary of State, eighteen hundred dollars an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For salary of Clerk in the State Department, nine hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars annually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses, two hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Printing, three hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Postage two hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Stationary, one hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Porter hire and Wood, one hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>Desks and other Furniture for Office six hundred dollars to pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase useful books.</p>
<p>For employment of additional service in the office of the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary of State, for the purpose of furnishing the Public Printers with copies of the laws, within the time required by law,fifty dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">SUPREME COURT.</head>
<p>For salary of the three Judges of the Supreme Court, annually two thousand dollars each.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of three branches of the Supreme Court, one thousand dollars each, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>Prining reports three thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Expenses of fitting up branches of the Supreme Court at Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton and Tyler, one thousand dollars each.</p>
<p>For increase of Supreme Court Library to be expended under direction of the Supreme Court Fifteen hundred dollars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">ATTORNEY GENERAL.</head>
<p>For salary of Attorney General, eighteen hundred dollars an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of Attorney General&#39;s Office, two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty, dollars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">DISTRICT COURTS.</head>
<p>For salary of the District Judges, seventeen hundred and fifty dollars each annually.</p>
<p>For salary of the District Attorneys five hundred dollars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TREASURY DEPARTMENT.</head>
<p>For salary of the Treasurer, eighteen hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Clerk nine hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses two hundred dollars annually.</p>
<pb n="238" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For Stationery, Postage and Printing one hundred and fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">OUTSTANDING LIABILITIES.</head>
<p>For G. Kerchberg for repairs of Iron Safe, fifty-two dollars, and for drilling vent holes, and putting iron pipes through the walls of Treasury vault twelve dollars.</p>
<p>For Deats and Brush for Four Tin Cases to preserve United States Bonds in, ten dollars.</p>
<p>For Teneyck&#8217;s and Deiterich for four yards oil silk to envelope United States Bonds, four dollars.</p>
<p>For Coney&#8217;s account paid to Negroes for removing Iron Safe, Five dollars and fifty cents.</p>
<p>For B. Roberts for Shelving Vault, Twelve dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">COMPTROLLER&#8217;S OFFICE.</head>
<p>For Salary of Comptroller, eighteen hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Clerk, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Clerk of Tax Bureau, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Five Assistant Clerks, nine hundred dollars each an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses, two hundred and seventy-five dollars annually.</p>
<p>For stationary and books, three hundred and fifty dollars an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For printing, three hundred and seventy-five dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Postage three hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For outstanding claims against Comptroller&#8217;s Office, one hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For Blank Assessment Rolls if required by law, three hundred and seventy-five dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of one Draftsman to be employed for one year eleven hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For salary of three additional Clerks, to be employed for one year, nine hundred dollars each.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">TREASURY BUILDING.</head>
<p>For Ragland, for repairs on Chimneys, seventy-two dollars&#8212;C. M. Laughlin, for flushing with zinc, and painting roof of Treasury building, one hundred and fifteen dollars.</p>
<p>For G. Kerchberg for pumps, repairs of doors, and locks, twenty dollars and fifty cents.</p>
<p>For amount of outstanding claims, two hundred and seven dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars and fifty cents.</p>
<p>For repairs and repairing windows one hundred and sixty dollars.</p>
<pb n="239" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For Porter hire for Treasury building, two hundred and fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAND OFFICE.</head>
<p>For salary of Commissioner of General Land office, two thousand dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Clerk, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Translator, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Draftsman, twelve huudred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For salary of two assistant draftsman eleven hundred dollars each annually.</p>
<p>For salary of four assistant draftsmen, one thousand dollars each annually.</p>
<p>For salary of eight clerks, nine hundred dollars each annually.</p>
<p>For salary of twelve second clerks, nine hundred dollars each an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For stationary seven hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Postage two hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses, two hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For fire wood, one hundred and fifty dollars annually.</p>
<p>For Printing blanks, fifty dollars annally.</p>
<p>For Porterage one hundred and eighty dollars annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PUBLIC PRINTING.</head>
<p>For printing Laws, Journals, Reports, Bills, Newspapers, &#38;c., for the use of the Sixth Legislature, Seventeen thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">MISCELLANEOUS.</head>
<p>For fencing the grounds around the Governor&#8217;s house, furnishing house, digging well, &#38;c., to be expended under the direction of the Commissioners of Public buildings, six thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For Henry Tierwester, James M. Day, Rolla M. Davis, James W. Nichols, John B. Thacker, David Cole, Michael Short, Thomas Bar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />net, and Thomas Norris, one hundred dollars each annually to be paid in semi-annual installments.</p>
<p>For S. M. Swenson as per account against Executive Department, forty-six dollars and fifty-five cents.</p>
<p>For charges on two packages forwarded to Governor Bell in 1853, two dollars and seventy-five cents.</p>
<p>For Payne and Phillips, for Portable steps for lamps in the Sen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ate Chamber, nine dollars and fifty cents. Notary&#8217;s fee fifty cents.</p>
<pb n="240" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For Librarians of three branches of the Supreme Court, three hundred dollars each annually.</p>
<p>For F. T. Duffau&#8217;s account two hundred and seven dollars and eighty one cents.</p>
<p>For balance for Printing the Laws, of the extra session of 1853, in the, Spanish Language, three hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For A. H. Cook for painting the roof of the capitol, three hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars, which sum is to be paid to said Cook, when the roof of the Capitol shall be secured against leakage, and the weights shall be attached to the windows of the capitol, and for furnishing iron in the erection of the capitol two hundred and fifty-seven dollars and fifty-six cents.</p>
<p>For stationary for the seventh Legislature, one thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For pay of Audited certificate No. 301, dated February 5th, 1842, three hundred and twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For balance due the late Secretary of the Senate for recording Journals of the Senate of the late Republic and State of Texas, under an act passed February 16th, 1852, as certified to by the commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners appointed to examine the work, four hundred and ninety<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />two dollars and seventeen cents.</p>
<p>For amount due Wiley Tipper, for services in taking charge of the capitol under the direction of the Governor and Comptroller, one hundred and fifty-six dollars and sixty-six cents.</p>
<p>For amount of balance required to pay second class claims, now audited as reported by the Auditor and Comptroller, twenty-one thousand three hundred and eighty-three dollars and fifty-two cents.</p>
<p>For recovering fugitives from justice out of the State, five thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For indemnity of owners of slaves, heretofore executed, two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For indemnity of owners of slaves, executed in the years 1856, and 1857&#8212;$7000.</p>
<p>For balance of pay of the members and officers of the Sixth Legis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lature, five thousand four hundred and sixty dollars.</p>
<p>For contingent expenses of the sixth Legislature of the State, twenty thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For survey of land script surveyed prior to 1856, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For survey of Land Script annually five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pension of David Webb, one hundred dollars annually, pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able semi-annually.</p>
<pb n="241" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For J. M. Massey, as clerk in the Adjutant General&#8217;s Office, fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For J. H. Cole, for compiling map of Dallas comity, one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For Stephenson Archer, for compiling map of EI Paso Land Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For Brewaster and West, as council for State, in certain mandamus cases, one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For F. T. Duffau, for stationary for Legislature, fifty-three dollars and eight cents.</p>
<p>For pay of seven additional assistant clerks of General Land Office, retained during the month of December, 1855, four hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-six cents.</p>
<p>For payment of accounts of Messrs Martin and Stremme, from March 18th, 1855, to January 1st, 1856, fifteen hundred and sixty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />two dollars and twenty-six cents.</p>
<p>For paying Robert Hughes, Benjamin C. Franklin, George F. Moore, Franklin H. Merriman, James Willie, A. M. Lewis, W. S. Oldham, as special Judges of the Supreme Court, one hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars each.</p>
<p>For printing the report of the commissioners, appointed to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pare a code of civil and criminal procedure to be paid on the order of the Governor, five thousand dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">PENITENTIARY.</head>
<p>For salary of the Superintendant, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For pay of Directors and Physicians, fifteen hundred dollars an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually.</p>
<p>For pay of Financial Agent, twelve hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For support of the Penitentiary, fifiteen thousand three hundred dollars annually.</p>
<p>For completion and support of Cotton and Wollen Factories, pay of employees, purchase of raw material, and fuel nine thousand dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars annually, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For John S. Besser, Financial Agent, for extra services, in the purchase of Engine, Machinery (and so forth) and receiving and shipping the same, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That no claim shall be paid out of the contingen fund until the same shall have been examined by the committee on con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tingent expenses, and signed by the Chairman.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That one tenth of the annual revenue of the State arising from direct taxation, is hereby appropriated, and set apart for edu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cational purposes.</p>
<pb n="242" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 4. That during the recess of the Legislature the Public Printer shall return all work to the Secretary, of State, which may be required by law, ordered by either House of the Legislature to be done, which if correct will be approved by him, and the account for the same shall be audited by the comptroller, and provided further, that the account for printing the reports of the code of commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers shall be examined and approved by the Governor, and that this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>4th of February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the Assessor and Collector of Tar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rant County to collect the taxes now assessed in the former Terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory of Tarrant County, and now Parker County and pay over the same to the County Treasurer of said County of Parker.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Assessor and Collector of the County of Tarrant be, and he is hereby authorized and required to collect all the tax that<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />may be now assessed in the former territory of Tarrant County, (now Parker County,) and pay over to the county Treasurer of Parker County all monies so collected from the citizens of said Parker coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty, including the State and County tax, taking the receipt of said Treasurer for the same, which shall be a sufficient voucher in his settlement with the County Court of Tarrant county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2nd Feb. 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to re-organize the Second Judicial District, and fix the times of holding the Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That the second Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Bastrop, Caldwell, Guadalupe, Hays, Williamson, Burnet and Travis.</p>
<pb n="243" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Court for the county of Bastrop shall be held on the first Monday in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Caldwell, on the second Monday after the first Mondays in April and October, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks. In the county of Guadalupe, on the fourth Monday after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue fn session two weeks. In the county of Hays, on the sixth Monday after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Williamson, on the seventh Monday after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks. In the county of Burnet, on the ninth Monday, after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week. In the county of Travis, on the tenth Monday after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all laws and parts of laws, heretofore enacted, relat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the time of holding the several Courts in the said second Ju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dicial District, be and the same are hereby repealed; and that all process which has been issued, and made returnable to the several Courts of said District, shall be, and are hereby made returnable to the said courts respectively, at the periods of their session as speci<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied in this act, and that all recognizances and bonds entered into by any person or persons, in said courts with reference to the period of their respective sessions under the law heretofore in force, shall be, and are hereby made obligatory upon the parties with reference to the terms of said courts respectively. and as prescribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all process made returnable to the District courts of any of said counties, as prescribed by law at the present time, shall be returnable to the terms of said courts as herein prescribed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage; Provided, that the Judge of the second Judicial District shall hold the court for the Spring of the present year, in the county of Fay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ette on the fourth Monday in March, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2nd Feb. 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="244" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the liquidation and settlement of certain Meritorious Claims therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas: Certain persons furnished supplies and other articles, for the use of our army in the years 1835, &#39;36 and &#8217;37, at par, and whereas, the Auditor and Comptroller in the adjustment of said claims, audited the same at less than their actual value, but recom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mended the parties for the residue of the amount, to the favorable consideration of the Legislature; and whereas, it is the disposition of the government to award full justice to all those who rendered her aid in her revolutionary struggle, therefore</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That on the acceptance of this State of an act of the United States Congress, entitled an act to provide for the payment of such creditors of the late Republic, of Texas, as are comprehended in the act of Congress of September the 9th, 1850, which act was approved on the 28th day of February, 1855, it shall be the duty of the Audi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor and Comptroller of this State, to ascertain the difference between the pro Tata payment which will be awarded to the creditors of said late Republic, under said act of Congress, and the face value of the claims of the following named individuals, and issue certificates of public debt &#39;therefor, including interest due on such difference from the date of the last payment of interest, to the first day of July, 1850, at the same rate per cent as the original certificates.</p>
<p>That is, the difference between the pro rata as aforesaid, and the face value of eighteen hundred dollars funded debt of June 7th, 1837, issued to Jesse Holderman; also the difference as aforesaid on the three thousand dollars of the same, issued to Henry Raguet; also the difference as aforesaid, on the four hundred dollars of the same, issued to J. H. Polly; also the difference as aforesaid, on the four hundred dollars of the same, issued to Kitty McCoy; also the differ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ence as aforesaid, on the four hundred dollars of the same, issued to Joshua H. Davis; also the difference as aforesaid, on the twelve thousand three hundred dollars of the same, issued to John W. King; also the difference as aforesaid, on the two hundred dollars is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to Joseph Barnard; also the difference as aforesaid, on the eleven hundred dollars of the same, issued to Aaron Calvin; also the difference as aforesaid, on the two hundred dollars of the same, issued to Lucian Navarro; also the difference as aforesaid, on the two thousand dollars of the same, issued to J. Antonio Nav<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="245" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>arro; also the difference as aforesaid, on the six hundred dollars, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to William E. Honth; also the difference as aforesaid, on the one thousand dollars of the same, issued to Howard Decrow; also the difference as aforesaid on the two hundred dollars of the same, issued to Eli Mercer; also the difference as aforesaid, on the thirty<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />one hundred dollars of the same, issued to David Decrow; also the difference as aforesaid, on the five thousand dollars of the same, is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to Elijah Decrow; also the difference as aforesaid, on the nine<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty-eight thousand nine hundred dollars of the same, issued to Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Kinney and Williams, less ten thousand dollars, redeemed on the settlement of the account of Gail Borden, jr., collector of Customs at Galveston, and on the six thousand one hundred and seventy<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />seven dollars and ninety cents, of the Treasury notes issued to Thomas Smith, with interest at ten per cent, from the thirteenth day of February, 1839.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the certificates when issued as aforesaid, shall be paid by the Treasurer out of any money in the Treasury, not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated; Provided, the same does not exceed sixty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the several amounts found to be due as aforesaid, shall be paid to the original claimants only as above specified, or their heirs, on their filing a receipt to the State in full satisfaction of the claims in question.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2nd February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to detect and prevent the payment of fraudulent certificates of Public Debt, and to provide for [the] collection of certain money due by the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas: It is known that a large amount of certificates of the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral classes of debt of the late Republic of Texas are in circula<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion and</p>
<p>Whereas: By an Act of the present Legislature assenting to the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />osition from the Congress of the United States, in relation to the debt of the said late Republic, said debt is be paid at the Treasury of the United States, and whereas, said counterfeits are likely to be paid at the Federal Treasury unless proper means are taken to detect and discover the same.</p>
<p>Therefore in justice to the bonafide holders of said debt; and to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vent fraud being committed.</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of public <pb n="246" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>accounts, under the direction of the Governor, to proceed to the city of Washington and examine all evidence of debt of the late Repub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of Texas, presented for payment at the Treasury Department un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the Act of Congress, approved on the 28th of February 1855, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore referred to, and if found genuine and correct, to approve the same; and to reject all such as are found fraudulent or counterfeit.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That said Comptroller shall obtain from the records of his or any other of the Treasury offices of this State, such evidence or records, either original or copies, as will enable him to carry into effect the object of this Act, and protect the interest of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the Comptroller to keep a reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ister of all certificates of debt by him approved, and also, of all cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates by him rejected or disallowed as fraudulent, which register shall be deposited in the Comptroller&#8217;s Office as a public archive.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the said Comptroller shall collect from the Treasury of the United States all money due this State for payments made on account of that class of debt for which the revenues of the late Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public were pledged as are comprehended in the act of Congress known as the boundary Act approved September 9th 1850; accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the report of the Secretary of the Treasury to the President of the United States, and approved by him on the 13th of Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber 1851; and the opinion of the Attorney General of the United States addressed to the Secretary of the Treasury, under date of Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember 26th 1853, for which purpose the Treasurer or other officers of this State, shall deliver to the said Comptroller such evidence of payment as will enable him to obtain the money aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That it shall be the duty of the Comptroller of public accounts to transmit all funds that he may collect for the State un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the provisions of this Act to the Treasury of this State in some<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />secure manner, after deducting therefrom the actual expense in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curred in carrying this Act into effect, an account of which shall be audited by the Secretary of State and Treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this Act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="247" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Courts of this State to grant a Li<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cense for the retail of spirituous, vinous and [other] intoxicating liquors in quantities less than a quart, and imposing a license tax for such privilege.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That any person or firm hereafter wishing to engage in the business occupation of selling spirituous, vinous or other intoxicat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing liquors in quantities, less than a quart, shall have the privilege of doing so, upon his, her or their application in writing to the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty court of the county where he, she or they shall reside, stating the house or place where he, she or they propose to carry on such busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness and occupation and for what length of time.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That upon the presentation of the written application of the party or parties to the county court, it shall then be the duty of said court to order the Clerk thereof to issue to the applicant a li<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cense, authorizing him, her or them to retail spirituous, vinous or other intoxicating liquors in quantities less than one quart at the house or place specified in said written application, and for the length of time applied for upon conditions hereinafter prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. that before the Clerk of the county court shall issue to the applicant a license to retail spirituous, vinous and other liquors in quantities less than a quart, he, she or they shall make and deliver to the county Treasurer, a bond payable to the Chief Justice of said county, with two or more good and sufficient sureties to be approved by said Treasurer, in the sum of one thousand dollars, conditioned that the applicant and those acting or attending to said business for him, shall keep an orderly house or place for the retail of spirituous liquors, and that he will not permit a sale of spirituous liquors to be made at bis house or place to minors under the age of sixteen years, or students of any institution of learning, or to negro slaves without the written permission of the master, mistress or overseer of said slave, and that he will not permit any games to be played at the house or place whether licensed or not, which bond upon being ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the said county Treasurer, shall be filed in his office, as an obligation belonging to his county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That when the party or firm shall have executed the bond with security as prescrbied in the preceding section of this Act and shall have paid into the county Treasury of the county a license tax, at the rate of two hundred and fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars for one year, for the time he, she or they have applied for <pb n="248" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the license, and shall produce to the Clerk of the county court, the county Treasurer&#8217;s receipt for the amount of money paid by him, then the said Clerk shall issue to him a license to sell at retail any spirituous, vinous or other liquors, in quantities less than a quart, at the house or place, and for the time specified in the application.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That if any person or firm shall sell or be in anywise con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cerned in selling spirituous, vinous or other intoxicating liquors in quantities less than one quart, without first having obtained a li<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cense therefor in the manner prescribed by this Act; he, she or they shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof, before any District court Justice of the Peace or Mayor of any City or incorporated town shall be fined in any sum not less than fifty nor more than two hundred dollars, and be imprisoned in the county Jail until such fine and the costs be paid, and no person so convicted shall be discharged from such imprisonment before the expiration of thirty days, unless the fine and costs be sooner paid, any law to the contrary notwithstanding.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That if any person or firm shall sell or be concerned in selling, or shall permit any other person to sell any spirituous vin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous or other intoxicating liquors in quantities of a quart or more and shall permit or suffer the same to be drunk at or about the place or establishment where sold, or at or about any other house provided for that purpose, he, she or they upon conviction thereof, before any court mentioned in the next preceding section shall be fined as therein pescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That all fines, forfeitures and penalties and revenues aris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing under the provisions of this Act shall be exclusively appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated by the county Treasurer to the payment of general and petit Jurors of the county in accordance with the existing laws regulat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the jury-fund of counties: That in all prosecutions for any vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lation of any of the provisions of this Act, it shall be sufficient to allege and prove that the person charged with any such violation did sell or was concerned inselling spirituous, vinous or intoxicating liquors, and it shall not be necessary to allege or prove the kind of liquor sold, the name of the person or persons to whom the same was sold, or that the same was sold without license. This Act shall in all cases be liberally and remediably construed.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That no license shall be issued by the Clerk of the county court, nor shall the county court grant a license to any party or firm for a less term than four months.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That if any person or firm shall violate any of the conditions of the bond required of him, her or them by the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="249" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>visions of this Act, it shall be the duty of the county Treasurer to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitute suit thereupon in the name of the Chief Justice of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty for the use and benefit of the Jury-fund of the county, and the full amount of the penalty shall be recovered from the principals and sureties upon proof of a breach of any of the conditions thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That it shall be the duty of the county Clerk, Treasurer and county Commissioners to prosecute for all violations of the fifth and sixth sections of this Act, before the Justices of the Peace of the precinct where they are committed.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That if any person or firm shall sell any spirituous, vin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous or other intoxicating liquors in quantities less than a quart what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, to any person without first having obtained a license therefor according to the provisions of this Act, such sale shall be deemed contrary to public policy, and any person or persons who shall be sued upon such contract shall be allowed to plead the same in bar and to prove the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That no provision in this Act shall apply to Beer manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />factured in the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That an Act regulating and restricting the sale of spir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ituous liquors, passed 11th of February A. D. 1854, be and the same is hereby repealed; and this Act take effect and be in force from and after the first Monday of April next.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to fix the salaries of the Judges of the Supreme and District Courts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Judges of the Supreme Court of this State shall receive each a salary of three thousand dollars per annum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. The Judges of the District Courts of this State shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive each a salary of twenty-two hundred and fifty dollars per an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />num.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect only as to Judges hereafter elected.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="250" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act defining the Counties composing the third Judicial District, and the time of holding the Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, the following counties shall compose the Third Judicial District, to wit: Washing<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton, Burleson, Milam, McLennan, Bosque, Coryell, and Bell.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That there shall be two terms of the District Court held in each year, in each of the counties of the Third Judicial District, as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>In the county of Washington on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Burleson on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Milam on the sixth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of McLennan, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>In the county of Bosque on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Coryell on the tenth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>In the county of Bell on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process of every kind, that have been or may hereafter be issued from any of the District Courts of the Third Judicial district, shall be considered as returnable, and shall be returned to the terms established by this act, and all such writs and process shall have the same force and effect, as if they had originally been issued so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all acts, and parts of acts, conflicting herewith, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="251" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create Maverick County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory included within the following limits, to wit: beginning at the confluence of Elm creek and the Rio Grande, thence down the Rio Grande to the North-West corner of Webb county, thence along the North-West boundary of Webb county to the Nueces river, thence up the Nueces river with its meanders to the mouth of Indian creek, thence in a direct line to the place of beginning, be, and the same is hereby created into a new county, to be called Maverick county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Ludovic Colquhoun, of the town of Eagle Pass, be, and he is hereby authorized to organize the said county by ordering and causing an election to be held therein, for the necessary county officers. He shall for that purpose, at any time within six months after the passage of this act, order an election to be held at the elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion precincts already established in said territory, on a day to be designated by him; he shall appoint a presiding officer for each pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cinct, and shall cause notices of the time and place of holding said election to be posted ten days previous thereto, at three or more pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic places in said territory, the said election shall be conducted in all respects as other elections for county officers, the said Ludovic Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quhoun is also authorized to administer the necessary oath of office to the persons who may be elected at the said election.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That in the case the said Ludovic Colquhoun shall fail to organize the said county as provided in this act, the Chief Justice of Medina county shall be authorized to organize the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Eagle Pass be, and the same is hereby declared the county site of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That until the said county of Maverick shall be organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized, all the territory included within the limits mentioned in the first section of this act be, and the same is hereby attached to the county of Kinney, for all judicial and county purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all acts and parts of acts conflicting with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="252" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Uvalde.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that territory included within the following limits, in the county of Bexar: beginning at the junction of the Rio Frio and Leona rivers, thence up the Rio Frio to the South-Western cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of Medina county, thence North with the Western boundary line of Medina, county thirty-six miles to its North-Western corner, thence West to the Nueces river, thence down the river Nueces to the crossing of the upper Presidio del Rio Grande road, thence in a direct line to the place of beginning, be, and the same is hereby created a new county, and named the county of Uvalde.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the County Seat be established within eight miles of the centre of said county, to be called the town of Uvalde.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Medina county to cause an election to be held within three months from the passage of this act at the various precincts already established in said territory for the purpose of electing county officers for the said county of Uvalde, which election shall be conducted in accordance with the mode prescribed by law for the election of county officers, and the said Chief Justice shall award certificates of election to those persons who shall be duly elected as officers of said county of Uvalde, within the time and in the manner prescribed by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act creating the County of Young.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory comprised within the following limits, to wit: beginning at a point due West of the South West corner of the county of Jack, and six miles Easwardly from the South-East corner of the Indian reserve, as surveyed by English measure, thence North thirty miles, thence West thirty miles, thence South thirty miles, thence East to the place <pb n="253" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of beginning, be, and the same is hereby created into, and consti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tuted a new county, under the name and style of the county of Young.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That William H. Burkett, Peter Harmanson, Allen John<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son, Harry George, and James Duff, a majority of whom may act, be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners, with full powers to organize said county, whose duty it shall be, as soon as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable after giving the notice required by law, to open and hold an election for all necessary county officers, said Commissioners to have full authority to qualify them as the law directs.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of said Commissioners to cause an election to be held at the time of electing county officers, for the purpose of choosing a seat of Justice for said county. The Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners in selecting places to be voted for as the county site, shall have due regard for donations of land that may be offered, timber, water, and eligibility of site, &#38;c. One or more places to be put in nomination, and the place receiving a majority of all the votes cast, shall be declared the Seat of Justice for the county of Young, under the name and style of Belknap, provided the place so elected shall be within five miles of the centre of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Commissioners appointed by this act, before entering upon the discharge of their duties, shall take and subscribe an oath before some one competent to administer oaths, to faithfully and impartially discharge the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That for Judicial purposes the territory embraced within the limits of the county herein provided for, together with the ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory North of the Wichata, thence West to the source of the same, thence South to the Clear Fork of the Brazos, and down said stream to its mouth, shall be attached to the county of Wise, until other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise provided for by law.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create Kinney County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all the territory included within the following limits to wit: Beginning at the north west corner of Uvalde county on the Nueces river; thence west to Devils river;</p>
<pb n="254" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>thence down the same to its junction with the Rio Grande; thence down the Rio Grande to the mouth of Elm creek; thence in a direct line to a point on the west bank of the Nueces river, opposite the mouth of Indian creek; thence up the Nueces river with its meanders to the place of the beginning, shall be created into a new county to be called Kinney county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That Oscar B. Brackett of the county of Bexar be, and he is hereby authorized to organize the said county of Kinney by ordering and causing an election to be held therein for the necessary county officers. He shall, for that purpose, at any time within six months after the passage of this Act, order said election to be held at the election precincts already established in said territory, on a day to be desginated by him, he shall appoint a presiding officer tor each precinct, and shall cause notices of the time and place of holding said election to be posted ten days previous thereto, at three or more public places in said territory; the said election shall be conducted in all respects, as other elections for county officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the said Oscar B. Brackett also be authorized and empowered to administer the necessary oath of office to the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons who may be elected at said election. In case of the failure of the said Oscar B. Brackett, to organize the said county of Kinney as provided in this Act, it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Medina county to organize the said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all the territory between the Rio Grande and Nueces rivers, south of the county of Kinney as hereby created, and north of Webb county, shall for all judicial and county purposes, be at<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tached to the county of Kinney, until the same shall be organized into a separate county.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That survey No. 283 section No. 13, at or near the head of the Las Moras creek, be and the same is hereby declared the county site of said county, and shall be called Brackett.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this Act take effect from and after its passage, and that all Acts and parts of Acts conflicting herewith be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="255" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the official acts of J. P. Dumas, District surveyor of Grayson county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all surveys made by J. P. Dumas as District surveyor of Grayson county, and his Deputies, between the eighteenth day of June 1849, and the eighteenth day of August A. D. 1852, be, and the same are hereby made as legal and valid as if the official bond of said Dumas had been a legal one.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>4th February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of an act concerning Crimes and Punishments, approved 20th March, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That if any person or persons shall falsely make, counter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />feit, forge, or fraudulently alter or change any instrument of writing, or printing, or document of any kind, with the intent, and for the purpose of being used or made for use, in or at any of the public de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />partments or offices of this State, at the Seat of Government, or at any of the public offices of any county of this State, with intention of obtaining from any such public office of said State or county, any certificate, county or donation warrant or land scrip, or patent for any of the public lands of the State, or with the intent of obtaining any money or property belonging to the State or county, then he, she, or they, shall be deemed guilty of fraud and forgery, and upon conviction thereof shall, be imprisoned in the Penitentiary not less than five nor more than twenty years.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any authentic copy of a proclamation which the Governor shall issue, offering a reward for the arrest of any per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son charged with having committed any such fraud or forgery, as described in the first section of this act, or for the arrest of any person who may be charged with wilful and malicious burning of any building, containing the books, papers, records, archives and documents of any such public office, shall be suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient authority to any officer or citizen holding any such au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thentic copy, to arrest, and hold, and carry such person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="256" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sons, from the place of arrest, through any county or counties, to the place of prosecution and trial, without the necessity of having any other warrant, or other criminal process.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the sum of ten thousand dollars be, and the Same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury of the State, for the purpose of paying the expenses of arresting any such offenders, and carrying them to the county or counties where the prosecution is commenced, and for the compensation of such wit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nesses who shall be summoned in behalf of the State upon such trials, and for the safe keeping of such offenders in custody, until the final trials thereof, and for the payment of such other expenses, concerning the prosecution of such offenders as the Governor and Attorney General, or the Governor and District Attorney of any Judicial District shall deem necessary, and shall certify to be just and reasonable, without regard to former laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall be given in charge by the District Judges of the several Districts to the Grand Juries of the several Counties of this State, and that this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>2d February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the Trustees of the several School Districts of Comal County to levy and collect a special tax for school pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />poses.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Court of the county of Comal, are hereby authorized and required to levy in the several School Districts of said county, a special tax for school purposes: Provided, That the inhabitants of each district to be taxed, shall consent to such taxa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion by a vote as prescribed in the second section of this act: and provided further, that said tax shall not be of greater amount in any district than the State tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of said Comal County to order an election at any time within three months after the passage of this act, at which election a vote of the inhabitants of each School District in the county shall be taken; those in favor of the tax to vote &#8220;for the special school tax,&#8221; and those opposed thereto, to vote &#8220;against the special school tax;&#8221; returns of such election shall be made to the <pb n="257" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Chief Justice within ten days thereafter; and in those districts in which a majority of the votes cast shall be for the special school tax, a tax shall be levied and collected agreeably to the first section of this act, and in those Districts in which a majority of the votes cast shall be against the special school tax, no such tax shall be levied.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the taxes herein before provided for shall be col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lected by the Assessor and Collector of said Comal County, in the manner in which other taxes are collected, and that when Collected, he shall pay the same to the County Treasurer, whose duty it shall be to pay the sum collected in each district to the trustees or other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons having supervision of the public schools of said District: Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, This law shall not apply to the property of non-residents of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from, and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>4th February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to pay Assessors and Collectors of Taxes, fox taking the number of the scholastic population of their respective Counties, for the years 1854 and 1855.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Assessors and Collectors of the different Counties of the State of Texas, shall be entitled to ten cents a head for each and every person they may have returned to the County Clerk and Treasurer of the State, over six and under sixteen years of age, in discharging the duties assigned them by an act, entitled an act to establish a system of Schools, approved January 31st, 1854, and they shall be paid the said sum of ten cents per head for taking the scholastic population for each of the years 1854 and 1855, by the Treasurer, out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated, and this act shall take effect immediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>4th February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="258" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to An Act, entitled An Act relating to the Indians of Texas, approved Feb. 6, 1854.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That jurisdiction over five leagues of land of the vacant domain of the State of Texas, or so much thereof as the government of the United States may select, be and the same are hereby set apart and appropriated for the use and benefit of the several tribes of Indians residing west of the Pecos river, and within the limits of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the government of the United States is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to cause to be selected and surveyed of the vacant domain of the State, or to purchase of private individuals, and cause to be distinctly marked, one district, containing five leagues as aforesaid or less, which said district shall be located and selected west of the Pecos river, and the said quantity of land may be determined ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cording to English measurement.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever the proper agent of the government of the United States, shall notify the District Surveyor of the land district within the limits of which the land so selected or purchased may be situated, it shall be the duty of said District Surveyor to cause such land, so selected or purchased, to be plainly delineated upon the County Map of the County in Which the same is situated, and any location or entry upon any vacant land, after the same shall have been so designated for Indian purposes, shall be held null and void.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the jurisdiction over said five leagues of land, or any portion thereof, which may be selected for Indian purposes, within the meaning of this act, and the act to which this is a supplement, be, and the same is hereby ceded to the government of the United States, so far as to enable it to extend any act of Congress now exist<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or hereafter to be passed, regulating trade and intercourse with the Indian tribes; Provided this cession of jurisdiction shall not be construed so as to deprive the State of Texas of the right of jurisdic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion over any person, other than an Indian, for any offence committed upon the person or property of any one within the limits of the State; and further provided, that all process issuing from any of the Courts of this State, may be served in like manner, and have the same force and effect as though executed in any other portion of this State, and the survey heretofore made by the authority of the <pb n="259" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>United States for Indian Reserves, be recognized in the General Land Office of this State according to English measure.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the settlement, conditions and restrictions, named in the fifth section of the act to which this is a supplement, approved February 6th, 1854, be, and the same are hereby declared to attach to the grant of jurisdiction herein named.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>4th February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to restore land sold for Taxes and purchased by the State, to the former owners on certain conditions.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the former owner of lands that have been sold for taxes, and purchased by the State, shall have two years from and after the passage of this act, to redeem the same upon paying to the Assessor and Collector of Taxes, of the County wherein the land lies all ar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rearages of taxes unpaid, with fifty per cent per annum on all taxes that are or should be due on such lands, had the former owner con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued to own and give in the same for taxation, and a fee of two dollars to the Assessor and Collector for his services.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of the Assessors and Collectors to compute the value of lands that have been sold for taxes, and have remained unassessed for any number of years in accordance with the value of lands lying in the vicinity of such land so sold and purchased by the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Assessor and Collector shall make a separate quar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terly return to the Comptroller, specifying the lands redeemed as herein provided, and the amount of taxes collected thereon, which tax he shall pay into the Treasury, as required for the payment of other taxes. The certificate of the Assessor and Collector shall be sufficient evidence that the lands have been redeemed, and the for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer owner restored to all the rights he possessed in such lands prior to the sale of the same for taxes. Nothing in this act shall be so construed as to prevent parties from paying the taxes so due to the Comptroller. And this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>5th. February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="260" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act providing a remedy for persons wishing to change their Christian and sir names, or either, and to adopt another, instead thereof.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That hereafter when any person, acting in his or her own right, or a minor, under the age of twenty-one years, shall desire to change either his or her Christian, or sir-name, or both, and to adopt another name instead thereof, shall file his or her application in the District court, of the county, of his or her residence, setting forth the causes which induce him, or her, to desire a change of name, and to adopt another, whereupon the Judge, of the said court, if in his opinion it should be for the interest or benefit of the applicant to change his or her name, and to adopt another, shall by a Judgment of said court, order that the adopted name, of the party, shall be substituted for the original name.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Whenever it shall be the interest of any minor, under the age of twenty-one years, to change his or her name, and to adopt another name instead of the original name, the guardian, or next friend of said minor, shall file his or her application in the District court of the county of the said minor&#8217;s residence, setting forth the causes, which induce the minor, to desire to change the original name, accompanied with the full name, which the minor, wishes to adopt. Whereupon the Judge of said court, if the facts contained in the application, shall satisfy him, that it will be for the benefit and interest of the minor to change his or her name and to adopt another, shall grant authority to change his or her original name, and to adopt another instead thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Whenever any person shall change his or her original name, and adopt another instead thereof, it shall not operate, so as to release the person from any responsibility which he or she may have incurred by the original name, nor shall it operate, by said change of name, to defeat or destroy any rights of property or action which the person had or held in his original name.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. This Act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>5th February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="261" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to regulate Mustang chases West of the San Antonio River.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That any citizen of this State wishing to chase mustangs or wild cattle, shall apply to and receive from the Chief Justice of any of the counties lying west of the San Antonio river a written per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mit, with the seal of his office thereunto attached, which shall in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clude the name of the party applying and those of his associates, and the time for which said permit is given, which time shall not be longer than six months.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall not be lawful to run mustangs or wild cat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tle within the spring or summer months, to wit: March, April, May, June, July and August; nor shall it be lawful to run mustangs or wild cattle within ten miles of the Rio Grande.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the person so applying shall give bond and security in the sum of two hundred dollars, payable to the Chief Justice of the county extending the said permit, conditioned that all the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this Act shall be complied with.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the person so applying shall be responsible for the orderly conduct of their associates, and that all animals taken in the chase shall be presented and such taxes paid thereon as shall be prescribed by law; that they shall pay to the Chief Justice and county Clerk of the corresponding county, the sum of fifty cents for each application.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That there shall be paid to the county Treasurer, by the parties holding permits, the sum of twenty-five cents on each and every unmarked or unbranded horse, mare, colt, cow or bull, and a tax of two dollars on each and every mule so presented.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the county Treasurer shall be entitled to retain ten per cent of all monies so collected by him under the provisions of this Act, and the residue shall be placed to the credit and for the benefit of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That it shall be the duty of the parties holding per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mits, to report to the Chief Justice, or county Clerk, all branded or marked beast taken in the chase, and shall advertise them, fully describing the color, mark or brand and time of sale, by posting in writing a notice in each of the several precincts in the corresponding county, one of which shall be at the court house door, at least twenty days before the day of sale, and all such sales shall take place at the court house door, provided no claim<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="262" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ant appears, of the county in which the beast were taken; the sale shall be conducted by or under the supervision of the Chief Justice or county Clerk of the corresponding county. Ten per cent of such sale shall be retained by said Chief Justice or county Clerk; fifty per cent shall go to the parties returning the same, and the residue shall be paid to the county Treasurer, and be placed to the credit of the said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That all violations of this Act shall subject the parties to a confiscation of all animals taken in the chase or otherwise; sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enty-five per cent shall be paid to the informant or complainant, and the residue paid to the Treasurer of the county in which said confiscation shall be made, and they shall also be liable to such fine and imprisonment as the court may prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this Act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>6th February 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act more particularly declaring the duties of Deputy Clerks.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That all deputies regularly appointed by the Clerks of the several District Courts of this State, shall have power to take depo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sitions, and to do and perform all other acts that may be lawfully done by said principal Clerks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further enacted; That the deputies regularly ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointed by the several Clerks of the County Courts of this State, have power to take the separate acknowledgements of married wo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, acknowledging the execution of deeds and other instruments of conveyance, executed by them, in the same manner as the same may be taken by said principal Clerks, and that such Deputy Clerks have power to take proof of the execution of all deeds, mortgages and other instruments of writing that are by law required or allowed to be recorded. And to take the acknowledgements of the persons executing such deeds, mortgages and other instruments of writing, and to do and perform all other acts required to be done by said principal Clerks. And that all such acts heretofore done by such Deputy Clerks are hereby declared to be as valid as if done by said principal Clerks. And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>9th February, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>