<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="1137" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="265" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">JOINT RESOLUTIONS.</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 1.</head>
<opener>
<salute>A Joint Resolution instructing our Senators and requesting our Representatives in the Congress of the United States to use their endeavors in procuring a Regiment of Texas Mounted Volunteers, to be raised for the protection of the Western frontier of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Depredations and murders are constantly occurring on our borders; that a considerable mounted force has been necessarily withdrawn from our frontier; And Whereas, Major General Twiggs, commanding the troops in the Department of Texas, has recommended to the Government of the United States the great necessity of a mounted volunteer corps from Texas. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators be instructed, and our Representatives be requested to urge upon the Congress of the United States the passage of a law for raising and equipping, at as early a day as possible, a Regiment of Texas mounted volunteers, to serve not less than twelve months.</p>
<p>Resolved, 2d, That a copy of these resolutions be furnished each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>November 17th, 1857</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1138" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="266" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 2.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing the Governor to raise and muster into the service of the State mounted men for the protection of the frontier.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Many of our fellow citizens are suffering in life and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty from the depredations of hostile bands of Indians, on the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />treme frontiers of the State; And Whereas, the limited number of mounted Federal troops, at present stationed on our borders, are inadequate to afford protection. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to order out mounted vol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />unteers, not to exceed one hundred in number, to be divided into two or more companies, as he may think proper, to be armed and equipped as he may direct, and placed upon such portions of the frontier as he may consider best for the interests of the country; said company or companies to be mustered into the service for the term of three months, and as much longer as the Governor may think necessary.</p>
<p>Be it further Resolved, That the sum of twenty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to defray the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />penses of said company or companies; and that the pay and allow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances of the troops so called into service, shall not exceed that al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed to mounted volunteers during the Mexican war; and that these resolutions take effect from their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>November 17, 1857</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1139" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="267" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 3.</head>
<opener>
<salute>John Resolution requesting our Representatives and instructing our Senators in the United States Congress to call upon the United States Government to refund the money heretofore paid out by the State of Texas for the defence of her frontier, since the twenty-eighth day of February, 1855.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, Under the compact of annexation, the States of Texas is entitled to protection from the depredations of Indians, by the Government of the United States; And Whereas, that protection has in many instances, not been afforded to the exposed portions of the frontier, since the 28th of February, A. D. 1855, in conse<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quence whereof the Governor of this State has, from time to time, been compelled to order Rangers or volunteers into the field to protect the lives and property of our citizens, against the preda<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory bands of Indians which have infested our frontier; And Whereas, the Legislature has appropriated nearly one hundred thousand dollars, out of the Treasury of the State, to pay the troops so called out, which sums of money have not been re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />funded to the State by the United States. Therefore,</p>
<p>Resolved, That our Senators in the United States Congress be instructed, and our Representatives be requested, to urge upon the Government of the United States the necessity of refunding the amount of money paid out by Texas for the defence of the frontier, at the earliest day possible; and that the Governor be requested to furnish each of our Senators and Representatives in the United States Congress, and the Secretary of War, with a copy of this pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />amble and resolution, accompanied by a full statement of all sums of money paid by the State for the defence of the frontier as afore<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />said.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>November 25th, 1857</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1140" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="268" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 4.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of Claims be authorized to employ two additional Clerks, whose services shall be dispensed with from and after the first of January, 1858.</p>
<p>Be it further Resolved, That the compensation allowed said Clerks shall not exceed that of other Clerks employed in said office; and this resolution be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>24th November, 1857</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 5.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution recognizing the rank of Captain John G. Tod, late Texas Navy, requesting our Senators and Representatives to use their influence to procure the passage of a law incorporating him in the United States Navy, with the rank he held at the time of annexation.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Congress of the United States did at its last session pass an act, which was approved, March 3d, 1857, the twelfth sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of which reads as follows: &#8220;And be it further enacted, that the surviving officers of the Navy of the Republic of Texas, who were duly commissioned as such at the time of annexation, shall be entitled to the pay of officers of the like grade, when waiting orders in the Navy of the United States, for five years from the time of said annexation, and a sum sufficient to make the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment is hereby appropriated; Provided, that the acceptance of the provisions of this act, by any of the said officers, shall be a full relinquishment and remuneration of all claims on his part to any further compensation on this behalf from the United States Government, and to any position in the Navy of the United States.&#8221; The benefits of which act have been denied to Captain Tod, by decision of the Secretary <pb n="1141" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="269" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>of the Navy of the United States, declaring the commission of Captain Tod void. And</p>
<p>Whereas, It is believed that the decision of the Secretary of the Navy is erroneous, and that if even technically correct, Captain Tod ought not in justice to be excluded from the benefits of said act of Congress, by any mere irregularity connected with his com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission; and</p>
<p>Whereas, The Legislature recognize as true the brief synopsis of the history of Captain Tod&#39;s connection with the Navy of the late Republic of Texas, embraced in the report of the committee on Federal Relations, accompanying this preamble; which history proves his connection with said navy, in various capacities, from 1837 until it was surrendered to the United States, together with the flag of the Republic, and that he discharged his duties so well and so ably, that he won from the Republic which he served in her hour of darkness and danger, the plaudits most dear to the patriot: &#8220;Well done, thou good and faithful servant.&#8221; There<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved, by the Legislature the State of Texas, That we recognize John G. Tod as entitled to the rank of Captain in the Navy of the late Republic of Texas, according to the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mission issued him by President Anson Jones, on the 8th of July, A. D. 1845, and now on file in the Navy Department of the United States, and that he is properly entitled to a continuation of his pay, from the Congress of the United States, and should be so recog<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nized by said Government, and that we recommend his case to the special consideration of the Federal Government.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further Resolved, That, as by accepting the five years waiting orders pay, under the aforesaid act, the officers of the Texas Navy of 1843 and 1846 have made a full relinquishment and renunciation for further compensation, and position in the Navy of the United States; that our Senators and Representatives in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress are requested to use their influence to procure the passage of a law by the Congress of the United States, incorporating Captain John G. Tod in the Navy of the United States, in the rank which he held at the time of annexation as a &#8220;souvenir&#8221; to Texas of her Naval interest in that great event.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Be it further Resolved, That the Governor be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to cause copies of this preamble and resolutions, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1142" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="270" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>gather with a copy of the report of the committee accompanying them, to be immediately forwarded, to our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>1st December, 1857</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 6.</head>
<opener>
<salute>A JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United States be requested to use all proper exertions, consistent with their official duties, to procure the establishment of a mail route, by stage, from the town of Marshall, in Harrison county, to the town of Dallas, in Dallas county, via Gilmer, in Upshur county, via, Quitman, in Wood county, via Greenville, in Hunt county.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 15th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 7.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution granting leave of absence from the State to the Hon. Charles A. Frazer, and A. W. Terrel.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Hon. Charles A. Frazer, Judge of the 6th Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict, and A. W. Terrell, Judge of the 2nd Judicial District, be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed leave of absence from the State during any any one vacation of their Courts within the next two years from the passage hereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Joint Resolution take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 15, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1143" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="271" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 8.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution instructing our Senators and requesting our Rep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />resentatives in Congress on the subject of Indian spoliations.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, certain Indians located by the United States upon terri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tory adjacent to that of the State of Texas have at various times made descents upon citizens of this State, committing robberies and othe crimes; and, whereas, it is the duty of the General Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernment to furnish protection against the, assaults of the Indians and that that Government is consequently liable to indemnify the sufferers in such cases. Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators in Congress are instructed and our Representatives re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to call the attention of the General Government to the fre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quently recurring depredations committed by Indians, and to urge the adoption of a more adequate system of protection against them.</p>
<p>Be it further Resolved, That our Senators be further instructed and our Representatives requested to assist those of our citizens whose property may have been stolen or destroyed by the Indians aforesaid to enforce their claims for indemnity against the General Government, in such manner as to them may seem meet and most effective.</p>
<p>Be it further Resolved, That the Governor is hereby requested to transmit copies of these resolutions to our Senators and Repre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sentatives, and to the President and Secretary of War of the United States.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 16th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 9.</head>
<opener>
<salute>A JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That whereas, divers, charges have been made against John C. Watrous, District Judge of the United States for the <pb n="1144" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="272" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>Eastern District of Texas, before the House of Representatives of the United States, with a view to his impeachment, and a commit<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tee of said House has reported the following Resolution:</p>
<p>Resolved, That John C. Watrous, United States District Judge for the District, of Texas, be impeached of high crimes and mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanors.</p>
<p>And it is required for the honor of the State of Texas, and is due to the accused, that all of said charges be promptly and fully inves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tigated and finally acted upon: That without intending to express any opinion as to the guilt or innocence of Judge J. C. Watrous, the Representatives in Congress from this State, are hereby requested to take such steps as may be necessary to cause a full investigation to be made by the House of Representatives of the United States during the present session, of all the charges that have been made against said John C. Watrous, and to use their best exertions to cause definite action to be taken thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further Resolved, That the Governor is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to forward to each of the Senators and Representatives in Congress from this State, and also to said John C. Watrous, a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified copy of this Joint Resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 19, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 10.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution requesting our Senators and Representatives in Congress to use their exertions to obtain appropriations for United States Court Houses in Texas, and the establishment of another Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the public interest and convenience would be greatly promoted by the ereation of suitable buildings for Post-Offices and United States Court-rooms, at the Cities of Aus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tin and Tyler in the Western District of Texas, and at the City of Brownsville, in the Eastern District, and such other places as the United States District Court may be held, where such appropriations have not been made, and also by <pb n="1145" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="273" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>the creation of another Judicial District, in Texas: Therefore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in Congress be, and they are hereby requested to obtain the necessary appropriations, for the erection of such buildings.</p>
<p>Be it further Resolved, That our Senators and Representatives, be further requested to use their influence to procure the creation of the third Federal Judicial District in Texas, to be taken from the Western Judicial District, lying west of the Guadalupe river, and embracing the county of El Paso, and the counties on the Rio Grande, north of the Eastern District.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 27th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 11.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer is authorized to exchange the United States bonds and coupons in the Treasury, for coin at par, provided, the sum so exchanged shall not exceed one hundred thousand dollars: And provided further, that the Treasurer may pay out such United States bonds coupons, to satisfy claims on the Treasury, at par: Provided, the whole amount paid out shall not exceed one hundred thousand dollars. And that this Resolution take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 28, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1146" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="274" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 12.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That Hon. William S. Todd, Judge of the eighth Judicial District, be, and he is hereby allowed a leave of absence from the State, for two months during the present year, (1858); Provided, his absence does not take place during the regular session of his Court.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 13.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution relative to the establishment of a weekly overland mail route.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the existing mail route from San Antonio, Texas, to San Diego, in the State of California, established under An Act of the Congress of the United States, has resulted in a practical demonstration of the superiority of the southern route as a means of overland mail transportation, and whereas, notwithstanding many circumstances calculated seriously to embarrass and retard the progress of said mails, the same has been transported to and fro, within the postal schedule time, and Whereas, there exists an urgent and imperative necessity for an overland mail from the Atlantic States to the Pacific coast, to be carrled weekly. There<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in the Congress of the United States, be and they are hereby requested to use their efforts to procure the passage of a law establishing a weekly overland mail from some point in Texas, to San Diego in the State of California, with an ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation sufficient to enable the contractor or contractors, therefor, to erect suitable stations at convenient points along said route.</p>
<pb n="1147" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="275" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<p>Resolved further, That the Secretary of State be requested to fur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nish each of the delegation from this State in the Congress of the United States, with a copy of these resolutions.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 26th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 14.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, it is a fact ascertained to the satisfaction of the Governor, that the depredations committed upon the frontier citizens of this State, are done chiefly by United States Indians, who enter our territory about the junction of the larger Wichita and Red River, near which there is no military station or post; and whereas, it is believed by many well informed citizens living on the frontier, that the Comanche and other Indians who are fed by the United States on the Texas Indian Reserve, are also directly or indirectly engaged with them in these hostile forays, which is rendering the civilizing and feeding policy of the Government unpopular, if not useless, which would not be so if it were efficiently carried out. Therefore.</p>
<p>Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby requested to urge upon the authori<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of the Federal Government, at Washington, the great neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sity of the immediate establishment of a permanent military post as near the junction of the larger Wichita and Red River as prac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ticable, and the Indian Agents in charge of the Indians on the Texas Indian Reserve, be instructed to require every male Indian over the age of twelve years, to be upon the Reserve under his con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trol every day, unless such Indian or Indians have his special writ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ten permission to be absent; and that such Agents be instructed not to permit any Indian or Indians, to be absent from said Reservations by special permission more than three days at any one time, unless they are accompanied by some white man, or men, to be sent with them by him, to prevent them from committing depredations on the citizens of the country, or communicating with other Indians not known to be at peace with Texas, or sent with white men <pb n="1148" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="276" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>as guides, hunters, &#38;c., or sent by said Agents as spies, of express bearers; and that the Agents be required to enforce these instruc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and that the Government furnish and keep constantly, at each Reserve, a sufficient military force to enable Agents to carry out such instructions. And that our Senators and Representatives in Congress be requested to co-operate with the Governor in accom<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plishing the objects of this Resolution, and that the Governor be requested to furnish each of them and the President and Secretary of War, and Secretary of the Interior of the United States, with a copy of the same.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 15.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution instructing our Senators and requesting our Representatives in Congress to procure such action on the part of the United States, as will cause the Indians in Texas, west of the Pecos River to be collected upon the Reserve provided for them.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, the Indians within the limits of Texas west of the Pecos River, are of a roving character without permanent habitations, and subsist mainly by depredations upon the stock and other property of the citizens of Texas residing in that portion of the State, and whereas the State of Texas has made a liberal provision for said Indians by an appropriation of land to be selected by an agent for them to be appointed by the United States Government, for the purpose of collecting and permanently settling thereon and there to be taught the arts of agriculture and civilization un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the superintendence, control and management of said agent, whereby the citizens of the State will be relieved from the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinued losses sustained by the predatory incursions of said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians. Therefore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress be requested to use all proper means to force the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1149" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="277" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>pointment by the Government of the United States, of a compe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tent Agent to select a proper location west of the Pecos River with<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in the limits of Texas upon which to settle the Indians, inhabitating that section of the State, in accordance with the provisions of An Act supplementary to An Act entitled An Act relating to the In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dians of Texas, approved February 6th, 1854, approved February, 1856, and that said Agent be instructed to collect and settle said Indians upon such location so made, as aforesaid.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Be it further Resolved, That His Excellency the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor be requested to forward a copy of these Resolutions to each of our Senators and Representatives in Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>January 29, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 16.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Bt it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives be requested to use their influence in Congress to procure the establishment of a four horse line of mail coaches to run between Tyler in Smith county, and Waco in McLennan county, via Athens, Corsicana and Dresden, to make regular connection&#39;s with the line now established between Austin and Waco, and make the same number of trips made by that line.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 2d, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1150" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="278" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 17.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution for the relief of the heirs of D. Rowlett, deceased.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas: That upon the requisition of the Judge of the sixteenth Judicial District, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby required to permit the original certificate for one-third of a league of land, issued to Andrew Pinoro by the Board of Land Commissioners of Fannin county, on the 26th of April, 1838, to be withdrawn from the General Land Office, for the purpose of being used as evidence in the trial now pending in the District Court of Collin county in the case of the heirs of D. Rowlett vs. Curtis Moore. Provided, that a copy of said certificate shall he retained in the General Land Office, and the original returned to that Office after the determination of said suit.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Resolution take effect from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 3, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 18.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution authorizing and requiring the Governor and Comp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />troller to contract for re-modeling and re-covering the Capitol and old Land Office, and re-modeling the galleries of the Capitol.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor and Comptroller be, and they are hereby authorized and required to contract for the re-modeling of the roofs, and the re-covering of the Capitol building and the old Land Office in a good and substantial manner, and of fire-proof materials, to be guaranteed to stand good for ten years. They shall also cause the galleries of each Hall in the Capitol to be re-modeled and seats prepared in them in such a man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1151" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="279" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>ner as to accommodate spectators. Provided, the same shall not cost more than eight thousand dollars for both buildings; which sum of eight thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sary for that purpose, is hereby appropriated. And that this Joint Resolution take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 4, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 19.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions relative to the portrait of the late Abner S. Lipscomb.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the portrait of the late Abner S. Lipscomb, executed by the artist Alexander Ford, and by him tendered as a gift to the State, be accepted; and the thanks of the Legislature are hereby tendered to the donor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor of the State is hereby requested to receive in charge said portrait, and cause the same to be inclosed in a suitable frame, and placed in the room of the Supreme Court at Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Secretary of State transmit to Mr. Ford a copy of these Resolutions.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That one hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated to carry out the object of these Resolutions.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That these Resolutions take effect from and after their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 6, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 20.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be and he is hereby autho<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="1152" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="280" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>rized and required to pay over to S. A. Maverick, Treasurer of the San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Railroad Company, any funds collected or received by him for the use of said railroad, by virtue of the 12th section of an Act to incorporate the San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Railroad Company, approved September 5, 1850.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Resolution shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 6, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 21.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions recognizing the rank of Commander P. W. Hum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />phries, late Texas Navy, at the date of the annexation of Texas to the United States.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That we recognize P. W. Humphries as entitled to the rank of Commander in the Navy of the late Republic of Texas, from the third day of July, 1839, up to the date of annexation; and that, as such officer, he is entitled to pay according to rank, under and by virtue of the provisions of an Act of the Congress of the United States, approved March 3d, 1857.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That a certified copy of these Resolutions be furnished to Commander Humphries, upon application for the same, by His Ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cellency, the Governor.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>February 12, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 22.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of the Senate and Chief Clerk <pb n="1153" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="281" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>of the House of Representatives, be authorized and required to make an alphabetical index to all the Special and Private relief laws, and Acts of incorporation, which have been heretofore passed by the Consultation, Congress of the late Republic, and Legislature of the State of Texas; and that the sum of six hundred dollars or so much thereof as may be deemed necessary by the Secretary of State, to pay for such work, be and the same is hereby appropriated to carry into effect the provisions of this Joint Resolution.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this Joint Resolution take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 15, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 23.</head>
<opener>
<salute>JOINT RESOLUTION.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas: There is a considerable balance remaining in the Treasury of the United States, of the appropriation made by the Act of Con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gress, providing for the payment of a certain portion of the public debt of Texas, passed on the 28th February, 1855, owing, mainly, to the loss of securities by holders of the same. And whereas, under these circumstances, those parties may never be able to make the necessary exhibition of Texas liabilities at that Depart<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment to enable them to obtain the money due them, and will be compelled to apply to the State Legislature for relief; and whereas, Texas is entitled to any and all balances in the Treasury of the United States which has not been paid to the creditors un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the Act of Congress above referred to; therefore,</p>
<p>Be it resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That our Senators and Representatives in Congress be, and they are hereby requested to use every exertion in their power to obtain the passage of a law by Congress, authorizing the payment of any balance remaining in the Treasury aforesaid, over to the accredited agent of the State of Texas.</p>
<pb n="1154" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="282" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<p>Resolved, That the Governor of Texas be, and he is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quested to furnish each of our delegation in Congress with a copy of this Resolution.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 16, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 24.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution is relation to the Indians residing in the counties of Polk and Tyler.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of the State be, and he is hereby author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to remove the Indians located and now residing in the counties of Polk and Tyler, under and by virtue of an Act entitled an Act for the relief of the Coshattee Indians, approved August 30th, 1856, from said Polk and Tyler counties, and provide a permanent home for and settle them, in such manner and at such place as to him may seem expedient and for the welfare and benefit of said Indians. Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, such removal shall not take place unless the consent of said Indians thereto shall first be given through their Chiefs, to be as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />certained and reported to the Governor by an agent, to be appointed by him for the purpose of negotiating for such consent; and pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided further, that the lands, upon which said Indians are now set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled, shall, when abandoned by them, under the provisions of this Act, be and remain reserved from location, except upon such terms, and conditions as the Legislature may hereafter prescribe.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of five thousand dollars is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated to carry out the provisions of the first section of these Reso<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lutions; and the State Treasurer is hereby required to pay said sum out of any moneys not otherwise appropriated, upan a warrant or warrants drawn by the Governor by virtue hereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That these Resolutions shall take effect from and after their passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>February 16, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1155" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="283" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 25.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolution proposing an amendment to the State Constitution.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 3rd Section of the 10th Article of the Constitu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the State shall be so amended as to read as follows, viz:</p>
<p>Section 3. All public lands, which have heretofore, or, which may hereafter be granted for public schools to the various counties in this State, may be sold by the County Courts of each county to which the lands belong, or by such tribunals as may succeed to their jurisdiction, by consent of a majority of the legal voters in said counties, and under such general rules as the Legislature may, from time to time, prescribe. Provided, that the principal of the proceeds of the sale of such lands shall be retained, and invested as a permanent school fund for the counties owning the same, and the interest only shall be used for educational purposes.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 16, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER 26.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Joint Resolutions in response to Governor&#8217;s Message on Kansas Affairs.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, There exists, and has existed, a violent determination on the part of a portion of the inhabitants of the Territory of Kan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sas, to exclude, by force, the citizens of the slaveholding States from a just, equal and peaceful participation in the use and en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joyment of the common property and Territory of the members of the confederacy;</p>
<p>And, Whereas, This determination, owing to the state of political feeling in the Northern States of the confederacy, operating upon the Federal Government, may become effectual, and the ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusion perpetual&#8212;Therefore,</p>
<pb n="1156" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="284" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<p>1st. Be it Resolved by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor of this State is hereby authorized to order an election for seven Delegates, to meet Delegates appointed by the other Southern States, in Convention, whenever the Executives of a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of the slaveholding States shall express the opinion that such Convention is necessary to preserve the equal rights of such States in the Union, and advise the Governor of this State that measures have been taken for the appointment of Delegates to meet those of Texas. And that the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to pay the mileage and per diem of such Delegates, which shall be paid at the rate paid to members of the United States Congress, accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the law in force in the year 1854.</p>
<p>2d. That should an exigency arise, in the opinion of the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, in which it is necessary for the State of Texas to act alone, or by a Convention representing the sovereignty of the State, he is hereby requested to call a Special Session of the Legislature to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for such State Convention.</p>
<p>3d. That the Governor is requested to transmit copies of these resolutions to the Executives of each of the slaveholding States, and to our members of Congress.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>February 16th, 1858</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1157" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="285" /><fw type="header" place="top">Joint Resolutions.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">STATE OF TEXAS.</head>
<p>I, T. S. Anderson, Secretary of State of the State of Texas, certify that the session of the Seventh Legislature of said State commenced, at the city of Austin, on Monday, the second day of November, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-seven, and adjourned on Tuesday, the sixteenth day of February, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-eight.</p>
<p>And I further certify, That the Acts and Joint Resolutions con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tained in this volume are true copies, taken from the original rolls deposited in the Department of State, with which they have been carefully compared.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and official seal, the 30th day <floatingText rend="left"><body><p>[L. S.]</p></body></floatingText>of March, in the year one thousand eight hundred and fifty-eight.</p>
<closer>
<signed>T. S. ANDERSON.</signed>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="1158" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="286" />
<pb n="1159" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="i" />
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">INDEX TO THE GENERAL LAWS.</head>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">A</head>
<p>Page</p>
<p>Alamo Monument.&#8212;An act to provide for the purchase of.... <ref>130</ref></p>
<p>Appropriation.&#8212;To defray contingent expenses of the Sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enth Legislature................. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>To pay for State copies of 16th and 17th vols. Texas Reports ................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>To pay for printing Governor&#39;s Proclamation. <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>To pay mileage and per diem of members of Seventh Legislature................. <ref>20</ref></p>
<p>To pay contingent expenses for the support of the Penitentiary.................. <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>To pay certain claims therein named...... <ref>79</ref></p>
<p>&#34; To support the Penitentiary .............. <ref>207</ref></p>
<p>&#34; To supply deficiencies in former appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, &#38;c........................ <ref>224</ref></p>
<p>&#34; For the use and support of the State Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment for the years 1858 and 1859........ <ref>248</ref></p>
<p>Angelina County.&#8212;(See Counties,)</p>
<p>Archer County.&#8212;(See new Counties,)</p>
<p>Arms and Accoutrements&#8212;To authorize the Governor to draw from the Unites States for the State of Texas............. <ref>52</ref></p>
<pb n="1160" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Artesian Wells.&#8212;To provide for the boring of, between the Nueces and Rio Grande Rivers......... <ref>85</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; To amend the act concerning............ <ref>130</ref></p>
<p>Austin City.&#8212;An act to quiet titles to real estate in.......... <ref>22</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; &#34; &#34; for the relief of purchasers of city and out-lots in ............................ <ref>79</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">B</head>
<p>Bee County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Bell County.&#8212;(See Gonzales county,)</p>
<p>Brown County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Buchanan County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Blanco County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Baylor County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Brazoria County.&#8212;An act to amend an act concerning public and private roads in, approved January 28th, 1856, and the act supplementary thereto, approved August 11th, 1856... <ref>129</ref></p>
<p>Bonds.&#8212;An act to provide for the sale of a certain amount of United States ............................... <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint Resolution authorizing the State Treasurer to exchange United States and coupons for coin at par, &#38;c....................... <ref>273</ref></p>
<p>Blind.&#8212;An act to purchase a permanent location for the insti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tution for the education of, in Texas............. <ref>153</ref></p>
<p>Boundary.&#8212;An act supplementary to and amendatory of an act providing for running between Texas and the United States..................... <ref>64</ref></p>
<p>Buffalo Bayou.&#8212;An act to provide for the manner in which the fund set apart for the improvement of, shall be expended.................. <ref>133</ref></p>
<p>Buckhart.&#8212;To permit Wm. H. to practice law................. <ref>14</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">C</head>
<p>Callahan County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Capitol.&#8212;Joint Resolution authorizing the Governor and Comptroller to contract for remodeling and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />covering the Capitol and old Land Office............. <ref>278</ref></p>
<pb n="1161" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Clay County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Certiorari.&#8212;An act concerning writs of, from Justice&#8217;s Courts. <ref>84</ref></p>
<p>Calhoun County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Census.&#8212;An act to provide for taking, in the State for the year 1858....................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Comptroller.&#8212;An act to establish salary of Chief Clerk of.... <ref>247</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to render the receipts of, valid in cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain cases ................ <ref>144</ref></p>
<p>Chambers County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Claims.&#8212;An act supplemental to an act supplemental and amendatory of an act to ascertain the legal claims for money and lands against the State, approved August 1st, 1856, approved January 16th, 1858.. <ref>208</ref></p>
<p>Concho County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<p>Coleman County.&#8212;(See new counties,)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">COUNTIES.</head>
<p>Angelina.&#8212;An act to permanently locate the county seat of... <ref>102</ref></p>
<p>Calboun.&#8212;An act to authorize certain sales in, to be made at the door of the &#8220;Casimer House&#8221; in Indianola.... <ref>35</ref></p>
<p>Comanche.&#8212;Act to amend an act creating and the act amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing said act, approved August 25th, 1856..... <ref>102</ref></p>
<p>Clay.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Concho. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Coleman. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Callahan. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Dallas.&#8212;An act to authorize the clerk of the County Court of, to transcribe certain records therein named.... <ref>5</ref></p>
<p>Dawson.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Dimmit. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Duval. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Eastland. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Edwards. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Encinal. &#34; &#34;</p>
<pb n="1162" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="iv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>El Paso.&#8212;An act to amend an act relinquishing the title to cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain lands therein described to the inhabitants of Ysleta in&#8212;Approved January 21st, 1854....... <ref>222</ref></p>
<p>Fayette.&#8212;An act to legalize transcripts of records of certain field notes therein named................ <ref>1</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to authorize the clerk of the District Court to transcribe certain records therein named..... <ref>15</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to authorize the clerk of the County Court to transcribe certain records therein named....... <ref>16</ref></p>
<p>Frio.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Goliad.&#8212;An act to adjust the boundaries of........... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Gonzales.&#8212;An act to authorize the County Court of, and Bell, to levy an additional tax to build a courthouse .. <ref>197</ref></p>
<p>Grayson.&#8212;An act to authorize the clerk of the County Court of, to transcribe records therein described.... <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Hamilton.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Hardin. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Hill.&#8212;(See Limestone.)</p>
<p>Haskell.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Hardeman. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Hopkins.&#8212;An act to legalize as a Land District, and to legalize surreys made therein.............. <ref>6</ref></p>
<p>Jack.&#8212;An act to amend an act creating............. <ref>97</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to legalize the organization of .............. <ref>128</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; An act to locate permanently the county seat of..... <ref>129</ref></p>
<p>Johnson.&#8212;An act to authorize the clerk of the County Court of, to transcribe certain records therein named.. <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Jones.&#8212;(See new Counties.)</p>
<p>Kimble&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Knox&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>La Salle &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Limestone.&#8212;An act to define the dividing line between the counties of Limestone, Navarro and Hill......... <ref>218</ref></p>
<pb n="1163" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="v" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Llano&#8212;An act to amend an act creating................ <ref>147</ref></p>
<p>Live Oak&#8212;An act to legalize the location of County Site of... <ref>96</ref></p>
<p>Mason&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>McMullen&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Menard&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Montague&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Nacogdoches&#8212;An act to authorize the Clerk of the District of, to transcribe certain records therein named.... <ref>64</ref></p>
<p>Navarro&#8212;(See Limestone.)</p>
<p>Nueces&#8212;An act to adjust the boundaries of................... <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>Palo Pinto&#8212;An act to amend the act creating................. <ref>123</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act donating 320 acres of land to...........103</p>
<p>Presidio&#8212;An act to organize................ <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Runnels&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>San Patricio&#8212;An act to adjust the boundaries of............. <ref>10</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to adjust the boundary between and Nueces ...................... <ref>65</ref></p>
<p>San Saba&#8212;An act to amend the act creating................ <ref>148</ref></p>
<p>Shackleford&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Smith&#8212;An act to authorize the Clerk of the County Court of, to transcribe certain records therein named.... <ref>53</ref></p>
<p>Taylor&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Travis&#8212;An act requiring certain forced sales to be made at the corner of black 70, on Congress Avenue in the city of Austin................. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>Throckmorton&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Trinity&#8212;An act to attach a portion of to Walker.............. <ref>54</ref></p>
<p>Upshur&#8212;An act to Change the time of holding the County Court of, sitting as a Commissioners Court...... <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to amend an act to organize&#8212;Approved April, 27 1846 .................... <ref>105</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to amend an act to change the time of hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing County Courts, approved November 13, 1857. <ref>75</ref></p>
<p>Walker&#8212;(See Trinity.)</p>
<pb n="1164" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Webb&#8212;An act to authorize County Court to levy a special tax. <ref>151</ref></p>
<p>Wharton&#8212;An act to authorize the County Court of, to levy a special tax, &#38;c.................... <ref>47</ref></p>
<p>Wilbarger&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Wichita&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Wood&#8212;An act to legalize the acts of Wm. T. Harris, Sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of ................. <ref>77</ref></p>
<p>Zavala&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Zapata&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Constitution&#8212;Index proposing to amend the State <ref>283</ref></p>
<p>County Courts&#8212;An act to prolong the time of holding the regular quarterly sessions of, &#38;c., (See Roads,).. <ref>38</ref></p>
<p>Court of Claims&#8212;An act to authorize the Commissioner of, to issue certain Headlight Certificates there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in named..................... <ref>211</ref></p>
<p>Court of Claims&#8212;An act to authorize the Commissioner of, to issue certain Headlight Certificates there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in named...................... <ref>213</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act to authorize and require the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of, to approve certain Donation and Bounty Land Certificates therein named, (See Donation and Bounty Land Certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates.) .................... <ref>94</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act to authorize the Commissioner of, to issue certain Headright, Bounty, Donation Land Certificates therein named.......... <ref>226</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act to establish the salary of Chief Clerk of......................... <ref>247</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; Joint Resolution authorizing Commissioner of, to employ two more clerks till January 1st, 1858 .............. <ref>268</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act to amend the act establishing, &#38;c... <ref>40</ref></p>
<pb n="1165" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="vii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Code of Criminal Procedure&#8212;An act supplemental to and amendatory of an act to establish a, for the State, approved August 26, 1856............... <ref>228</ref></p>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">D</head>
<p>Dallas County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Deaf and Dumb&#8212;An act for the permanent location of the In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution for.................. <ref>120</ref></p>
<p>Digest&#8212;An act to provide for a Digest of the laws of Texas... <ref>253</ref></p>
<p>Donation and Bounty Land Certificates&#8212;An act to authorize and require Commissioner of Court of Claims to approve certain, therein named, (See Court of Claims,) ............... <ref>94</ref></p>
<p>District Courts&#8212;An act granting further time for the holding of, in the counties of Henderson, Kaufman and Van Zandt................ <ref>246</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act further regulating proceedings in.... <ref>110</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">E</head>
<p>El Paso County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Eastland County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Edwards County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Encinal County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">F</head>
<p>Fayette County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Federal Court&#8212;Joint Resolution in relation to another Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict of, in Texas............... <ref>272</ref></p>
<p>Ferries&#8212;An act to exempt Ferry Boats from forced sales..... <ref>210</ref></p>
<p>Fiscal Year&#8212;An act to change, the and provide a uniform time for termination of..................... <ref>17</ref></p>
<pb n="1166" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="viii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Frazer&#8212;Joint Resolution granting leave of absence to the Hon. Charles. A.......................... <ref>270</ref></p>
<p>Free Negroes&#8212;An act to permit to select their own masters and become slaves....................... <ref>75</ref></p>
<p>Frio County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Frontier&#8212;An act for the better protection of............... <ref>77</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint Resolution instructing our Senators, &#38;c., in relation to the raising by the U. S. Government of a regiment of Texas Mounted Volunteers for the protection of................................ <ref>265</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint Resolution authorizing the Governor to mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter into the service of the State mounted men for the protection of.................... <ref>266</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Index requesting our Representatives, &#38;c., in relation to the refunding by the United States, of money paid and by Texas since Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 28th, 1855, for the protection of............. <ref>267</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint Resolution relative to the establishment of a Military Post for the protection of, near the junc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the larger Wichita and Red River, &#38;c.... <ref>275</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">G</head>
<p>Galveston Dry Dock Company&#8212;An act relinquishing to the, right of the State to twenty-five acres of land therein described.................. <ref>142</ref></p>
<p>Galveston and Brazos Navigation Company&#8212;An act to permit the, to relocate their Land Certificates....... <ref>223</ref></p>
<p>Galveston, Houston and Henderson Railroad Company&#8212;(See Railroad Companies.)</p>
<p>Geological Survey&#8212;An act to provide for, in the State......... <ref>144</ref></p>
<p>Gonzales County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Goliad County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Governor and Lt. Governor&#8212;An act to provide for the manner of recording votes for.................. <ref>19</ref></p>
<p>Grayson County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1167" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="ix" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">H</head>
<p>Hamilton County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Hardeman County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Hardin County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Haskell Comity&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Hopkins County&#8212;(See counties).</p>
<p>Hill County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Commander late of the Texas Navy, &#38;c......... <ref>280</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">I</head>
<p>Index.&#8212;oint resolutions requiring Secretary of State and Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives to make an alphabetical, to all special and private laws of the consultation, Congress of the Repub-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> lic, and Legislature of the State, &#38;ec <ref>280</ref></p>
<p>Indians.&#8212;Joint resolution requesting our Senators, &#38;c., to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure the removal of, west of the Pecos river to the Reserve provided for them............ <ref>276</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint resolution in relation to, residing in Polk and Tyler counties....................... <ref>282</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; An act to prohibit the sale of vinous liquors to i asaw T</p>
<p>Indian S <ref>105</ref></p>
<p>County.&#8212;(See counties.) Jones County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
</div3>
</div2>
<pb n="1168" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="x" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">JUDICIAL DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>First.&#8212;An act to amend an act to define the District and to fix the time of holding courts therein, approved July 19th, 1856................. <ref>40</ref></p>
<p>Second.&#8212;An act to define the time of holding courts therein. (See Seventeenth.) ..................... <ref>39</ref></p>
<p>Third.&#8212;An act to re-organize and define the time of holding courts therein ............. <ref>51</ref></p>
<p>Fourth.&#8212;An act to define the time of holding courts in. (See page 98) ................. <ref>81</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to define the time of holding courts in.. <ref>98</ref></p>
<p>Fifth&#8212;An act to define the time of holding courts in......... <ref>82</ref></p>
<p>Seventh&#8212;An act to define and fix the time of holding courts in .............................. <ref>99</ref></p>
<p>Eighth.&#8212;An act to reorganize and fix the time of holding courts in.............................. <ref>261</ref></p>
<p>Tenth.&#8212;An act supplemental to an act to change the time of holding courts in................... <ref>191</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to fix the time of holding courts in...... <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Eleventh.&#8212;An act supplementary to an act to change the time of holding courts in................. <ref>57</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to change the time of holding terms of courts in ........................ <ref>8</ref></p>
<p>Twelfth.&#8212;An act to define the time of holding courts in..... <ref>83</ref></p>
<p>Thirteenth.&#8212;An act to reorganize and fix the time of holding courts in ..................... <ref>121</ref></p>
<p>Fourteenth.&#8212;An act supplementary to an act to change the time of holding courts in........... <ref>191</ref></p>
<p>Fifteenth.&#8212;An act to regulate the time of holding courts in.. <ref>252</ref></p>
<p>Sixteenth.&#8212;An act to reorganize and fix the time of holding courts in ................ <ref>131</ref></p>
<p>Seventeenth.&#8212;An act to amend an act to organize and reor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize the second, and fix the time of holding courts in, approved September 1st, 1856. (See Second.) .. ...................... <ref>100</ref></p>
<pb n="1169" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Eighteenth.&#8212;An act to fix the time of holding courts in...... <ref>101</ref></p>
<p>Nineteenth.&#8212;An act to create and to regulate the holding of courts in, and to provide for the election of a Judge and District Attorney in............ <ref>23</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act supplementary to the act to create, &#38;c., approved December 19th, 1857............... <ref>82</ref></p>
<p>Juries&#8212;An act to amend an act regulating, approved 4th of May, 1846........................ <ref>204</ref></p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">K</head>
<p>Kansas&#8212;Joint resolution in relation to the Governor&#8217;s mes<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sage on...................... <ref>283</ref></p>
<p>Knox County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Kimble County &#34; &#34;</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">L.</head>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">LAND DISTRICTS.</head>
<p>Bexar&#8212;An act to require the Commissioner of the Land Office to make out transcripts of field notes of surreys heretofore made in, which hare been returned to his office, and which are now included in Young Land District, &#38;c. (See also Milam Land Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict) ................. <ref>191</ref></p>
<p>Bastrop.&#8212;(See Milam.)</p>
<p>Burleson.&#8212;(See Milam.)</p>
<p>Cooke.&#8212;(See Young.)</p>
<p>Denton.&#8212;(See Young.)</p>
<p>Karnes.&#8212;An act to legalize surveys made in.............. <ref>4</ref></p>
<p>Milam.&#8212;An act to legalize surveys made in the disputed ter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ritory between, on Bexar, and also between, and Bastrop and Burleson. (See also Bexar.)</p>
<p>Young&#8212;An act to provide for making legal and valid the transcripts of records of surveys of maps taken from Cooke and Denton Land Districts, and now included in, (See Bexar.)............. <ref>190</ref></p>
<pb n="1170" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Land Office.&#8212;An act to establish the salary of the Chief Clerk of................. <ref>247</ref></p>
<p>Lands.&#8212;An act to relinquish the right of the State to certain, therein named................ <ref>155</ref></p>
<p>La Salle County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Limestone County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Lipscomb&#8212;Joint resolution relative to portrait of the late Abner S. ................... <ref>279</ref></p>
<p>Live Oak County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Loan Bill.&#8212;An act to amend. (See Railroad Companies.).... <ref>57</ref></p>
<p>Lunatic Asylum.&#8212;An act to organize, and fox the care and maintenance of the insane............. <ref>114</ref></p>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">M</head>
<p>Mail Routes.&#8212;Joint resolution requesting our Representatives, &#38;c., to procure a certain, therein described. <ref>270</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint resolution relative to overland, to San Diego, California ....... <ref>274</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint resolution instructing our Senators &#38;c., to procure the establishment of a four horse line of coaches from Tyler, via Waco, &#38;c., &#38;c., to Austin.................... <ref>277</ref></p>
<p>Mason County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>McMullen County. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Menard County. &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Mercer&#8217;s Colony.&#8212;An act to repeal an act supplementary to an act for the relief of, passed February 2d, 1850, approved August 30th, 1856...... <ref>21</ref></p>
<p>Military Companies.&#8212;An act to incorporate all organized or to be organized, in the State................ <ref>220</ref></p>
<p>Minority.&#8212;An act to remote the disabilities of, from certain persons therein named................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to remove the disabilities of, from Certain persons therein named............... <ref>252</ref></p>
<pb n="1171" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xiii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Minute Men.&#8212;An act to provide for the payment of, com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />manded by Capts. Sansom, Davenport and Black <ref>209</ref></p>
<p>Mississippi and Pacific R. R. Reserve.&#8212;An act to authorize the location, sale and settlement of.............. <ref>7</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to define the northern boundary of......... <ref>30</ref></p>
<p>Montague County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Mustang Chases.&#8212;An act to repeal an act regulating, west of the San Antonio river, approved February 6th, 1856 ............................ <ref>144</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">N</head>
<p>Nacogdoches County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Navarro County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Nueces County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<div4 type="section">
<head type="main">NEW COUNTIES.</head>
<p>Archer.&#8212;Act creating .................................... <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Act supplementary to the act creating............ <ref>63</ref></p>
<p>Baylor.&#8212;An act to create...................................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Bee.&#8212;An act to create and attach to the fourteenth Judicial District ............................... <ref>11</ref></p>
<p>Blanco.&#8212;An act to create ................................. <ref>198</ref></p>
<p>Brown. &#34; &#34; .................................... <ref>122</ref></p>
<p>Buchanan. &#34; &#34; ..................................... <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>Callahan. &#34; &#34; ................................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Chambers.&#8212;An act to create .......................... <ref>192</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to define the boundaries of ..................... <ref>193</ref></p>
<p>Clay.&#8212;An act to create ................................ <ref>33</ref></p>
<p>Coleman.&#8212;An act to create .......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Concho. &#34; &#34; ............................. <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Dawson. &#34; &#34; ............................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Dimmit. &#34; &#34;........................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Duval. &#34; &#34; ............................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<pb n="1172" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xiv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Eastland.&#8212;An act to create ....................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Edwards. &#34; &#34;.......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Encinal. &#34; &#34; ........................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Frio. &#34; &#34; .............................. <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Hamilton. &#34; &#34; ............................ <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>Hardeman. &#34; &#34; ....................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Hardin. &#34; &#34; ...................... <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>Haskell. &#34; &#34; ........................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Jones. &#34; &#34; ............................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Kimble. &#34; &#34; ......................... <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>Knox. &#34; &#34; .......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>La Salle. &#34; &#34; ......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Mason. &#34; &#34; ........................ <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>McMullen. &#34; &#34; .................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Menard. &#34; &#34; ...................... <ref>58</ref></p>
<p>Montague. &#34; &#34; ......................... <ref>31</ref></p>
<p>Runnels. &#34; &#34; ...................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Shackelford. &#34; &#34; ........................ <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Taylor. &#34; &#34; ......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Throckmorton. &#8220; &#34; ......................... <ref>36</ref></p>
<p>Wilbarger. &#34; &#34; .......................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Wichita. &#34; &#34; ..................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Zayalla. &#34; &#34; ........................... <ref>87</ref></p>
<p>Zapata. &#34; &#34; ............................ <ref>58</ref></p>
</div4>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">O</head>
<p>Ochiltree.&#8212;An act to authorize to Thomas P., to practice law in the State.......................... <ref>200</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">P</head>
<p>Palo Pinto County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Penal Code.&#8212;An act supplemental to and amendatory of an act to adopt and establish, for the State of Texas, approved August 28th, 1856........... <ref>156</ref></p>
<pb n="1173" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xv" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Penitentiary.&#8212;An act making appropriation to support, (See appropriation.) ................... <ref>207</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act making contingent appropriation for support of, (See appropriation.)..................... <ref>34</ref></p>
<p>Peters&#8217; Colony.&#8212;An act to repeal a portion of the act of Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 10th, 1852, entitled an act relating to land in............... <ref>36</ref>.</p>
<p>&#34; An act to ascertain what land certificates have been illegally issued by the County Courts of certain counties in, and to pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vide for issuing patents on such of said certificates as are legal............... <ref>106</ref></p>
<p>Pre-Emption Settlers.&#8212;An act for the relief of, under certain acts therein named, and of actual set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tlers in the Mississippi and Pacific Railroad Reservation................ <ref>152</ref></p>
<p>Public Debt.&#8212;An act to pay certain, of late Republic, known as Second Class &#8220;C&#8221;................ <ref>262</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; An act to pay a portion of the second class, of the late Republic.................... <ref>263</ref></p>
<p>&#34; &#34; Joint resolution instructing our Senators, &#38;c., in relation to the balance due Texas in the U. S. Treasury, after payment of our public debt, under act of Congress of February 28th, 1855 ................... <ref>281</ref></p>
<p>Public Domain.&#8212;An act to authorize the sale of............. <ref>193</ref></p>
<p>Public Printer.&#8212;An act to provide the manner in which he shall return his work after the adjourn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the Legislature.............. <ref>264</ref></p>
</div3>
<pb n="1174" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xvi" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">R</head>
<p>Railroads and Railroad Companies.&#8212;An act supplemental to the act to encourage the building of railroads, &#38;c., approved January 30th, 1854............ <ref>263</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act supplemental to and amendatory of an act to regulate................... <ref>25</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to amend the fourth section of the Loan Bill, passed August 13th, 1856................ <ref>57</ref></p>
<p>&#34; Joint resolution authorizing Comptroller to pay to S. A. Maverick funds collected by him for San Antonio and Mexican Gulf Railroad Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, &#38;c.................. <ref>280</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to prohibit the issuance or delivery of land certificates, and the survey of patenting of land to the Galveston, Houston and Henderson Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road Company, until said company shall have complied with the requirements therein named <ref>217</ref></p>
<p>Rangers.&#8212;An act to amend the 1st section of Joint Resolution for the relief of company of, commanded by Capt. Becknell in 1836, approved February 11th. 1852................... <ref>55</ref></p>
<p>Records.&#8212;An act to provide for transcribing county............ <ref>80</ref></p>
<p>Revenue.&#8212;(See Taxes.)............... <ref>258</ref></p>
<p>Rivers.&#8212;An act extending the appropriation and the times for making the contracts for letting out the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments for certain, and other navigable streams in Texas, under the act of August 1st, 1856, and the act supplemental to and amendatory thereto of August 23d, 1856................... <ref>103</ref></p>
<p>&#8220; An act declaring the intent, &#38;c., of the act of August 1st, 1856, to encourage the improvement of, and other navigable streams in Texas by making appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priations for the same, and supplemental thereto.. <ref>257</ref></p>
<pb n="1175" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xvii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Rivers.&#8212;An act to authorize the cancellation of contract for work to be done on the Sabine, upon conditions therein named .................. <ref>95</ref></p>
<p>Roads.&#8212;An act to authorize County Courts to regulate and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />point overseers of................ <ref>133</ref></p>
<p>Rowlett.&#8212;Joint resolution for the relief of D............... <ref>278</ref></p>
<p>Runnels County.&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">S</head>
<p>Sabine River.&#8212;(See Rivers.)</p>
<p>San Saba County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>San Patricio County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Schools.&#8212;An act for the relief of the Trustees and patrons of certain School Districts therein named............ <ref>104</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act supplementary to and amendatory of an act to provide for the support of, approved August 29th, 1856. ................... <ref>124</ref></p>
<p>Scrolls and Seals.&#8212;An act to dispense with the use of.......... <ref>96</ref></p>
<p>Shackelford County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Slaves&#8212;An act to encourage the reclamation of, escaping be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />yond the limits of the United States. (See also Free Negroes) .................. <ref>202</ref></p>
<p>Smith County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Special Election&#8212;An act to provide for, in 21st Senatorial District....................... <ref>13</ref></p>
<p>State Department&#8212;An act to establish the salary of Chief Clerk in................... <ref>247</ref></p>
<p>Supreme Court&#8212;An act to define the time of holding sessions of ................... <ref>9</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to amend the second Section of an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled an act to amend the second Section of an act entitled an act to amend the second and sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />enth section of an act entitled an act to organ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ize, approved November 30th, 1850, approved February 13th, 1854. ............... <ref>15</ref></p>
<pb n="1176" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xviii" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<p>Surveyors&#8212;An act supplementary to and amendatory of an act to give each corporate county its own Surveyor, and Maps, and Records, &#38;c., and defining duties of Surveyors .............. <ref>66</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">T</head>
<p>Taxes&#8212;An an act to extend the provisions of, an act to restore lands sold for and purchased by the State, to for<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mer owners on certain conditions, approved Feb<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ruary 5th, 1856 .................... <ref>143</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to relinquish State, to certain counties for the purpose therein mentioned............ <ref>255</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act amendatory of the laws to raise revenue by taxation ................. <ref>258</ref></p>
<p>Taylor County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Texas Reports&#8212;An act to provide for the purchase of an addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional supply of................. <ref>213</ref></p>
<p>Terrell&#8212;Joint Resolution granting leave of absence to the Hon. A. W....................... <ref>278</ref></p>
<p>Throckmorton&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Todd&#8212;Joint Resolution recognizing the rank of Capt. John G., in the Navy of the Republic, &#38;c............ <ref>268</ref></p>
<p>Todd&#8212;Joint Resolution granting leave of absence to the Hon. Wm. S. ...................... <ref>274</ref></p>
<p>Towns and Cities&#8212;An act to provide for the incorporation of. <ref>69</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act supplementary to an act to provide for the incorporation of.................. <ref>127</ref></p>
<p>&#34; An act to change the names of certain towns therein named.................... <ref>128</ref></p>
<p>Translation&#8212;An act to provide for the, of certain general laws into the Spanish, German and Norwegian lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guages .................... <ref>219</ref></p>
<p>Travis County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Treasury.&#8212;An act to establish the salary of Chief Clerk..... <ref>247</ref></p>
<p>Trinity County.&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
</div3>
<pb n="1177" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xix" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">U</head>
<p>University&#8212;An act to establish a State............... <ref>148</ref></p>
<p>Upshur County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">V</head>
<p>Volunteers&#8212;An act to provide for the payment of mounted, called into the service to protect those transpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing goods, &#38;c., over the road from San Antonio the Gulf.............................. <ref>18</ref></p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">W</head>
<p>Watrous&#8212;Joint Resolution in relation to the Hon. John C... <ref>271</ref></p>
<p>Walker County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
<p>Webb County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Weights and Measuers&#8212;An act to establish uniform........ <ref>200</ref></p>
<p>Wilbarger County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Wichita County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<p>Wood County&#8212;(See counties.)</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">Z</head>
<p>Zavala County&#8212;(See new counties.)</p>
<p>Zapata County&#8212; &#34; &#34;</p>
<pb n="1178" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="xx" /><fw type="header" place="top">Index.</fw>
</div3>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>