<text xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 UNTtite%20(1.3).xsd" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="TEI">
<body>
<pb n="419" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="1" />
<div1 type="article">
<head type="main">GENERAL LAWS <lb/>OF <lb/>THE SIXTH LEGISLATURE <lb/>OF <lb/>THE STATE OF TEXAS <lb/>PASSED AT ITS <lb/>ADJOURNED SESSION CONVENED JULY 7, 1856</head>
<byline>BY AUTHORITY.</byline>
<byline>AUSTIN 1856</byline>
<pb n="420" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="2" />
<pb n="421" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="3" />
<head type="sub">GENERAL LAWS</head>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the better security of the Archives of the State Department.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Secretary of State be, and he is hereby authorized, upon the adjournment of the present Legislature, to take posses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sion of two or more rooms, as may be necessary, in the basement story of the Capitol, for the use of the State Department, and the better preservation and protection of the Archives of said office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect upon the adjournment of the present session of the Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 16th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the first Judicial District, and to fix the time of holding the District Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the passage of this act, the counties of Matagorda, Wharton, Colorado, Fayette, Austin, Fort Bend and Brazoria, shall compose the first Judicial District of the State of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. From and after the final passage of this act, the District Courts in the first Judicial District shall commence and be held as follows, to wit: In the county of Brazoria, on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; In the county of Matagorda, on the <pb n="422" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="4" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>second Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Wharton, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Colorado, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and Octo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session two weeks; In the county of Fay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ette, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and Oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tober, and may continue in session three weeks; In the county of Austin, on the ninth Mondays, after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; In the county of Fort Bend, on the eleventh Mondays, after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. All writs and process, that have been, or may hereafter be issued from any of the District Courts of the first Judicial Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict as defined by this act, shall be considered as returnable, and shall be returned to the terms as established and fixed by this act; and they shall have the same force and effect as if they had origi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nally been issued so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the provisions of all laws, so far as they conflict with this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and that this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 19th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create and organize the Eighteenth Judicial District, and to define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the counties of Atascosa, Medina, Bandera, Uvalde, Kinney and Maverick, be, and the same are hereby created into a New Judicial District, to be called the Eighteenth Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts shall be held in the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties composing said eighteenth Judicial District as follows, to wit: In the county of Atascosa, on the third Mondays after first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Medina, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, <pb n="423" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="5" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and may continue in session one week; In the county of Bandera on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Uvalde, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Kinney, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Maverick, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays of March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Governor of the State be, and he is hereby authorized and required to order an election for a District Judge, and a District Attorney for said eighteenth Judicial District, im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately after the passage of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws and parts of laws, conflicting with this act, are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 22d, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Supplementary to the act of January 28th, 1840, concern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing Wills, and authorizing persons to dispose of their Estate by Will.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all persons are hereby authorized and permitted to dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose of their own estate, real and personal, by will or otherwise, and that the thirteenth and fifteenth sections of the act of January 28th, 1840, entitled &#8220;An Act concerning Wills,&#8221; and the provisions of all other acts so far as they conflict with this, be, and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>July 24th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="424" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="6" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the fourth section of An Act entitled &#8220;An Act regulating attachments,&#8220; approved March 11th, 1848.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fourth section of the above recited act be hereby amended so that the same shall hereafter read as follows, to wit: The Judges and Clerks of the District Court and Justices of the Peace, may issue original attachments, returnable to their respective Courts, upon the party applying for the same, his Agent or Attorney mak<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing an affidavit in writing, stating that the defendant is justly in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />debted to the plaintiff and the amount of the demand; also, that the defendant is not a resident of this State, or that he is about to re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />move out of this State, or that he secretes himself so that the ordi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nary process of law cannot be served on him; or that he is about to remove his property beyond this State, or that he is about to remove his property beyond the county in which the suit is to be or has been commenced, or that he is about to transfer or secrete, or has trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fered or secreted his property for the purpose of defrauding his ceditors, and that thereby the plaintiff will probably lose his debt, and he shall also swear that the attachment is not sued out for the purpose of injuring the defendant.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>July 24th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the time of holding the District Courts in the tenth and fourteenth Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Courts shall be held in each of the counties composing the Tenth Judicial District, twice in each year, and at the following times, to wit: In the county of Calhoun, on the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Vic<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />toria, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Jackson, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in February and August, and may continue in session one <pb n="425" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="7" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>week; In the county of Lavaca, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; In the county of DeWitt, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Gonzales, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts shall be held twice a year in each of the counties composing the fourteenth Judicial District, as follows, to wit: in the county of San Patricio, on the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Live Oak, on the first Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Karnes, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Goliad, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Refugio, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Nueces, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days of April and October, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the provisions of all laws conflicting with this act, are hereby repealed, and that from and after the time this act takes effect, all process issuing from officers of District Clerks, of said counties, shall be made returnable in conformity with the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act shall take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>July 24th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define more particularly the Eastern Boundary line of Bastrop county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Eastern Boundary line of Bastrop county shall commence at the south-east corner of a league and labor survey made for John Vashney; thence to the south-east cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of a third of a league survey, the headright of Thomas <pb n="426" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="8" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Rinds; thence with the north-eastern boundary line of said Rind&#8217;s survey, to the south-east comer of Joseph Martin&#8217;s survey; thence with the north-eastern boundary line of said Martin&#8217;s survey and in the same direction with a survey made for E. Harris and Isaac Carsnier, to the north-east corner of said Carsnier&#8217;s surveys, on the line of Travis county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the county surveyor of Bastrop county be, and he is hereby authorized to run and mark the line herein above described, and that this act take effect and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>July 28th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER LXXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to extend the intercourse laws of the United States for the prevention of the introduction or sale of Wines and Spirituous Liquors, within ten miles of the Indian Reserves, in the State of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the intercourse laws of the United States for pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />venting the introduction, giving or sale of Wines or Spirituous liquors to Indians within the Indian country, be extended for a dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tance of ten miles from the boundary line of the Indian reserves, in this State, upon which Indians have been or may hereafter be set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled by the United States Indian Agents; and may continue in force so long as such reserves are kept for Indian purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>July 28th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XC.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act entitled An Act to change the time of holding Court in the 10th and 14th Judicial Districts.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That so much of the above entitled act as requires the District Court to be held in the county of Calhoun, on the first Monday of August, and in the county of Victoria, on the second Monday after the first Monday of August, shall not take effect until the first of January, 1857; and that the Fall Term of said Court, 1856, shall be held in Victoria county on <pb n="427" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="9" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the second Monday of November, and may continue in session two weeks. And the Fall Term, 1856, of said Court, for the county of Calhoun, shall be held on the first Monday of December, and may continue in session until the business is finished. And that all pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cess returned to these Courts, at any other time shall be returnable at the time fixed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in case of epidemic, or other cause deemed suffi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cient, the District Court for Calhoun county may be adjourned by the Judge thereof to a special term: provided, that said special term shall, in no case, interfere with the regular term of the District Court of any other county in the Tenth Judicial District.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>July 29th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Supplemental to An Act entitled &#8220;An Act to fix the salaries of the Judges of the Supreme Court and District Courts,&#8221; ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved 2nd February, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the act entitled &#8220;An Act to fix the salaries of the Judges of the Supreme and District Courts,&#8221; approved 2nd February, 1856, shall take effect and be in force immediately, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>July 29th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to encourage the improvement of the Navigation of the Rivers and other Navigable Waters in Texas, by making appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priations for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of three hundred thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated, and, set apart as a special fund for the improvement of the navigable rivers, bayous, lakes and bays, of Texas, and that the Governor is hereby authorized to draw from the Treasury said fund for the use and benefit of said rivers, bayous, lakes and bays, as herein<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="428" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="10" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>after provided in this act; and to report to the Legislature, at each and every session thereof, his acts and proceedings relative to said fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any navigable river, bayou, lake or bay, for the improvement of which any specified amount, not less than one thousand dollars, may be raised by private subscription, or other contribution or appropriation, except by the State, shall be entitled to receive, from said fund, four times the amount of said sum so raised and contributed, provided no one river, bayou, lake or bay shall be entitled, under the provisions of this act, to more than fifty thousand dollars of said fund, and provided further, that said sums so contributed by the State and private subscription, and ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriation, shall be expended for the improvement of the naviga<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of such rivers, bayous, lakes and bays, by the removal of all serious obstacles from the mouth up, or on such portion as shall be specially designated on said subscription.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever the citizens interested in the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of any navigable river, bayou, lake or bay, may desire to se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cure the benefits of this act to said river, bayou, lake or bay, they shall have the power, in public meeting, to appoint some good and responsible person as Collector and Treasurer, who shall be author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to take up a subscription for the benefit of said river, bayou, lake, or bay, which subscription must specify for what river, bayou, lake or bay, it is taken. And no subscription shall be received by said Collector and Treasurer, unless at least five per cent. of said subscription is paid in actual cash. That said Collector and Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, before entering upon the duties of his office, shall enter into a bond, with good and sufficient security, in the sum of twenty thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars, payable to the Governor, and his successors in office, for the faithful discharge of the duties of his office, which bond shall be approved by the Governor, and filed with the Secretary of State, and may be sued upon as other bonds. That said Collector and Treasurer shall be entitled to five per cent. on the amount received, and five per cent. on the amount disbursed by him, as hereafter required to be subscribed and raised independent of the amount, raised for said rivers, bayous, lakes or bays; and shall be author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to sue and recover, in his own name, for the benefit of said river, bayou, lake or bay, any amount subscribed for the improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of the same, as in other cases in law and equity; and shall have the power to call upon said subscribers, at any time, <pb n="429" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="11" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>for installments on said subscription, provided no more than twenty per cent. of said subscription shall be required every sixty days.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That said Collector and Treasurer shall be required to report quarterly, to the Governor, all accounts collected and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bursed by him, together with a copy of his subscription lists, and all his acts and accounts connected with said business, and shall also be required to keep an accurate record of the same, in a book to be kept for that purpose.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. There shall be elected, by the Legislature on joint bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lot, a State Engineer and Superintendent, Who shall receive an an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nual salary of three thousand dollars, payable quarterly. And said Engineer and Superintendent shall, before entering upon the duties of his office, enter into a bond, with good and sufficient security, in the sum of ten thousand dollars, payable to the Governor of the State, and his successors in office, for the faithful discharge of the duties which may be assigned him, and with such other conditions as may be prescribed by the Governor, which bond shall be approv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by the Governor, and filed with the Secretary of the State, and may be sued upon as other like bonds.</p>
<p>And said Engineer and Superintendent shall also take and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribe the following oath, before any officer legally authorized to administer the same:&#8212;&#8220;I do solemnly swear (or affirm, as the case may be) that I will well and truly discharge all the duties required of me as State Engineer and Superintendent.&#8221; And whenever, in the opinion of the Governor, the State Engineer and Superintend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent cannot perform the duties required of him, under this act, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sistently with his performance of other duties, the Governor may appoint some competent person to superintend the work upon any river, bayou, lake or bay, designated by the Governor, who shall give bond and take an oath of office in the same manner as is re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired of the State Engineer and Superintendent, and shall receive a compensation of five dollars per day, during the time he is employ<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed in actual service.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That when the Governor shall be notified that a Collector and Treasurer has been appointed and qualified as, provided by this Act, and that he has raised a subscription of bona-fide solvent subscribers for as much as the sum of one thousand dollars for one or more Rivers, Bayous, Lakes or Bays, and that five per cent. of said subscription has been paid in cash; then said Engineer and Superintendent, shall, sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="430" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="12" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>vey, explore, and lay off the work to be done on said River, Bayou, Lake or Bay, in sections of convenient length, and shall form estimates of the work, and let out the same to the lowest bidder at such time and place as shall be fixed upon by him, and shall enter into written contracts with said contractors, fully specifying the nature of the work to be done, and the time in which the same is to be completed. And said contractors shall enter into bond with se<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curities, to be approved by said Engineer and Superintendent in double the amount of his bid, for the faithful performance of his contract, which bond shall be made payable to the Governor, and may be sued upon and collected as other like bonds. Said Engineer and Superintendent, shall superintend the work, and see that it is done in conformity with the contract, and shall make full and ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />curate examinations of the same, and shall report quarterly to the Governor all his proceedings and transaction&#39;s relative to the same, and the condition and progress of all the works of which he is Superintendent. And said Engineer and Superintendent shall not be directly or indirectly interested in any bid or contract whatever, for the improvement of said Rivers, Bayous, Lakes or Bays.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Said Engineer and Superintendent shall, after, or at the time of, making his quarterly report to the Governor, draw drafts on the Collector and Treasurer for said River, Bayou, Lake or Bay, and also on the Treasurer of the State, in favor of the Contractor or Contractors for such work as they may find upon examination to be entitled to. Provided, That in no case shall he draw for more than three-fourths of the work actually done and performed, until the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tire contract shall be completed&#8212;and further provided, that he shall not draw said drafts, upon the Treasurer of the State until corresponding drafts of one-fifth of the amount have been paid by the Collector and Treasurer for said River, Bayou, Lake or Bay; and the Governor, when satisfied that said corresponding amount has been paid out of the private subscription, shall countersign the drafts so drawn upon the Treasurer, upon which payment shall he made out of said fund, and no payment shall be made upon said drafts upon the Treasurer, until the same are countersigned by the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That any sum of money, which may be appropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated by the State of Louisiana, for the improvement of the navigation of the Sabine River, shall authorize the Engineer to draw on the Treasurer of this State for the same amount <pb n="431" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="13" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of money, which sum so drawn, shall be appropriated to the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement of said river, under the provisions of this act; and a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tified copy of an act of the State of Louisiana, making such appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priation, shall be sufficient evidence that the appropriation has been made. Provided, the sum drawn from the Treasury of this State shall not exceed fifteen thousand dollars under this provision. And should the State of Arkansas appropriate any sum of money for the improvement of the navigation of Red River, or any amount be raised in the Choctaw Nation for the same purpose, a like amount may be drawn from the Treasury of the State, and used for the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement of the navigation of Red River above the Northeast cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner of the State, under the provisions of this act,&#8212;rovided, the same shall not exceed fifteen thousand dollars. And should the Re-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> public of Mexico, or any of its States bordering on the Rio Grande, appropriate any amount for the improvement of the navigation of the Rio Grande, then a like amount for the same purpose may hb drawn from the Treasury of this State,&#8212;&#8212;ovided, the same shall not exceed fifteen thousand dollars. But no part &#62;o said appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />$tions shall be drawn &#39;-om the Treasury, under the 8th section of this act, until corresponding appropriations of said adjoining States and Republic have been actually expended upon said streams, and good and satisfactory evidence shall be shown to the Governor of said expenditure.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That money may be raised in the same manner as provided for in this act for the construction of any canal between any two navigable points, and any canal for the construction of which any amount may be so raised by private subscription or approp tion, shall be entitled and subject to all the benefits and visions of this act,&#8212;rovided, that no money- hall &#39;e drawn ^ the Treasury for the benefit of any such canal, until satisfaector evidence has been shown to -he Governor, together with the report of a -ompetent engineer, that the amount raised by private subscrip-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> tion, together with the amount to which said private subscription &#9632;hall entitle it from the State Treasury, will be amply sufficient to construct -nd -omplete said canal so far as to connect -wo naviga-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> ble -oints, with a good navigable--hannel, and provided that no canal, or any river, bayou, lake or bay, receiving the benefits -f the provisions of this act, shall, at any &#39;ime, receive-or collect &#39;olls for -he navigation of the same. And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="432" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="14" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to ascertain the legal claims for money and lands against the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be elected, by a Joint vote of the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, a Commissioner of Claims, who shall hold his office until the first day of January, A. D. 1858, and until his successor shall be duly elected and qualified. He shall keep his office at the city of Austin, and shall receive an annual salary of two thousand two hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>Before he enters upon the discharge of the duties of his office, he shall enter into bond, with two or more good and sufficient sure<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, in the sum of twenty thousand dollars, made payable to the Governor of the State of Texas, and his successors in office, condi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned that he will well and truly discharge all the duties that may be required of him by law, which bond shall be approved by the Governor, and by him filed in the office of the Secretary of State; he shall be allowed one Clerk, to be appointed by him, who shall receive an annual salary of one thousand dollars; if, from any cause, a vacancy shall occur in said office of Commissioner of Claims dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the recess of the Legislature, the Governor shall fill it by ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment, which shall continue in force until the expiration of ten lays from the first meeting of the Legislature thereafter.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All land certificates of every description, except headright tificates of the first and second class, which have been returned as g uine and legal, by the Commissioners appointed under an act &#8220;to detect fraudulent land certificates, and to provide for the issuing pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ents to legal claimants,&#8221; approved 29th January, 1840; and certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates issued under some special act of Congress of the Republic of Texas, or of the Legislature of this State, and certificates to the col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />onists of Peters&#8217; Colony; Mercer&#8217;s Colony; Castro&#8217;s Colony; Fisher and Miller&#8217;s Colony, and the colonists of the German Emigration Company; and certificates issued for premium lands in said colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nies, and certificates issued to companies incorporated under the laws of this State, for the purposes of internal improvement, and to persons for building vessels, under the provisions of the act of February the third, 1854, entitled &#8220;An Act to encourage the building of steamboats, steamships and other vessels in the <pb n="433" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="15" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>State of Texas,&#8220; and certificates for unlocated balances heretofore issued, and pre-emption certificates, shall be presented to said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of Claims for registry, within two years from and after the first day of September, one thousand eight hundred and fiftysix, or they shall be forever barred from location, survey and patent. And any such certificates which have been entered, located, or sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed and filed in any Districts Surveyor&#8217;s office, or returned to the General Land Office, may be withdrawn from said office for the pur$$pose of being presented to said Commissioner of Claims, without, in any manner, affecting or vitiating said entry, location, or survey.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. It shall be the duty of said Commissioner of Claims, to keep a register of every certificate presented to him under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the next preceding section, stating its number and date, by whom, and to whom, it was issued, the quantity of land it calls for, whether it is a bounty, donation, or headright certificate. If it is a bounty, or donation certificate, he shall state for what service it was issued. If it is a headright certificate, he shall state whether it is a conditional or an unconditional one, and of what class. If it was issued to an assignee, he shall state the name of the assignor and assignee; he shall also state by whom it was presented, and who is represented to be the owner of it at the time; he shall also write across the face of each certificate, the word &#8220;registered,&#8221; and sign his name, with the date of its registry.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. It shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, as early as practicable after the passage of this act, to furnish said Commissioner of Claims with a register of every land certificate that has been returned to his office, except headright cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates of the first and second class, which have been returned as genuine and legal claims, by the Commissioner appointed under &#8220;An Act to detect fraudulent land certificates, and to provide for issuing patents to legal claimants,&#8221; approved 29th January, 1840, and certificates issued under some special act of the Congress of the Republic of Texas, or of the Legislature of this State, and certificates issued to colonists of Peters&#8217; Colony; Mercer&#8217;s Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony; Castro&#8217;s Colony; Fisher and Miller&#8217;s Colony; and the colonists of the German Emigration Company, and certificates issued for premium lands in said colonies, and certificates is<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sued to companies incorporated under the laws of this State, for purposes of internal improvements, and to persons for building vessels, under the provisions of an act of February <pb n="434" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="16" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>3d, 1854, entitled &#8220;An Act to encourage the building of steamboats, steamships, and other vessels in the State of Texas,&#8221; and certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates for unlocated balances heretofore issued,&#8212;hich register shall state the number, and elate of each certificate, by whom and to ty, donation,&#8212;or headright certificate. If it is a bounty, orbdun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />a ty, donation, or headright certificate. If it is a bounty, or dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion certificate, it shall state for what service it was issued&#8212;if it is a headright certificate, it shall state whether it is a conditional or an unconditional one, and of what class. If it was issued to an as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signee, it shall state the name of the assignor and assignee, and af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terwards he shall furnish each week, to said Commissioner of Claims, a similar register of all certificates of the above description, which have been returned during the previous week, and which had not been previously registered by the Commissioner of Claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, to make out, and retain in his office, certified copies of all the reports which have heretofore been made, or may hereafter be made, to his office, by the Clerks of the Boards of Land Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners, and of the District and County Courts of the several coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties of the Republic and the State of Texas, and to transfer the or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />iginal reports to the Commissioner of Claims; and also a certified list of all the certificates issued under the provisions of an Act for the relief of the heirs of those who fell with Fannin, Ward, Travis, Grant, and Johnson, during the war with Mexico, in the years 1835 and 1836, approved February 9th, 1850, to the office of the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of Claims, immediately after he shall have entered upon his duties; and the said certified list of certificates shall have the same force and effect in the office of said Commissioner of Claims, as if it was an original record of his office.</p>
<p>After the said Commissioner of Claims shall hare entered upon the discharge of his duties, the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall not issue a patent upon any land certificate, except headright certificates of the first and second class, which have been returned as genuine and legal by the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners appointed under the provisions of &#8220;An Act to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tect fraudulent land certificates, and to provide for the issuing of patents to legal claimants,&#8221; approved 29th January, 1840. and cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates issued under some special act of the Congress of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, or of the Legislature of this State, and certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="435" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="17" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>cates issued to colonists of Peter&#8217;s Colony; Mercer&#8217;s Colony; Cas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tro&#8217;s Colony; Fisher and Miller&#8217;s Colony; and the colonists of the German Emigration Company; and certificates issued for premium lands in said colonies, and certificates issued to companies incor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />porated under the laws of this State, for the purposes of internal improvements, and to persons for building vessels under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of the act of February 3rd, 1854, entitled &#8220;An Act to en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />courage the building of steamboats, steamships, and other vessels in the State of Texas, and certificates for unlocated balances hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore issued, and pre-emption certificates, until it shall have been presented to and approved by the Commissioner of Claims.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Whenever a land certificate is presented to the said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of Claims for his approval, under the provisions of the next preceding section, he shall register it as directed by the third section of this act, if it has not already been registered, and if it is a headright certificate, he shall compare it with the report of the Clerk of the Board of Land Commissioners, or of the Court by which it purports to have been issued, and if satisfied that it is a genuine certificate, he shall write across the face of it the word &#8220;ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved,&#8221; with the date of its approval, and sign his name thereto. If, however, such certificate was issued to an assignee, and he shall have reason to believe the assignment thereof was forged, he shall withhold his approval until the assignment is proved to be genuine by the evidence of, at least, two credible witnesses, in open Court, or by depositions taken before any officer in this State using a seal, and until the identity and residence of the parties, and witnesses to such assignment is proved in the same manner. If such certificate is a bounty, or donation certificate, and he has in his office any rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ord, or paper, showing it to be a genuine one, or if the evidence of at least two Credible witnesses taken as above, is produced to him that it is a genuine one, he shall file such evidence, and shall write across the face of the certificate the word &#8220;approved,&#8221; with the date of its approval, and sign his name thereto: Provided, however, that he shall withhold his approval from any bounty, or donation cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate, issued to an assignee since the 24th day of November, 1851, until the genuineness of the assignment, and the identity and residence of the parties and witnesses thereto, shall be proved by the testimony of, at least, two credible witnesses, in the manner herein prescribed; and should the Commissioner of Claims, upon said investigation and examination of any such <pb n="436" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="18" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>bounty or donation, headright or other certificate, issued to an as<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signee, be satisfied that the original assignor was entitled to said certificate, and no satisfactory evidence of the genuineness of the assignment shall be presented, he shall endorse said certificate &#8220;ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved for the benefit of the oroginal assignor,&#8221; giving his name, and in all such cases the patents upon said certificates shall issue in the name of said original assignor, and be retained in the office of the Commissioner until the rightful owner thereof shall be shown. In all cases where certificates shall be approved under the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this section, the said Commissioner shall note the approval, with the date thereof, in the margin of his register, opposite to the entry of the certificate; and any individual holding a headlight cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate which may be rejected, or refused to be approved by said Commissioner of Claims, shall have the right within twelve months from the time of such rejection, to bring suit in the District Court of the county in which said certificate issued, for the establishment of the same; which suit shall be brought and conducted in the man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ner prescribed for the establishment of certificates not recommend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by the act of February 4th, 1841, entitled &#8220;An Act supplement<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary to an act to detect fraudulent land certificates and to provide for the issuing patents to legal claimants.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sec. 7. Any person entitled to a headright, or bounty, or dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion land, under the colonization laws of Coahnila and Texas, or the Constitution and laws of the Republic or State of Texas, who has not heretofore received a patent, or certificate therefor, or his heirs, in case he be dead, may apply to the said Commissioner of Claims, and obtain a certificate for such land, in all eases where he or they, prove their right by such evidence as would have author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized the issuance of such certificate by any officer or officers of the Republic or State of Texas, under the laws in force at any time pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious to the first day of November, A. D. 1853, and shall also prove his or their identity and residence by the testimony of, at least, two credible witnesses, in the manner herein prescribed: Provided, how<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever, that no certificate shall issue to an assignee under the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this section; and provided, also, that this section shall not apply to the claims of those persons who fell with Fannin, Ward, Travis, Grant and Johnson, in 1835 and 1836, which are otherwise hereinafter provided for.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. In eases Where persons described in the nest preced<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing section, shall not be able to prove their right before the <pb n="437" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="19" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Commissioner, by such evidence as would have authorized the issu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of such a certificate by any officer, or officers, of the Republic or State of Texas, under the provisions of the laws in force at any time previous to the first day of November, A. D. 1853, they may present their application to said Commissioner, with the best evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence it is in their power to produce in regard to their right to the land for which they apply, together with proof of their identity and residence, by the testimony of, at least, two credible witnesses, and it shall be the duty of said Commissioner to report to the Legisla<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ture, for its action, as often as it may meet, a list of all such appli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cations, with the evidence in support thereof, and his opinion in re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gard thereto. All such claims for land, not presented within two years after the passage of this act, shall be forever barred.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The Commissioner of the General Land Office shall, as early as practicable after the passage of this act, furnish to said Commissioner of Claims, certified copies of those copies of the mus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter rolls of the several companies that were under the command of Fannin and Ward, and also of those copies of the lists of the names of those who fell in the Alamo, with Travis and with Grant, and under the command, of Johnson, during the war with Mexico, in the year 1836, which were furnished by the Adjutant General to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, under the provisions of an act for the relief of the heirs of those who fell with Fannin, Ward, Travis, Grant and Johnson, during the war with Mexico, in the years 1835 and 1836, approved February 9th, 1850; which copies, when furnished, shall have the same force and effect in the office of said Commissioner of Claims, as if they were original rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ords in his office. And the said Commissioner of Claims shall here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after perform all the duties of the Adjutant General under the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of said recited act; provided, however, that no Certificate shall hereafter he issued under the provisions of said act, unless the applicant shall prove his identity, and residence by the testi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mony of, at least, two credible witnesses, in the manner herein pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed; and provided, also, that no certificate shall be issued in the name of an assignee under said act.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The said Commissioners of Claims shall hereafter per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />form all the duties required of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, under the provisions of an act to provide for the liqui<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dation of the public debt of the Republic of Texas, approved Febru<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 11th, 1850.</p>
<pb n="438" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="20" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 11. The Commissioner of Claims shall also perform all the duties required of the Commissioner of the General Land Office, under the provisions of an act authorizing the issuing of duplicates, land warrants, discharges, and certificates for head-right claims upon certain conditions, approved 14th January, 1840, and also un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the provisions of an act to amend the 1st Sec. of an act approv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed 14th Jan., 1840, entitled An Act authorising the issuing dupli<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate land warrants, discharges and certificates for head-right claims upon certain conditions, approved May 11th, 1846. He shall be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to issue duplicate, bounty and donation certificates, in the same manner that the Secretary of war, or Adjutant General could have done at any time heretofore: Provided, the applicant for a duplicate shall comply with all the requisites prescribed in said two acts, and shall also prove by the testimony of at least, two credible witnesses or record evidence, that the original certificate which is said to have been lost or destroyed, did, in fact, issue; and shall also prove that the original has not been returned to the General Land Office, and shall also prove his identity and residence by the same number of witnesses; and provided also, that if the original certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate was issued to an assignee, the assignment and the identity and residence of the parties and witnesses thereto, shall be proved in the same manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Whenever any person shall desire to procure a certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate for an unlocated balance, of any certificate upon which a pat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ent has issued, he may procure from the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office, a certificate showing that he is entitled to such unlocated balance, and also fully describing the original certificate, and how much thereof has been patented, and upon the presenta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion thereof to said Commissioner of claims, he shall record it, and issue a new certificate, for such unlocated balance. Such new certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate shall he countersigned by the Commissioner of the General Land Office, and may then be located, surveyed and patented as other genuine certificates. The Commissioner of claims shall keep a descriptive register of all such new certificates issued by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. Whenever a certificate shall be presented to the Commissioner of Claims for registry only, and he shall have reason to believe that it was improperly issued, from any cause, he shall, after registering it, write his belief across the face of it, with the date and his signature, before returning it; and also, whenever a certificate shall be presented to him for his approval, and he shall fail to approve it for any cause, <pb n="439" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="21" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>he shall write across the face of it the reason why he fails to ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prove it, with the date and his signature.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. The Governor shall be, and he his hereby authorized to appoint three discreet persons, with powers to examine the rec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ords of any of the Boards of Land Commissioners, and of the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict and County Courts of any county in this State, and to examine persons in regard to the manner in which such records have been kept, and make a full report of their proceedings whenever in his opinion the public interest will be subserved by such examination, and the persons so appointed shall be entitled to receive from the State the sum of three dollars each, for every day they may be neces<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sarily employed under their appointments.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. It shall be the duty of the Commissioner of Claims, to procure all duplicates and copies of muster rolls of the companies that have heretofore served in the Republic or State of Texas, with such evidence in regard to their authenticity, as can be obtained, and file the same in his office, for the purpose of aiding him in detecting frauds that have heretofore been practiced upon the Government, or that hereafter may be attempted.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. All oral evidence submitted to said Commissioner of Claims, shall be reduced to writing, and signed by the party giving it, and shall then be sworn to before said Commissioner, or his clerk, who shall be authorized to administer oaths in all cases required in the discharge of the duties of their office, and all such evidence, and all other testimony issued before said Commissioner, shall be filed and preserved by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. That said Commissioner of Claims shall report weekly to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, a descriptive list of all certificates which he has issued and approved for the week pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vious, and he shall annually make a report on the first day of Oc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tober, to the Governor, of the number and description of certificates that he has issued and approved for the year previous.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. He shall demand and receive a fee of one dollar for each duplicate certificate and for each certificate for an unlocated balance, and for each certificate to a Railroad Company, and for each certificate, as a reward or bonus for the building of a steamboat, steamship, or other vessel, that he may issue. He shall also demand and receive a fee of five dollars for each certificate for one league and labor; three dollars for each certificate of twelve hundred and eighty acres, or over <pb n="440" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="22" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>that amount, and less than one league and labor, and two dollars for each certificate for loss than twelve hundred and eighty acres, that he may issue as head-rights, and no fee shall be demanded for any original bounty or donation certificate. He shall enter all such fees, and by whom paid, in a book, to be kept for that purpose, and shall account for and pay over all such fees quarterly, to the State Treasurer.</p>
<p>Sec. 19, He shall procure a seal for the authentication of all in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struments of writing emanating from his office, which shall have a star of five points in the center, and the words &#8220;Commissioner of Claims, Texas,&#8221; around the star.</p>
<p>Sec. 20. The several clerks of the District and County Courts of this State, shall, hereafter, report to the said Commissioner of Claims, all certificates for land obtained from their courts, in the same manner that they were heretofore required to report them to the Commissioner of the General Land Office.</p>
<p>Sec. 21. The said Commissioner of Claims shall, hereafter, issue all land certificates to Rail Road Companies, which the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioner of the General Land Office is authorized or required to issue under any law of the State; and also all land certificates that the Commissioner of the General Land Office is authorized or required to issue under the provisions of an act, to encourage the building of steamboats, steamships, and other vessels in the State of Texas, approved 3d February, 1854, and all applications for such certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates shall, hereafter, be presented to said Commissioner of Claims, in the same manner as they were heretofore required to be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sented to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, and the said Commissioner of Claims shall issue all such certificates in like manner, and under like restrictions as the Commissioner of the Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral Land Office, was heretofore required to issue them.</p>
<p>Sec. 22. The list of persons composing the regiment un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the command of Edward Burleson, at the Battle of San Jacinto, which is now in the possession of the Governor of this State, together with the affidavit of Captain Jesse Billingsley, attached thereto, proving its authenticity, and also the manu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />script book, now in possession of the Governor, purporting to contain copies of certain muster rolls that were heretofore in the Adjutant General&#8217;s Office, shall be deposited in the office of the said Commissioner of Claims, and may be used by him as evidence upon Which to approve bounty, and donation certificates heretofore issued by the Adjutant General of this <pb n="441" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="23" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>State, and by the Secretary of War of the late Republic of Texas.</p>
<p>Sec. 23. The said Commissioner of Claims shall not act as the agent of any person for the prosecution of a claim of any de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scription against the Republic or State of Texas; nor as the agent of any person in locating lands or procuring patents for lands; nor as the agent for any person in or about the registry; approval, or issu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of any land certificate whatever; nor shall he hereafter pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase any interest in any claim for land or money against the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public or State of Texas; and if he shall violate any of the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this section, he shall, on conviction therefor, be fined in a sum not less than two thousand dollars, and shall thereafter be ineligible to hold any office in this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 24. That said Commissioner of Claims shall also perform all the duties imposed upon the Auditor, by the provisions of &#8220;An Act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved March 20th, 1848, in the same manner, and under like restrictions; and every person having a claim against the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, for services, or supplies furnished the government or the army, or for property taken for the use of the government, or the army, shall present the same to the Commissioiner of Claims, and Comptroller of Public Accounts, on or before the first day of January, 1858, or the same shall be forever barred.</p>
<p>Sec. 25. When any claim is presented to said officers, under the provisions of the next preceding section, if the party shall produce to said officers such vouchers, and proof in support thereof, as would have permitted it to be audited under the laws of the Republic of Texas, they shall jointly receipt for the same, under their hands and seals of office, setting forth the par value thereof, at the time ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />crued, the name of the person to whom it accrued, and the date and amount thereof; and such receipts shall be paid by the State Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nrer, whenever an appropriation shall be made therefor.</p>
<p>Sec. 26. Every person who shall present a claim to the said Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner and Comptroller, under the provisions of this act, shall prove his identity and residence, by the testimony of, at least, two credible witnesses, in the manner herein prescribed; and if the ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plicant be an assignee, he shall also prove the identity and residence of the parties and witnesses to the assignment, in the same manner.</p>
<p>Sec. 27. That all the books, papers, and archives, in and <pb n="442" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="24" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>belonging to the Auditor&#8217;s office, shall be turned over to the Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioner of Claims mentioned in this act, and become a part of the archives of his office.</p>
<p>Sec. 28. That &#8220;An Act supplementary to an act to provide for ascertaining the debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved March 20th, 1848, and so much of an act to fix the salaries of cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain State officers, approved 11th February, 1854, as fixes the salary of Auditor at Fifteen Hundred Dollars, and an act to provide for closing the business of the late war and marine department, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved April 27th, 1846, and the second section of &#8220;An Act requir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents upon unconditional headright certificates for land,&#8221; approved May 12th, 1846, and &#8220;An Act to provide for the issuance of bounty, and donation land warrants, to persons entitled to the same,&#8221; approved 31st January, 1854, and so much of &#8220;An Act to fix the salary of certain State Officers,&#8221; approved 11th February, 1854, as places the salary of the Adjutant General at Twelve Hundred Dollars; shall be, and the same are hereby repealed; and all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed; and this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 1, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to punish persons for writing upon, defacing, or disfiguring the walls of the public buildings of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That any person or persons who may write, scratch upon, in any manner deface or disfigure the walls of the State Capitol, or any other public buildings belonging to the State, either inside or out<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />side of the same, or of any of the rooms, halls, steps, columns, ban<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isters, galleries, doors or other appurtenances in any manner be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing or pertaining to the same, shall be deemed guilty of a mis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />demeanor and subject to a fine of not exceeding fifty nor less than five dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Mayor of the city of Austin, or any Justice of the Peace in said city, shall have and exercise juris<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />diction in all offences under the first section of this act, and that whenever information shall be given to said Mayor or <pb n="443" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="25" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Justice of the Peace that an offence has been committed within the meaning of this act, he shall issue his warrant directed to any Mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />shal or Constable of said city or beat, commanding the arrest of said offender or offenders.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever any person or persons shall be found guilty of any offence under this act, and shall fail to pay the fine and costs adjudged against him or them, then and in that case, said Mayor or Justice of the Peace, before whom said offender shall be tried, shall have the power of imprisoning said person or persons so found guilty, in the county or city jail until the fine and costs of prosecution be paid. Provided said imprisonment shall not exceed forty days. And that in all prosecutions under this act, the said Mayor, Justice of the Peace, Marshal or Constable shall be allowed the same fees as are by law allowed in prosecutions for misdemean<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ors, in the District Court, said fees in all cases to be taxed against the defendant. And all fines collected under this act shall be paid by said Mayor or Justice of the Peace into the Treasury of the city of Austin, for the use and benefit of said city.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to locate permanently the County Seat of Newton county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the town of Newton, in the county of Newton, be, and the same is hereby declared to be the permanent County Seat of Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice of said county, and all laws and parts of laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed. Provided that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to prevent the citizens of Newton county from removing or selecting the County Seat under the provisions of an act entitled &#8220;An Act pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viding for the removal of County Seats of Justice,&#8221; approved May 9th, 1838.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="444" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="26" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for the per diem pay and mileage of the members of the sixth Legislature, and the per diem pay of the officers of the same at the adjourned session thereof, which commenced on the 7th day of July, A. D. 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the members of the adjourned session of the sixth legislature, shall be entitled to mileage at the same rate that members are en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled by law, to receive at the regular session of tho Legislature, and that the sum of fifty thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any monies in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the per diem pay and mileage of the members, and the per diem pay of the officers of the sixth Legislature of the State of Texas, at the ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />journed session thereof, which commenced on the seventh day of July, A. D., 1856, and that the certificate of the Secretary of the Senate and the Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives shall be authority for the Comptroller to draw on the Treasurer for the sev<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral amounts that the members and officers are respectively en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Vetoed by the Governor and passed by a constitutional majority, <date>August 4th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for compensation for arms lost by the Georgia Battalion at the massacre of Goliad.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of three thousand dollars or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury, not otherwise appropriated, for the purpose of paying for arms lost by the Georgia battallion at the massacre of Goliad.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That the Governor of the State of Texas is hereby required to ascertain from the Governor of the State of Georgia, how much the State of Georgia demands of the State of <pb n="445" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="27" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Texas, as due for said arms, and who is entitled to the same, and when the Governor of the State of Texas has ascertained how much there is due for said arms, he shall draw on the Treasurer of the State in favor of the party found to be entitled to the same, for the amount ascertained to be due, and this act shall be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 6th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create a new Land District out of the territory comprised within the County of Karnes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of the land district of Bexar, Goliad and San Patricio, comprised within the limits of the county of Karnes, be, and the same is hereby declared to be a separate Land District.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall cause to be made a map of said district, upon good drafting paper, embracing all the returned surveys of land situated in said District, up to the time of making the same map, which have been properly returned by the several District surveyors, and forward said map as soon as possible to the Chief Justice of Karnes County, who shall deliver the same to the surveyor of said District, subject to such amendments alterations and additions as future surveyors may make necessary.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That the Chief Justice of Karnes county shall, as soon as he is satisfied that all the provisions of the law relative to the cre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ation of new land districts, have been complied with, order an elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion for a District Surveyor of said District, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 7th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="446" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="28" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER XCIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to locate permanently the County Seat of Justice of Ange<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lina County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first Tuesday in November, A. D., 1856, be fixed as the day for holding an election in the county of Angelina, for the selection of a suitable and permanent location for the seat of Justice of said county, and it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of Angelina county, to give public notice of said election and to give orders for the same, and to have them posted at the different precincts of said county, at least ten days previous to said election; and should an election not be holden on the day above mentioned, then said Chief Justice shall again advertise by posting up public notices as above for another election on such day as he may select, and that place which shall receive a majority or the highest num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber of votes, shall be the seat of Justice in said county, provided it shall be within five miles of the recognized centre of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That should there be unappropriated land within five miles of the centre of said county, and should a majority of the voters select the same as a suitable place for the location of said seat of Justice, then and in that ease the State does hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />linquish her right to, and does hereby donate to the said county of Angelina, six hundred and forty acres of land, which may be patent<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by the Commissioner upon the return of the field notes into his office, accompanied with satisfactory evidence that the said seat of justice has been located upon the same, in conformity with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That it shall be the duty of the Chief Justice of said county to receive written proposals of donations by private indi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viduals, of any lands lying within five miles of said centre, as in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducements for said location, and that he shall make said proposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions public, and have power to enforce that individual whose propo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sition has been accepted, and the seat of justice located on the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed donation, to make and convey title to said county to all lands by him proposed to be donated; by suit in the District Court, commenced and conducted in the name of the said county of An<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gelina.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, That the election of said seat of Justice shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="447" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="29" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ducted as other elections, and the returns made to the Chief Justice within ten days after the election, who shall publish the result and declare the place receiving the majority or highest number of votes, to be the best legal seat for the county of Angelina.</p>
<p>Sec. 5, That Thomas Crawford, Calvin Jones, P. J. Cochrane, James L. Ewing, Dr. Manning, William Gann and Joseph Jones, four of whom shall constitute a quorum to do business, shall be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners to lay out, sell and trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fer lots, to superintend the location made and selected according to the provisions of this act, and to report to the Chief Justice whether or not the title to the land upon which said seat of justice has been located, has been made to the county by individuals, or by the State in accordance with the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6, That as soon as county buildings have been received by the Commissioners and reported to the Chief Justice, the Clerks of the District and County Courts, Sheriff and Surveyor, shall remove their offices and papers to the place selected as said seat of justice.</p>
<p>Sec. 7, That all laws, and parts of laws, conflicting with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, be, and they are hereby repealed, and that this act shall take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 11, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER C.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the County Court of McLennan County to levy a special tax for two years.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the County Count of McLennan county shall have power to levy a special tax for the purpose of building a Court House in said county, upon all the subjects of taxation in said county, on which a tax may be levied by the State or County, Provided, said tax shall not exceed in any one year double the amount of the tax levied by the State on such subjects of taxation; and provided also that such tax shall be apportioned in the same manner as the State Tax.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That the special tax levied by virtue of this act, shall be assessed and collected by the Assessor and Collector <pb n="448" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="30" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of the State Tax of said County, in the same manner as the State Tax, and shall be paid by him into the county treasury. Said Asses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sor and Collector shall have the same power to enforce the collection of such tax for said county as for the collection of taxes for the State, and shall receive the same compensation.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That the revenue raised under the provisions of this act, shall be expended exclusively in building and furnishing a suitable Court House for said county, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 11, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide an Office for the Court of Claims.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of tie State of Texas, That tie Commissioner of Claims be, and be is hereby authorized to use two of the rooms in the basement story of the Capitol, for the transaction of the business of his office. And that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 11th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplemental and amendatory of an act to authorize and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire the County Court of the county of Brazoria, to establish, dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />continue and regulate public and private roads in said county, and to cause public roads and bridges to be constructed and kept in good repair. Approved January 28th, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the second section of the aforesaid act shall read as follows:</p>
<p>&#8220;Section 2, That the County Court shall divide the county into road precincts, and assign to each precinct as many sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyors as may be necessary. Every application for a new pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic road in said county, must be made by at least twelve house holders in the precinct in which the road is desired, and must <pb n="449" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="31" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>specify the place of beginning, and the termination of the road pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 21 of said act shall read&#8212;&#8220;That it shall be the duty of the County Court of said county, at their first regular term in every year, to appoint for each precinct surveyors of the public roads therein, who shall serve for one year and until others are appointed.</p>
<p>Section 28 of said act shall read&#8212;&#8220;That he shall cause them to be kept clear of obstructions of all kinds, of necessary width, and secure from falling of dead timber thereon; he shall cause such causeways, ditches and culverts to be made as shall seem necessary.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 40 of said act shall read&#8212;&#8220;That no surveyor during his time of service shall be required to serve on jury (juries), in any of the courts of the county, unless by his consent, nor shall he be re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to pay a road poll tax.&#8221;</p>
<p>Section 64 of said act shall read&#8212;&#8220;That the Assessor and Collec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tor of the county shall assess and collect the road tax at the same time and under the same regulations and penalties prescribed by law, so far as they may be applicable for the assessment and collection of the county tax, and he shall give a bond unto the county for the faithful performance of his duties, in a sum double the amount of the tax assessed, and said bond shall correspond in its form and legal application and effects, to the bond required to be given by him to the county for the collection of the county tax, and this act shall take effect from and after its passage.&#8221;</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 11th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the investment of the Special School Fund in the bonds of Railroad Companies incorporated by the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor, Comptroller and Attorney Gen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eral, shall ex-officio constitute a board of School Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to draw from the Treasury the Special School Fund created by the act of January 31st, 1854, enti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled an act to establish a system of Schools, and such other amount as may hereafter be added to said fund, and invest the <pb n="450" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="32" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>same as provided in this act. And said board shall annually report to the Governor its acts and proceedings relative to the said School Fund, which shall be laid before the Legislature at each and every session thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the five per cent. indemnity bonds belonging to said Special School Fund may, and shall be loaned to legally incorporated Railroad Companies in this State, at their current value, including premium; provided, said value shall not be less than par, otherwise at par, for the term of ten years from the date of said loans, at an inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est of six per cent per annum, payable annually upon the terms and conditions specified in this act; provided, that one half of said fund shall be loaned to companies whose work lies east of the Trinity riv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er, and the residue to companies whose works lie west of said river.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. Said Board of Commissioners, is hereby authorized to in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vest. said funds by loaning to any such company which has been chartered for the purpose of building a railroad in this State, the sum of six thousand dollars per mile, for each and every mile of Rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road constructed as hereinafter provided. Said loans to be secured by the bonds of such company for said principal and interest, made and executed to the State of Texas, in the Corporate name of such company, signed by the President and countersigned by the Secre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary or Treasurer, under the seal of such company; which bond shall constitute a lien upon the road and charter rights of such company, including the road bed, right of way, grading, bridges, iron rails, equipments and masonry, and upon all the stock subscribed for in said companies, all the depots and depot stations, and all the prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty owned by such company, as necessary for its business. And the State of Texas, upon the execution of said bonds, and by virtue of the same, shall be invested with said lien or mortgage, for the pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of said bonds and the interest thereon, as the same becomes due, without the necessity of any deed, special contract or act of reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istration.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said Board of Commissioners shall loan said sum of six thousand dollars for every mile of road completed, to any such company as shall have completed in a good and sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stantial manner, and furnished ready for actual use a conti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nuous section of twenty-five miles of the road of said company, and graded an additional consecutive section of twenty-five miles, ready for the cross ties and other superstructure; and the same amount per mile for every additional consecutive sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="451" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="33" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tion of ten miles, which shall be so completed and graded ready for the ties and other superstructure. And the same amount per mile for every section of ten miles which shall be so completed and furn<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ished ready for use upon any railroad which shall be a continuation of, or connection with any other railroad running from any ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />joining State or Territory in the State of Texas; provided, said road shall, together with such continuation or connection, be completed at least twenty-five miles in length; and provided, that before said loan is drawn upon any completed section of ten miles, an additional consecutive section of ten miles shall be graded ready for the ties and other superstructure.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That upon the application of any such railroad company to said Board of Commissioners, for said loan, and its representa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions that section fourth of this act has been complied with, said Board of Commissioners shall appoint some competent Engineer, who shall, at the expense of the company, examine the road of said company, and make a full report upon the condition of the same, under oath, and shall report all matters pertaining to the business of said company, which he may deem useful to said Commissioners, in ascertaining the true condition of said road and company. And upon being fully satisfied that any section or sections of said road hare been constructed and completed, as provided in the fourth sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of this act, and that said section or sections are not subject to any lien whatever, other than such as may be created by this act, in favor of the State, said Board shall draw a warrant on the Treasury of the State, in the name of said company, against said Special School Fund, for such amount of said bonds as it may be entitled to under the provisions of this act, which warrant shall state on ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count of what work it is drwan, shall be signed by said Board of Commissioners and countersigned by the Governor, and delivered to the President or the duly authorized agent of said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That upon the presentation of such warrant or warrants to the Treasury of the State, the amount of said indemnity bonds called for in the same, shall be delivered and transferred according to law, to the President or authorized agent of said company; his receipt taken therefor and the same charged to the Special School Fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That before said Board shall deliver to said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany said warrant or warrants upon the Treasury, it shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quire said company to execute and deliver into the Treasury <pb n="452" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="34" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the bonds of said company, for said loan or loans in sums of not more than one hundred and fifty thousand dollars, and not less than fifty thousand dollars each, payable to the State of Texas ten years after date, together with coupon bonds for the six per cent interest thereon, payable annually as above stated; which bonds shall be exe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cuted in the mode prescribed in the third section of this act, and shall be made payable at the office of the Treasurer of the State, and which shall be a lien in favor of the State as specified in the third section of this act, and shall have a priority over all other claims against said company. That in addition to the annual interest of six per cent, every company accepting any loan under the provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act, shall pay annually at the expiration of each year, from the date of the loan, the further sum of two per cent upon the amount of the loan, info the Treasury of the State, for the purpose of establishing a sinking fund, to be applied towards the payment of the loan at its maturity, and the amount so paid for the purpose of such Sinking Fund with their accumulations, shall be credited to such Railroad.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. And after the execution of said bonds upon said first section, or any subsequent constructed section, it shall not be law<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ful for said company to give, create or convey to any person or per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons, or body corporate whatever, any lien, incumbrance or mort<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gage of any kind which shall have priority over, or come in conflict with the lien herein secured, and any such lien, incumbrance or mortgage, shall be null and void, as against said lien or mortgage, in favor of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That it shall be the duty of any such company as the interest becomes due upon said bonds, executed as aforesaid, to de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posit the same in the Treasury of the State, which amount shall be credited to the Special School Fund, and shall be subject to the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediate appropriation for school purposes, as provided by law. And all railroad companies shall pay said interest so due by them, an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nually, on the first day of March, out of the first receipts arising from said road, independent of any expenses or other liabilities of said roads, and the coupon bonds of such companies so satisfied, shall be cancelled and delivered up.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. Whenever any of the bonds of said company for the principal loaned thereon, shall become due, said company shall deposit said sums so due, in the Treasury of the State, <pb n="453" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="35" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and said bonds, when so paid, shall be cancelled and delivered up, and said principal sums so returned into the Treasury, shall be cred<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ited to the Special School Fund, and subject to reinvestment by said board as provided in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. That if any such company shall fail or refuse to pay said principal or interest bonds from time to time, as the same shall become due, the road of said company, together with all the rights and property of said company, specified in section third of this act, shall be sold or caused to be sold by the Governor of the State, for the satisfaction of said bonds so due, as well as the bonds of said company, which may have been given under this act to the State, and the whole of said bonds shall be deemed due if said sale takes place, and the proceeds of such sales shall be deposited in the Treasury and credited to the Special School Fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. That upon the failure of any such company to pay said principal or interest bonds, as required in this act, it shall be the duty of the Governor, after the expiration of thirty days, to cause notice of the sale of such road to be advertised in some newspaper published at the seat of government, for the term of three months. And after due notice has been given, shall cause the entire road, to<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gether with all the rights and property of said company, specified in the third section of this act, to be sold at public auction to the high<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est bidder for cash, at the door of the Capitol of the State, and at the time specified in said advertisement; provided, that if the princi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pal or interest bonds which may have become due before the giving of said notice, and all cost attending said proceedings shall be paid before the day of sale, then said proceedings for sale shall be stopped.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. In the event of any sale of any railroad under the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act, it shall be the duty of the Governor, either in person or by agent, to attend such sale and protect the interest of the Spe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial School Fund, and shall, if necessary to protect said interest, buy in said road with all the rights and property belonging to said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany, in the name of the Board of School Commissioners; provided, he shall not bid more than the amount of the bonds of said com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pany with the interest due thereon, and the cost and expenses attending said sales. And in the event of any such purchase in the name of the Board of School Commissioners, the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor shall appoint a receiver, who shall be required to enter <pb n="454" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="36" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>into such bonds as may be required by the Governor, and whose duty it shall be to take immediate possession of and to control and man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age said road, under direction of the Governor, until otherwise dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of by law, the said Board of School Commissioners shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain in the Treasury of the State, charged to the credit of the School Fund, five per cent of the United States bonds, of all sums loaned, as provided in this act, as a sinking fund, to be used for the &#8220;pro rata&#8221; appropriation annually due to the several counties for school purposes, an the event of the interest due to the School Fund after the sale of any railroad, shall not be paid by said road.</p>
<p>Sec. 14. The Slate of Texas expressly reserves the right to enact hereafter all such laws as may be deemed necessary to protect the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest of the Special School Fund, in securing the payment of said bonds and in enforcing the lien reserved thereon.</p>
<p>Sec. 15. That the provisions of this act shall not extend to any railroad company which may be entitled to receive from the State a larger grant of land than sixteen sections of six hundred and forty acres to the mile, for the construction of such road, nor to any road for more than a single trunk, with the necessary turn outs, nor to any branch road, nor to any road which shall not be commenced and prosecuted as required by the provisions of its charter. Provided, that no company shall be entitled to a loan under this act for any section of road between the cities of Galveston and Houston, or Gal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veston and the crossing of Buffalo Bayou, near the city of Houston.</p>
<p>Sec. 16. That no railroad which, is less than fifty miles in length, according to the terms of its charter, shall be entitled to the benefits of this act, except on the foliowing terms: The Brownsville and Rio Grande Railroad shall be entitled to the benefits of this act on its entire length, as soon as it is completed from Point Isabel to Brownsville; and any other railroad which is less than fifty miles in length, according to the terms of its charter, whenever One-half of its entire length has been completed and put in rnnning order, and the other half has been graded ready for the ties and other super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />structure, shall be entitled to said loan on said completed section, which shall be expended for the completion of the entire road; and in no event shall said roads be entitled to said loan on more than one-half of its entire length.</p>
<p>Sec. 17. If any person making an affidavit as herein required, shall knowingly swear falsely, he, upon conviction thereof be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="455" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="37" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fore any court of competent jusisdiction, shall suffer all the pains and penalties of perjury.</p>
<p>Sec. 18. That it shall be the duty of any railroad company re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceiving the benefits of this act, to make through its proper officers an annual report under oath, to the Governor, containing a full and complete statement of the affairs of said company, together with the receipts, expenditures and liabilities of said companies, and with such other facts as may be necessary, under the general laws regulat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing railroads and said railroad companies.</p>
<p>Sec. 19. That every railroad company before it shall be entitled to the privileges of this act, shall establish upon the line of its road an oflice where books shall be kept, showing the state of its stock and general accounts, and where the company may be legally served with all notices and processes, and the Superintendent or principal manager of the transportation business of the road, shall reside in this State. And whenever a majority of the shares in the capital stock of the company shall be owned in this State, a majority of the Directors, including the President, shall be residents thereof. And that this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 13th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>Ad Act to make valid certain surveys made in the county of Hen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the surveys made by A. F. Mallard, as the District Surveyor of Henderson District, in the county of Henderson, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tween the 24th day of December 1853, and the first Monday of Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust, 1854, be and the same are hereby made as valid as if said Mal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lard had been legally elected and qualified.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall not be so construed as to affect the rights of third persons, nor to make valid any survey made upon land not at the time legally open to location and survey.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 15th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="456" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="38" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the Commissioner of Claims to employ an addi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tional Clerk.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of Claims be, and he is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized to employ an additional Clerk whenever the business of the office may require it, at a salary of seventy-five dollars per month, who shall continue in office only so long as his services may be required.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 15th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Clerk of the County Court of Houston County to transcribe the Mark and Brand Book of said County, and index the Same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Clerk of the County Court of Houston county, be, and he is hereby authorized and required to transcribe the Mark and Brand Book of said Houston county, in a well bound book, to be furnished him by said County Court for that purpose, and prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erly index the same, and when the same shall have been examined and approved by the County Court of said county, the same shall have all the force and effect in law and equity that the original could or should have, and all certified copies taken from the same shall be as valid and have the same force and effect as if taken from the original.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the said County Clerk shall receive such compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation for his services as shall be allowed and paid by said County Court, not to exceed fifteen cents for each hundred words so trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect and be in force from and after is passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 15th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="457" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="39" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Pre-emption Claimants.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all persons who have heretofore settled within the limits of Peter&#8217;s Colony, as Pre-emptionists, and have complied with the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quirements of the laws in force at the time of their settlement, shall he as fully entitled to the benefits of the pre-emtpion laws under which they made their settlements as pre-emptionists in any part of the State. Any reservation for colonial purposes, to the contrary notwithstanding; provided, such pre-emption settlements do not con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flict with any legal locations or surveys previously made.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all pre-emptionists who failed to have their land surveyed within eight months after their settlement, shall have eight months further time to do so. And twelve months after the passage of this act, in which to return the same to the General hand Office. And where no field-notes of a survey were made out, a certified copy of the surveyor&#8217;s record of survey shall be sufficient in lieu of such field-notes.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That sections one and two of this act shall apply to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />emptors outside of Peter&#8217;s Colony, as well as to those within it; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that this act shall not be construed to confer any rights or grant any relief to those persons who have settled as pre-emptors within the Pacific Railroad Reservation, since twenty-first day of December, eighteen hundred and fifty-three, whether they have set<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tled within or without Peter&#8217;s Colony; and that this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 15th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish an Institution for the Education of the Blind.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated and set apart for the establishment of an Institution for the Education of the blind of Texas, which shall be located at the city of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. A board of five Trustees stall be appointed by the <pb n="458" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="40" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Governor, whose duty it shall be to administer the funds of said In<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />stitution and provide for its going into operation as soon as practica<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble, by renting a suitable building and appointing such superinten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dent and other officers as may be required for the successful man<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />agement of said Institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The said sum of ten thousand dollars shall be paid on the order of said Trustees, approved and countersigned by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, as the actual current expenses of maintaining the Institution, shall accrue; provided, that not more than five thousand dollars shall be expended in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said Trustees shall be and they are hereby required to make full and accurate annual reports to the Governor of the State, showing the condition and progress of the Institution, with a full exhibit of all expenditures, and it shall be the duty of the Governor to lay the same before the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act shall take effect from date of passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 16th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to pay James H. Rogers for services as Special Judge of the Supreme Court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller be authorized to draw a draft on the Treasurer in favor of James H. Rogers, for two hundred dollars, which shall be paid out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the same being the amount due the said Rogers for services as Spe<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cial Judge of the Supreme Court, in the case of Horton vs. Ennis and Reynolds, decided at the April term, A. D. 1852, and Blunt vs. Webster, at the April term, A. D. 1856, at Tyler.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 19th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="459" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="41" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first and fifth sections of an act creating the country of Young, approved 2d February, 1856.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 1st of the above recited act, and section 5th of same act, read as follows:</p>
<p>Sec. 1. That all the territory comprised within the following limits, &#8220;to wit:&#8220; beginning at a point six miles east from the south-east corner of lower Brazos Indian reserve, as surveyed by English meas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ure; thence north thirty miles; thence west thirty miles; thence south thirty miles; thence east to the place of beginning, be, and the same is hereby created into and constituted a new county, under the name and style of the county of Young.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That for Judicial purposes the territory north from the north-east corner of said county, to Red River; thence west with said stream to the United States territory; thence south to a point west from the southern source of the clear fork of the Brazos; thence east to the source of such stream, and down the same to the main Brazos, and thence in a direct line to the south-east corner of said county; thence north to the place of beginning, shall be un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the jurisdiction of said county: and when said county is created into a Land District, it shall embrace the above described territory.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 19th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to validate the acts of Levi S. McMicken, as Deputy County Clerk of Polk county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the official acts of Levi S. McMicken, as Deputy Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty Clerk of Polk county, under W. H. Dukes, his principal, from the date of his deputation, until his successor was or shall be elected and - duly qualified, be, and the same are hereby declared to be valid and legal as though said Dukes had continued to reside in Polk county.</p>
<pb n="460" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="42" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 19th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>All Act to legalize surveys made in Hunt county by John Grainger, between the 1st day of August 1851 and 1852.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all surveys made in Hunt county by John Grainger, between the 1st day of August 1851 and the 1st day of August 1852, be, and they are hereby declared to be as legal and valid as if the said Grainger had been the legally elected Surveyor of said county. Provided that in all other respects the said surveys shall have been made in pursuance of the laws of this State, and further provided that this act shall in no wise validate surveys made during said period, not otherwise in strict accordance with law. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>20th August, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation for defraying the expenses of the State Penitentiary.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated, for the purchase of material, pay of master work<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />men, Engineers, &#38;c., and other contingent expenses of the State Penitentiary. And that the said sum be Subject&#8212;and the Treasurer is hereby authorized and required to pay&#8212;to the order of the Super<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />intendent of said institution so much of said appropriation as may be necessary. And that such payments be accredited to the State Account.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 20th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="461" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="43" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to change the line between the counties of Lavaca and Gon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />zales.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the line between the counties of Lavaca and Gonzales be so changed as to attach a part of Gonzales county to Lavaca county by commencing at the north-west corner of Lavaca county and running a line south-west five miles to a stake.</p>
<p>Thence due south to a point where it intersects the Lavaca county line.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 21st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act relinquishing to the counties the State tax tor the years 1856 and 1857.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That nine-tenths of the State tax hereafter to be collected, under ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />isting laws, on the assessment to be made for the years 1856 and 1857, are hereby relinquished to the respective counties where the property is situated on which said tax is assessed, to be disbursed for the benefit of said counties, at the discretion of the respective County Courts of said counties. Provided that said taxes shall be applied: first, to the erection of good and substantial public buildings,, or to the payment for the same if already erected and not paid for, and afterwards to such general purposes as may be directed by the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty Courts of the respective counties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Said tax to be assessed and collected by existing laws regulating the same, returns of the assessment rolls to be made, and one-tenth of said tax to be passed to the credit of the Free Common School Fund, and nine-tenths of said tax on property situated in counties other than that in which the assessment is made, for the benefit of said counties res<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pectively, shall be made by the Assessor and Collector to the Comptroller, at the time provided by law, and it shall be the <pb n="462" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="44" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>duty of the several Assessors and Collectors to use the forms and pursue the instructions of the Comptroller as heretofore. And the County Court shall exercise a general supervision over the Assessors and Collectors and Treasurers of their respective counties, and in case of any delinquency or defalcation of said officers, said Courts shall have power to remove or suspend said officers, and do any other thing necessary to the protection of the interests of the county and State, and the punishment of said offending officer or officers.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Assessor and Collector shall monthly pay over, to the Treasurer of the county, all monies collected under this act, and report to the County Court, at each regular meeting, the time and amounts of said payments, and submit to said court, whenever re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired, his books and accounts, and also make an annual statement at the same time he is now required to make his final settlement with the Comptroller under existing laws, and it shall be his duty to use the forms and pursue the instructions of the Comptroller, as here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tofore; provided, said Assessors and Collectors and county Treasur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ers shall collect and account for gold and silver only.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the liability of the Assessor and Collector shall be as heretofore, and as provided for in section second, and in the event of any Assessor and Collector failing or refusing to comply with the laws regulating the assessment and collection of taxes, said officer and his securities shall be prosecuted by the District Attorney of the district where such officer resides, on the bond or bonds he may have executed to the State of Texas and county for the faithful discharge of such officer&#8217;s duty, and a certified copy of such bond by the Coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty Clerk of the county where such bond is of record, shall be entitled to the same degree of credit that the original bond would be if pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />duced in Court.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. It shall be the duty of the District Attorneys of the dif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ferent districts to prosecute all delinquent tax collectors when noti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied by the County Court; that such officers, if residing within their respective districts, have failed to assess and collect the taxes in such county, in the manner provided for by law, and a statement of such officers&#8217; accounts, certified by the Court of the county shall be prima facie evidence of such officer&#8217;s delinquency, and the District Attor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ney shall prosecute the cause in the manner provided for by law, and the proceeds of such prosecution shall be paid into the county Treasury.</p>
<pb n="463" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="45" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 6. The Treasurer of the county shall report to the County Court of his county, at each regular meeting of said court, the amount of money in the Treasury, when and from whom received, and account for all monies paid out, none of which shall be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bursed except by order of the Chief Justice, attested by the County Clerk. He shall enter into bond to the county in a sum of which the County Court may consider double the probable amount of the relinquished State tax for the term of two years, in addition to the bond now required by law, and his liability shall be as heretofore.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The pay allowed the Assessor and Collector for going to, and returning from the seat of Government settling his accounts, shall be as heretofore provided by law, the same to be paid out of the county Treasury, on the certificate of the Comptroller that said As<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sessor and Collector has settled his accounts.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The Comptroller shall receive the taxes due from non<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />residents of the State, and nine-tenths of the State tax assessed on property in counties other than those in which the assessment is made, and pay the same to the Assessors and Collectors of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties where the property so paid upon is situated, for the benefit of such counties.</p>
<p>It shall be the duty of the Comptroller to ascertain upon what real estate the taxes have not been paid, and take the needful steps to enforce the payment of the amount due on such property, as pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided for in the Taxation Act, approved February 11th, 1850.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The county Treasurer shall be entitled to receive two per cent, for receiving, and the same rate for paying out monies received under this act, and no more.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That this act shall take effect, and be in full force, from and after its passage.</p>
<p>Vetoed by the Governor, and passed by a constitutional majority, August 21st, 1856.</p>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the use of the Spanish language before Justices Courts, in certain cases, and in the counties West of Guadalupe River.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be lawful in the counties West of the <pb n="464" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="46" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Guadalupe River, except the counties of Nueces, San Patricio, and Refugio, to make use of the Spanish language in all Judicial pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceedings before Justices of the Peace, when neither the Justice of the Peace nor the parties are able to write or understand the Eng<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lish language.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That in any case in which one of the parties only speats the English language, and the Justice or either party is unable to speak the English language, the cause may be removed, on motion, to the nearest Justice of the Peace speaking that language. Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided that the English language shall be used in all cases in which any one of the parties interested shall only speak the English lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 22d, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making an appropriation to pay a judgment rendered in the District Court of Galveston county, against James H. Cock, de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased, late Collector of Customs for the late Republic of Texas, in favor of Samuel Jones, surviving partner of the firm of E. P. Kolkin &#38; Co.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of six hundred and fifty dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, be and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, for the payment of the judgment alluded to in the caption of this act, and the Treasurer shall pay the same upon presentation of the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipt of the plaintiff&#8217;s Attorney.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 22d, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amendatory of, and supplemental to an act to encourage the improvement of the navigation of the rivers and other navi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gable waters of Texas, by making appropriations for the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That in the execution of the act to which this is <pb n="465" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="47" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>supplementary and amendatory, and of this act, all those bodies or water, in the vicinity of the Gulf of Mexico, locally designated as bays and lakes, shall be considered as parts of the bay through which they have their principal out-let to the Gulf, and all passages between bays, sometimes designated as Bayous, shall be considered as parts of the bays which they connect.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That not more than fifty thousand dollars shall be drawn from, the appropriation made by the act, to which this is supplemen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tary and amendatory, for the improvement of the different bays of the State, and not more than ten thousand dollars shall be drawn for the improvement of any one bay.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That each county, or any number of counties, interested in the improvement of any navigable river, bayou, lake or bay, may after general notice, and at a general meeting called for the purpose, appoint a Collector and Treasurer, and any subscription received by any Collector and Treasurer, previous to the approval of his bond by the Governor, shall be as valid and binding as if made afterwards, and the Collectors and Treasurers appointed under the act to which this is supplementary and amendatory, and under this act, shall return to the Governor before the first day of January, 1857, a list of all sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions received by them, with a statement of the amounts paid thereon, and also their bond.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That on or alter the first clay of January, 1857, the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, State Engineer and Comptroller shall examine the list of sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions returned, and if the amount of subscriptions for the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />provement of the bays shall be more than sufficient to consume the entire amount of the State appropriation for that object, they shall reduce the subscription for each of said bays in such manner as to secure the benefits of the State appropriation equitably, for the im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prnvement of said bays according to the population accommodated by the same. If the amount of subscription for the navigable rivers, bayous and lakes, shall be more than sufficient to consume the en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tire amount of the State appropriation for these objects, they shall also reduce the subscription for each of said rivers, bay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ous and lakes, according to the population accommodated by the same. Provided, that in no event shall more than twenty thousand dollars, of the State appropriation, be applied to the improvement of any streams except the Colorado, Brazos, Trinity and Sabine rivers. And provided further, that no <pb n="466" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="48" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>river, bayou or lake, which is not navigable for at least ten miles, shall be entitled to the benefits of this act or the act to which this is supplementary and amendatory.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That if the State Engineer and Superintendent shall, af<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ter surveying, exploring and laying off any river, bayou, lake or bay, find that the appropriation as designated in said several private sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions, for such navigable waters will not effect a permanent, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinuous and valuable improvement upon such navigable water, said Engineer and Superintendent shall have the power to apply said sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scriptions and State appropriation to such portions of said navigable waters as he shall be satisfied will effect the most permanent and valuable improvement thereon, and he shall notify the Governor and said Collectors and Treasurers upon what portion of said waters said appropriations will be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. Said Engineer and Superintendent shall continue in office two years, or until the election and qualification of his successor in office. And whenever any vacancy occurs in said office, by death, resignation or otherwise, or in the office of any Collector and Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer, it Shall be the duty of the Governor to fill said vacancy by ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pointment, which appointment shall continue in office until twenty days after the next regular session of the Legislature. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>23d August, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the ninth section of an act, entitled an act concern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing free persons of color, approved February 5th, 1840.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the ninth section of the above recited act is hereby amended, so that the same shall hereafter read as follows, to wit: That it shall not be lawful for any master of a vessel, or owner thereof, nor for any other person whatsoever, to bring, import, induce or aid or assist in the bringing, importing or inducing any free person of colour, within the limits of the State of Texas, directly or indirectly. And any person so offending shall be deemed guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof in the District Court, shall be fined in a <pb n="467" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="49" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>sum of not less than one hundred dollars, nor more than two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars for each offence.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of January, 1857.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 25th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Chief Justice of Tarrant County to order an election to locate the County Site of said County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Chief Justice of Tarrant County shall order an election, to be held by the qualified voters of said county, on the first Tuesday in November, 1856, to locate the county site of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That if it shall appear from the returns, that there is a majority of the qualified voters voting for any one place, within five miles of the geographical centre of said county, then the Chief Justice shall declare such place duly elected, and shall become the county site of said county; but if there should not be a majority of votes cast in the first election for any one place, then the Chief Jus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tice shall order a second election, giving twenty days notice thereof, leaving out the place receiving the smallest number of votes, and so on until an election is made by some one place receiving a ma<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />jority of all the votes cast.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That when the question is decided by a majority vote as to where the county site shall be, then it shall be the duty of all the officers of said county to remove their offices to the place elected, within six months after said location, and that all writs and process be made returnable, according to the intent and purport of this act. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 26th 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="468" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="50" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the issuance of patents upon cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain Surveys in Peter&#8217;s Colony.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized and required to issue patents upon the following surveys in Peters&#8217; colony, viz.: headlight of William Long for six hundred and forty acres. Headright of Reuben W. Reynolds for six hundred and forty acres. Headright of James Clayton for four hundred and seventy-three acres. Bounty warrant of James Clayton for six hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred and forty acres, and for three hundred and twenty acres; and that a survey for six hundred and forty acres in the name of Jacob Bailsman may be relocated and patented, all of said tracts of land having been selected and located previous to the passage of the act of 10th of February, 1852, provided this act shall in no way affect the rights of third parties, and that said certificates and the one in virtue of which the Balliman survey may be relocated, shall be found to be genuine and valid, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 25th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the translation and transfer of a portion of the Archives of Bezar County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be and he is hereby authorized to appoint some suitable and competent person or persons to arrange and trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late into English all the documents in the Spanish language now on with with the archives of Bexar county, embraced in the chrono<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />logical index list prepared by Buquor and De Bray, and transmitted to the present Legislature by the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That when so arranged and translated, all the documents herein mentioned, including both the originals and translated copies and also the originals and translations hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore made thereof, under a previous law of the State, shall be transferred from the archives of Bexar county, and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="469" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="51" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>posited in the office of the Secretary of State, subject to the disposi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec 3, That the sum of fifteen hundred dollars, or so much there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of as may be necessary, be, and the same is hereby appropriated out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to enable the Governor to carry into effect the provisions of this act. And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 25th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to the act of March 13th, 1848, entitled &#8220;an act better defining the marital rights of parties.&#8221;</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the community property of the husband and wife shall be lia<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ble for all their debts contracted during marriage, except in such cases as are specially excepted by law. And in the settlement of community estates it shall be the duty of the survivor, executor, or administrator to keep a separate and distinct account of all the com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />munity debts allowed or paid in the settlement of such estates.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That it shall not be necessary for any surviving husband to administer upon the community property of himself and his de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceased wife, but he shall have the exclusive management, control and disposition of the same after her death in the same manner as during her life subject to the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That it shall be the duty of the surviving husband at the death of his wife, if she have a surviving child or children, to file in the County Court a full, fair and complete inventory and appraise<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of all the community property of himself and his deceased wife, to be taken and recorded as in eases of administration, and to have the same force and effect in all suits between parties claiming under it. After which, without any administration or further action what<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ever in the Probate Court, he shall have the right to manage, control and dispose of said community property both real and personal, in such manner as to him may seem best for the interest of said estate, and of suing and being sued with regard to the same, in the same manner as during the life of his wife. And he <pb n="470" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="52" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>shall keep a fair and full account and statement of all exchanges, sales and other disposition of community property, and upon final partition shall account to the legal heirs of his wife for their interest in said community, and the increase and profits in the same after de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducting a reasonable commission for the management of the same. And he shall he liable to the amount of said inventory and appraise<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment at all times for the interest of said heirs in said community property.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, That should said surviving husband neglect, fail, or refuse to file said inventory in the County Court as required by the provis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ions of this act, within sixty days after the death of his deceased wife, the County Court, upon complaint made and satisfactory proof thereof by any one having an interest in said estate either in person or by next friend, may upon its own motion or the motion of any party interested, require him to do so, or otherwise grant administra<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion upon said estate, as in other cases provided by statute.</p>
<p>And if upon the filing of said inventory it shall appear to the court, that it is in any way necessary for the protection of the property be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />longing to said estate, bond and security may be required of said sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />viving husband in such amount and with such conditions as may be deemed necessary by the court for the protection of the interest of the creditors and heirs of said estate, and upon failure to execute said bond with security as required by said Court, administration may be granted upon said estate as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 5, That should any of the heirs of the deceased wife, either in person, or by next friend or guardian, represent and show to any court of competent jurisdiction that said surviving husband is wast<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing or mismanaging or is about to waste or mismanage said commu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nity property, or is about to remove it out of the State or otherwise dispose of it in such manner as to injure, or defraud the right of such heir or heirs, the husband may be required to enter into such bond and security for the proper management of such property, and with such other conditions as may be required by the Court, or the Court may appoint an administrator over the estate of the wife as in other cases provided by statute.</p>
<p>Sec. 6, That said surviving husband may as each of the surviving heirs of his deceased wife or all of them, become of lawful age, set aside and deliver to him or them, what he considers their equal and equitable share in said community property, exhibiting therewith a full and complete statement of <pb n="471" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="53" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the same for which he may require the receipt of such heir, stating the amount description and value of the property delivered, which said partition and distribution shall be binding, and final upon said heir or heirs, unless proceeding is commenced in some competent court, within two years after said distribution, by such heir to set the same aside.</p>
<p>In which case, any party interested may require a full and fair investigation into the whole of said estate, and said partition and the court entertaining jurisdiction of the same, shall have full discre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion to enter all decrees and orders to obtain and carry out a full and fair settlement and partition of said estate, with such heir or heirs as may then be entitled to receive their distributive share.</p>
<p>Sec. 7, That the surviving wife may retain the exclusive manage<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and control of the community property of herself and her deceased husband, in the same manner, and subject to the same rights, rules and regulations, as provided in the foregoing provi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions of this act, until she may marry again.&#8212;But upon a second marriage she shall cease to have such control and management of said estate, or the right to dispose of the same under the provisions of this act, and said estate shall be subject to administration, as in other cases of deceased persons estates/.</p>
<p>Sec. 8, That the husband or wife may by last will and testament give to the surviving husband or wife the power to keep his or her separate property together, until each of the several heirs shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />come of lawful age, and to manage and control the same under the provisions of this act, and such other restrictions as may be im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed by will. Provided the surviving husband or wife is the father or mother, as the case may be, of the minor heirs&#8212;and provided further that any child or heir entitled to any part of said property, shall at any time upon becoming of age, be entitled to receive his distributive portion of said estate.</p>
<p>Sec. 9, That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage, and that the provisions of all laws, in so far as they con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />flict with the provisions of this act be, and the and the same are thus far repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="472" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="54" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to provide for the improvement of the Capitol Grounds.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated for boring an Artesian Well, and otherwise improving and ornamenting the Capitol Grounds, and that the well shall be completed and in successful operation previously to the setting out of trees and shrubbery.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That the Governor and Comptroller be, and they are hereby authorized to enter into a contract with some suitable and competent person, having respect to his actual qualification for the duties imposed by this act, for the purpose of carrying out the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions and object of this act, and that the person so contracted with shall execute a bond to the State of Texas, in double the amount of this appropriation, with at least two good and sufficient securities, to be approved by the Governor and Comptroller, for the faithful performance of his duties. Provided, that in no event shall the contract so entered into exceed the amount of this appropria<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That the Governor and Comptroller shall be author<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ized to draw the sum of money hereby appropriated from the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury, to be paid pro rata as the work progresses, provided that the amount so drawn shall in no event exceed the value of the work actually done.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, That this act take effect and he in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amending an act to change the Sixth and Ninth Judicial Districts, of the State of Texas, and to define the time of hold<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ings Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fourth section of the above recited act shall hereafter read as follows: That the District Courts of the ninth Judicial District shall be held as follows, viz: In the <pb n="473" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="55" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county of Houston on the first Monday of March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; In the county of Cherokee on the second Mondays after the first Monday in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks; In the county of Anderson on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber, and may continue in session three weeks; In the county of Hen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />derson on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Kaufman on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Van Zandt on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; In the county of Smith on the twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the busi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ness is disposed of.</p>
<p>And that this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>26th August, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act to create the County of Comanche.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an act to create the county of Comanche, approved January 25th, 1856, be amended so as to read thus: begin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning on the N. W. boundary of said county, five miles from the N. E. corner, thence It. 30&#176; W. ten miles to a point, thence S. 60&#176; W. to a point, twenty-five miles, thence S. 30&#176; E. ten miles to what was heretofore the N. W. corner of Comanche county, and that this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="474" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="56" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to repeal an act donating to actual settlers on vacant public domain 160 acres of Land.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act donating to actual settlers on vacant public domain one hundred and sixty acres of land, approved February 13th, A. D. 1854, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the location, sale and settlement of the Mississippi and Pacific Railroad Reserve.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That what is known as the Mississippi and Pacific Railroad Land Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />serve, shall, from and after the first day of January, A. D. 1857, be subject to location and sale as hereinafter prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all persons who are now settled upon any portion of the said reserve belonging to the State, shall pay fifty cents per acre for his or her claim not to exceed one hundred and sixty acres, and the said parties are hereby required to have their lands surveyed by the District or County Surveyor, and the field notes returned to the General Land Office by the 1st day of January, A. D. 1858, provided that all persons now resident on the said reserve shall, on or before the 1st day of January, A. D. 1858, pay over to the Commissioner of the General Land Office the said amount of fifty cents per acre, for the amount of their claims. And the Commissioner is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to patent the surveys authorized by this section as other sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any person holding a genuine land certificate, boun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty land warrant, or other headright land certificates, or railroad cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificates shall, after the 1st day of March, 1857, have the right to lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate the same within the reserve alluded to in this act, as on any oth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er public domain of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Commissioner of the General Land Of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="475" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="57" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>fice is hereby required after the 1st day of March, 1857, upon the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quest of any party, to issue land scrip at fifty cents per acre, to be paid in gold or silver before the delivery of the same; the scrip to be issued in the name of the party applying; and the scrip so issued may be located within the said reserve and upon any vacant and unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated land, but not on any previously titled lands, and when so lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated and surveyed shall be patented as other surveys upon the pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic domain of the State; provided that all surveys recognized by this act shall be in a square, should surveys made before the passage of the act incorporating the Mississippi and Pacific Railroad admit of it.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all monies received by the Commissioner of the General Land Office, under the provisions of this act, shall be paid over monthly to the State Treasurer, and by him placed to the credit of the special school fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That all laws and parts of laws, so fax as they conflict with the provisions of this act, be and the same are hereby repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the third section of an act entitled An Act for the investment of the special school fund, in the bonds of Railroad Companies incorporated by the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section 3d of the above entitled act shall be so amended as to read as follows:</p>
<p>Said Board of Commissioners is hereby authorized to invest said funds by loaning to any such company, which has been heretofore chartered for the purpose of building a railroad in the State, the sum of six thousand dollars per mile, for each and every mile of rail<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />road constructed as hereinafter provided. Said loans to be secured by the bonds of such company for said principal and interest, made and executed to the State of Texas, in the corporate name of such company, signed by the President and countersigned by the Secreta<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ry or Treasurer, under the seal of such company: which bonds shall constitute a lien upon the road and charter rights of such company, including the road-bed, right of way, grading, bridges, iron <pb n="476" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="58" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>rails, equipments, and masonry, and upon all the stock subscribed for in said companies, all the depots and depot stations, and all the property owned by such company, as necessary for its business. And the State of Texas, upon the execution of said bonds, and by the vir<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tue of the same, shall be invested with said lien or mortgage for the payment of said bonds and the interest thereon, as the same becomes due, without the necessity of any deed, special contract or act of reg<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />istration.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to establish an Institution for the education of the Deaf and Dumb.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of ten thousand dollars be, and the same is hereby appropriated and set apart for the establishment of an Institution for the education of the Deaf and Dumb of Texas, which shall be located at the city of Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. A Board of five Trustees shall be appointed by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, whose duty it shall be to administer the funds of said Institu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and provide for its going into operation as soon as practicable, by renting a suitable building and appointing such Superintendent and other officers as may be required for the successful management of said Institution.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said sum of ten thousand dollars shall be paid on the order of said Trustees, approved and countersigned by the Gov<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ernor, out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated, as the actual current expenses of maintaining the Institution shall accrue. Provided that not more than five thousand dollars shall be expended in any one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. Said Trustees shall be, and they are hereby required to make full and accurate annual reports to the Governor of the State, showing the condition and progress of the Institution, with a full ex<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />hibit of all expenditures, and it shall be the duty of the Governor to lay the same before the Legislature.</p>
<pb n="477" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="59" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect and be in force from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act supplementary to an act authorizing the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents on certificates issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Robertson county, under certain restrictions, approved Feb. 5th, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue patents upon all unconditional certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cates issued by the Board of Land Commissioners of Robertson county, under the same conditions and restrictions as is contem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plated by the act to which this is a supplement; provided, that noth<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing in this act shall be so construed as to apply to any other class of certificates than those expressly mentioned in this act, and that this act take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 26th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to quiet Land Titles.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the headrigbts, augmentations and special grants made to the colonists, in the colonies of Austin and DeWitt, are hereby ratified and confirmed, and all conditions attached to the same are hereby released; provided, that this section shall extend only to titles issued previous to the 13th day of November, A. D. 1835.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall take effect, and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="478" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="60" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the erection and support of a Lunatic Asylum.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of fifty thousand Dollars of the United States bonds, and the interest accruing thereon, now in the Treasury, be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated, set apart and applied, under the immediate direction of the Governor, Comptroller and Treasurer, in the erection of a suitable building for a Lunatic Asylum, which building shall be so constructed that it shall be susceptible of any additions that may be hereafter required.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized and required to appoint three Commissioners, whose duty it shall be to select a proper site for the Asylum, and secure by donation or pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase not less than fifty nor more than one hundred acres of land, which shall not cost the State more than five dollars per acre. The commissioners shall report their proceedings to the Governor within thirty days after their appointment, together with the deed for the land donated or purchased, which deed shall be duly recorded in the proper office, and filed in the office of the Secretary of State. The commissioners shall receive five dollars per day, while in actual service.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. The Governor, upon receiving the report of the Commis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sioners, shall, with the Comptroller and Treasurer, let out the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tract or contracts for the building of the Asylum under similar re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strictions and liabilities (so far as the same may be applicable) which were in force upon said officers, in the erection of the Treasury buildings and Governor&#8217;s mansion, and the same requirements which were made of the contractors in every respect, so far as the same may he applicable, shall be made from those who contract to do the work necessary in the construction of the Lunatic Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That so soon as he may deem it necessary, the Governor shall appoint a suitable Superintendant, who shall be a skilful Physician, and experienced in the treatment of Lunatics, and such other assistants, male and female, as may be required to carry out the objects of this act; the Superin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tendant shall have a salary of two thousand dollars annually; he shall report to the Governor semi-annually all the expen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ses of the Asylum, with such other information as may show <pb n="479" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="61" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>the condition of the Asylum and its inmates. The sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, of the United States bonds, now in the Treasury and the accruing interest thereon, is hereby set apart for the expenses of said Asylum until the meeting of the next Legislature.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 28, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the first section of an act entitled an act to amend the second and seventh section of an act entitled an act to or<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ganize the Supreme Court of the State of Texas&#8212;approved the 12th of May, 1846&#8212;approved November 30th, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of an act entitled an act to amend the second and seventh sections of an act entitled an act to organize the Supreme Court of the State of Texas, approved 12th of May, 1846, and approved November 30th, 1850, is hereby amended so that the same shall hereafter read as follows, to wit:</p>
<p>That the Supreme Court shall hold its sessions once in every year, at the city of Austin, in the county of Travis; once in every year, at the city of Galveston, in the county of Galveston; and once in every year at the town of Tyler, in the county of Smith, that the causes decided in the District Courts of the second, third, fourth, eleventh, thirteenth, sixteenth, seventeenth and eighteenth Judicial Districts, and the counties of Gonzales and Lavaca, in the tenth dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict when taken up by appeal or otherwise, shall be returnable to the Supreme Court, sitting at the city of Austin. That the causes decided in the District Courts of the first, seventh, twelfth, four<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teenth, fifteenth and tenth Judicial districts, with the exception of the counties of Gonzales and Lavaca, shall be returnable to the Supreme Court, holding its session at the city of Galves<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton. That the causes decided in the District Courts of the fifth, sixth, eighth and ninth Judicial Districts shall be return<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able to the Supreme Court, holding its session at the town of Tyler, in the county of Smith, provided that the parties, or their attorneys may, on filing an agreement for that purpose with the clerk of any District Court in either of the Judicial <pb n="480" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="62" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Districts, direct the records, accompanied by a certified copy of the agreement to be transmitted to the Supreme Court, holding its ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sions either in the city of Austin, the city of Galveston or at the town of Tyler; that the Supreme Court hold its session at the city of Austin on the third Monday in October of each and every year, and may continue in session nine weeks, or until the business before the Court is disposed of; at the city of Galveston on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />day in January, and may continue in session ten weeks, unless the business be sooner disposed of; at the town of Tyler on the first Monday in April, and may continue in session until the first day of July, unless the business before the Court is sooner disposed of.</p>
<p>And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 28, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the County of Jack.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory embraced within the following limits, to wit:</p>
<p>Beginning at the South-West corner of the county of Wise, thence west to the South-East corner of the county of Young, thence north thirty miles, thence east of the North-West comer of the county of Wise, thence south to the place of beginning, shall comprise and constitute the county of Jack.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be, and is hereby made the duty of Jas. W. Terry, E. Coker and Rad Ellis, to organize the said county of Jack, on the third Monday in October next, by ordering an election to be held at such places as they may designate, giving at least fif<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen days notice of such election, for all county officers; which said election shall be conducted in all other respects according to the laws regulating county elections, where the same does not conflict with the provisions and intentions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Commissioners shall, at the same time of ordering an election for county officers, order an election for the purpose of locating the seat of justice of said county, and it shall be the duty of said commissioners to select two or more suitable places within five miles of the centre of said <pb n="481" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="63" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>county, to be run for the seat of justice of said county. The re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns of said election to be made to said commissioners, at such time and place as they may designate, and if either of said places shall receive a majority of all the votes east, the same shall be the seat of justice of said county, and known as Mesquiteville; but if neither of the places run, shall receive a majority of all the votes cast, then said commissioners shall select the two places having received the highest number of votes, and order another election, and shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed as in the first, and the place receiving the highest number of votes, in the second election, shall be the County seat of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That until the seat of justice of said county shall have been located, the business to be transacted by the courts, shall be at the house of E. Coker; said commissioners, or either of them, are hereby authorized to administer the oaths of office to any officer elected under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That if said place so selected shall fall upon vacant and unappropriated land, the State of Texas hereby relinquishes the same to said county, to the amount of three hundred and twenty acres, and upon the presentation of the field notes duly made out and recorded by the District surveyor of Denton Land District, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized to issue a patent to and in the name of Jack county, for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That said commissioners or a majority of them shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceed to lay off said town into lots, and after giving notice of the same at least twenty days, to sell the same at public auction to the highest bidder either for cash or on time, as they may deem most advisable for the interest of said county, and after making said sales, shall proceed to make titles for the same in the name of said county, and if sold on time, take mortgages on the property sold to secure the payment of the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That if said site so selected stall fall upon lands now appropriated, then and in that case, said commissioners shall be, and they are hereby authorized to procure the same to the amount of one hundred acres, either by purchase or do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation; that the proceeds of the sales of said lots shall be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated to the building of a Court House and jail, in said town, provided that so soon as said proceeds or any part there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />of are collected, they shall be paid over to the Treasurer of <pb n="482" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="64" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>said county, subject to the order of the County court of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That said commissioners, shall receive each the amount of per diem pay that is now allowed to county commissioners, and no more, and that from and after the first sale of said lots, the duties of said commissioners shall cease, and they shall pay over to said Treasurer of said county all the proceeds of said sales, and from and after that time the business shall be transacted by the County Court of said county. And that this act take effect and be in force im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled &#8220;An Act to change the sixth and ninth Judicial Districts of the State of Texas, and to define the time of holding Courts therein,&#8221; approved 18th December, 1855.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the fourth section of the above entitled act, be, and the same is hereby amended, so as to read as follows:</p>
<p>That the District Courts of the ninth Judicial District, shall be held as follows, viz: In the county of Houston, on the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days of every March and September, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Cherokee, on the second Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session four weeks; In the county of Anderson, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Henderson, on the ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Kaufman, on the tenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Van Zandt on the eleventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Smith, on the fourteenth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That all writs and process issued from the District Court, in the county of Smith, and made returnable on the <pb n="483" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="65" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>twelfth Monday after the first Monday in September, 1856. Shall be returnable to said court on the fourteenth Monday after the first Monday in September 1856; and shall be as valid as if the same had been returned to said court on the twelfth Monday after the first Monday in September, and all causes triable in said court, at the term mentioned in the section of the above entitled act, amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed by this act shall be triable at the term of said court, specified in this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act take effect from and after it passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing a sale of a portion of the United States Bonds, now in the Treasury of the State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of the State is hereby authorized and required to dispose, at public sale, of such an amount of the United States Bonds, now in the Treasury, to the credit of the State ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count, as may be required from time to time, to meet the expenses of Government, and such appropriations as may be called for dur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing the years 1856 and 1857.</p>
<p>Sec. 2d. That the Comptroller shall be governed in the sale or Sales of said Bonds, by the stipulations and regulations of &#8220;An Act providing for the sale of one million of the Bonds of the United States, being a part of the indemnity received for the sale of a por<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion of the north-western Territory of the State of Texas,&#8221; approv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed February 16th, 1852; and such sales may be had at such times and in such amounts, of not less than fifty thousand dollars at a time, as the wants of the Treasury may require.</p>
<p>Sec. 3rd. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 28th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the county of Palo Pinto.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all the territory lying within the following <pb n="484" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="66" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>limits: beginning on the south-west corner of Parker county; thence north with said line of Parker county, 30 miles to the north<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />west corner of said county; thence west 30 miles, to a corner; thence south to a point which is north 30&#176; west, from the west corner of Erath county; thence in a direct line to the west corner of Erath county; thence following the boundaries of Erath and Parker coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, to the beginning, shall constitute a new county by the name of Palo Pinto.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief-Justice of Bosque county shall, as soon as practicable, order an election to be held in Palo Pinto county, for the purpose of electing a Chief-Justice, County Commissioners, Sheriff, Clerk of the District Court and County Court, and all other county officers, and shall have power to qualify the Chief-Justice so elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 3rd. That the Chief-Justice of Palo Pinto county, after being qualified, as provided for by the previous section, shall have power to qualify the other county officers according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 4th. That it shall be the duty of the Chief-Justice and County Commissioners of Palo Pinto county, when qualified, to select the county seat of said county, within five miles of the centre of said county; to lay off the county town, to designate the lots and land reserved for the use of the county, and to cause such buildings to be erected as are necessary for the use of said county, and any other business for the said county, not in conflict with the general laws.</p>
<p>Sec. 5th. That said county site shall be called Golconda, and that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the county of Brown, (&#8220;in honor of Captain Henry S. Brown, now deceased, one of the early Pioneers of Texas.&#8221;)</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of Territory contained within the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing limits, shall be created into a new county to be called Brown; beginning at the mouth of Pecan Bayou; thence N. 30&#176; E. 14 miles to the south-west boundary of Comanche county; thence with said boundary N. 30&#176; W. 38&#188; <pb n="485" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="67" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>miles; thence south 60 W. to Mute-water creek; thence down with the meanders of said creek, to its mouth; thence down the Colo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rado to the beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief-Justice of Lampasas county shall, as soon as practicable, order an election for county officers of Brown county, which election shall be governed in other respects, by the laws regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lating elections; and said Chief-Justice shall have power to qualify said officers when elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Chief-Justice of Brown county, when so quali<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied, shall have power to qualify the other officers of Brown county.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the County Court of Brown County, shall, as soon as practicable, after being duly qualified, proceed to locate the county seat of said county, by selecting two or more eligible seats within five miles of the centre of said county, hawing proper respect for any do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nation of land that may be made for that purpose; and when so selected, the Chief-Justice of Brown county shall order an election for a county seat, according to the laws regulating elections, and the place receiving a majority of all the votes cast, shall be declared the county seat of said county, and if from any cause a selection shall not be made at the first election, the Chief-Justice shall order an<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />other election in the same manner, until a selection shall be made by a majority of the voters.</p>
<p>See. 5. That the County Court of Brown county shall have power to purchase, if necessary, land not exceeding three hundred and twenty acres, for the use of said county, and shall lay off the same or any other place obtained for that purpose, into lots for a town, and after selecting and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary, for a Court House, Jail, Clerk&#8217;s office, school house, churches and burying ground, they shall sell the remainder or so much thereof as shall be necessary, at public sale, at such time and on such terms as said Court shall think best, and apply the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceeds to the erection of the public buildings necessary for the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the County Court of Brown county shall have power to name the county seat of said county, and do all other acts requi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />site to conclude the location of said county seat, and erection of said public buildings.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="486" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="68" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act defining the time of holding the District Courts in the twelfth Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the District Courts for the counties composing the twelfth Judicial District, shall, from and after the first day of Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary, A. D. eighteen hundred and fifty seven, be begun and holden as follows: In the county of Cameron, on the first Mondays in March and September of every year, and may continue in session four weeks; in the county of Hidalgo, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September of every year, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session two weeks; in the county of Starr, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September of every year, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Webb, on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember of every year, and may continue in session two weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Fall term of the District Courts for the year A. D. 1856, shall be begun and holden in said counties as hereto<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore required by law, with the exception of the District Court for the county of Cameron, in which county said Fall term shall com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mence on the eighth Mondays after the first Mondays in September, and may continue in session four weeks.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process that have been or may hereafter be issued from any of the District Courts of the Twelfth Judicial District, shall be considered as returnable to the terms as estab<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lished by this act, and shall have the same force and effect as if the same had originally been so returnable.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That all laws or parts of laws in conflict with the pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />visions of this act, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="487" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="69" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to create the county of McCulloch, (in honor of Captain Ben. McCulloch.)</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all that portion of territory contained within the fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowing limits, shall be created into a new county to be called Mc<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />Culloch: beginning at the upper Corner of San Saba county, on the west or south bank of the Colorado river; thence south along the west boundary of San Saba county, to a point thirty-five miles from the starting point; thence west thirty miles, to a corner; thence north to the Colorado river; thence down said river to the begin<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Chief-Justice of San Saba county shall, as soon as practicable, order an election for county officers of McCulloch county, which election shall be governed in other respects, by the laws regulating elections; and said Chief-Justice shall have power to qualify the said officers when elected.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That the Chief-Justice of McCulloch county, when so qualified, shall have poorer to qualify the other officers of McCul<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />loch county. i</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the County Court of McCulloch county, shall, as soon as practicable, after being duly qualified, proceed to locate the county seat of said county by selecting two or more eligible seats within five miles of the centre of said county, having proper respect for any donation of laud that may be made for that purpose, and when so selected, the Chief-Justice of McCulloch county shall order an election for a county seat, according to the laws regulating elec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions, and the place receiving a majority of all the votes cast, shall be declared the county seat of said county, and if from any cause a selection shall not be made at the first election, the Chief-Justice shall order likewise, until such such selection shall be made by a majority of the voters.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the County Court of McCulloch county shall have power to purchase, if necessary, land not exceeding 320 acres, for the use of the said county, and shall lay off the same or any other place obtained for that purpose, into lots for a town, and after selecting and setting apart such suitable lots as may be necessary for a Court-house, Jail, Clerk&#8217;s office, School houses, Churches, and burying ground, they shall pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="488" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="70" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ceed to sell the remainder or so much thereof as they may deem necessary, at public auction, at such times and on such terms as said Court shall think best, and apply the proceeds to the erection of public buildings, necessary for the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the County Court of McCulloch county shall have the power to name the county seat of said county, and all the acts to do and perform, necessary to conclude the location of the county seat, and the erection of the necessary public buildings.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 27th 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to require the Comptroller to perform the duties required of the Auditor and Comptroller, under the provisions of an act entitled An Act relating to lost Certificates of Public Debt, of the late Republic of Texas, approved February 7th, 1853.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Comptroller of Public Accounts be, and he is here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />by authorized and required to perform all the duties required of the Auditor and Comptroller, under the provisions of an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled &#8220;An Act relating to lost certificates of Public Debt of the late Republic of Texas,&#8221; approved February 7th, 1853. And he shall also issue warrants on all claims which have passed the Legislature since the first of January, 1856.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Thai this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 29th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend an act entitled &#8220;An Act to define the times of holding the several District Courts of the Fifth Judicial District,&#8221; approved February 13th, 1854.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the first section of the act entitled &#8220;An Act to define the times of holding the District Courts in the Fifth <pb n="489" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="71" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>Judicial District,&#8220; shall be so amended as to read hereafter as fol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lows:&#8212;ect. 1. That the District Courts of the Fifth Judicial Dis-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> trict of the State of &#39;exas, shall be held in the several Counties composing said District, at. he times hereinafter specified, to wit: In the county of Nacogdoches, on the first Mondays in February and August in each year, and may continue in session three weeks; in the county of Angelina, on the third Mondays after the first Mon-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> days in February and August in each year, and may continue in ses-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> sion one week; in the county of Jasper, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in February an&#39; August in each year, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Newton, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August in each year, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Sabine, on the seventh Mondays after the first &#39;ondays in February and August in each year, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Shelby, on &#39;he twelfth Mondays after the first Mondays in February and August in each year, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of San Augustine, on the fourteenth Mon-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> days afteTrthe first Mondays in February and August in each year, and may continue in session until the &#8217;usiness of the Court is dis-<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /> posed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act shall be in force and effect from the 1st January, 1857.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August the 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the disposition and sale of the University Lands.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of the several county and district Surveyors, in whose county or district any part of the fifty leagues appropriated by the fourth section of an act en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled An Act appropriating certain lands for the establishment of a general system of education, approved 26th of January, 1839, may be situated, to proceed as soon as practicable after the passage of this act, and divide the same into tracts of one hundred and sixty acres each. And in dividing any tract, if there shall be any fractional balance of less than one hundred <pb n="490" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="72" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and sixty acres, the same shall be attached to the adjoining tract. The Survey or shall cause the lines of each tract, when the same are in the timber, to be plainly marked, and shall establish the corners of each tract with good and substantial materials. He shall make a map of said work and field notes, in which each tract shall be num<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bered and the quantity thereof stated; the lines and corners shall he fully described; all streams of water shall be stated with their course; and the point or points at which they may intersect any line; and the quantity of timber, and prairie land, and the character of the same in each tract shall be stated as near as the same can be esti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />mated; provided that dividing said lands into one hundred and six<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty acre tracts, shall consist in running section lines one mile apart, and establishing corners at the end of every half mile.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. When said map and field notes shall be completed, in accordance with the provisions of the preceding section, the Survey<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />or shall record the same in a bound book to be kept in his office for that purpose, and return the original to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who, upon the receipt of the same, shall notify the Governor.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. After said map and field notes shall have been made and returned to the General Land Office, as herein before provided for, it shall be the duty of the Governor to cause each alternate section of six hundred and forty acres to be sold in lots of one hundred and sixty acres each, at public auction to the highest bidder, at the county seat of the county in which the same may be situated; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided such sale and the terms thereof shall first have been adver<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tised for sixty days in two newspapers published nearest to the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty in which the land is situated; also, in at least three public places in said county; and in at least one paper at the seat of Govern<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment; Provided also that such lands shall not be sold for a less price than three dollars an acre.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the terms of such sale be a credit of twenty years, bearing interest at the rate of eight per cent, per annum, the purchaser to pay to the Treasurer of the State, at the end of each year, after the day of sale, the interest due on the pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chase money and one-twentieth part of the original purchase money. The purchaser to give bond with two or more good securities, for the amount of the purchase money and interest thereon, after which he shall receive, from the person making the sale, a certificate of his purchase, and the amount and <pb n="491" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="73" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>terms thereof, and whenever he shall have fully paid the principal and interest of his purchase, the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall issue to him and his heirs or assigns, a patent; Provided that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to prevent any pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />chaser, his heirs, or assigns of such lands, from paying at any time he may desire the whole amount of the purchase money and inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />est, and so doing he shall receive a patent for the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. As often as any purchaser of said lands shall fail to pay the amount of interest, and instalment of his purchase, when the same is due, the Governor shall cause the same to be sold again, after thirty days&#8217; notice, by public auction, to the highest bidder, at the county seat of the county where the land is situated, the terms of such sale shall be that the purchaser shall pay in cash the amount then due on the land, and the costs of the sale, and for the residue of the purchase money he shall have the same number of years as there remain to run of the original credit, interest at eight per cent. to be paid thereon annually, and the principal to be paid at equal annual instalments; the purchaser to give a like bond and receive a like certificate as at original sales.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. If, at the re-sale of any tract of said land, it shall fail to bring an amount sufficient to pay the principal and interest ow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing thereon, and the costs of such re-sale, it shall be the duty of the Governor to cause suit to be brought against the obligees (obligors) in the bond of the original purchaser for such deficiency, and if it shall bring any more than the principal and interest thereon, and the costs of the re-sale, the excess shall belong to the parity whose property is so sold. At any such re-sale the Governor may, if he thinks it necessary for the protection of the rights of the (State, au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorize the land to be brought in for the State, to be held and dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of for the benefit of the University fund.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Governor may appoint one or more agents, from term to term, to conduct the sales herein authorized to be made, and all such agents shall give bond with two or more good securi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, in such amount as the Governor may direct, conditioned for the faithful discharge of their duties; and every such agent shall be al<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lowed the sum of five dollars for each and every day he may be ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tually employed in discharging the duties of his appointment.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. The proceeds of the sale of all such lands shall <pb n="492" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="74" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>constitute a University fund to be hereafter appropriated by the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. The alternate sections not herein directed to be sold shall be reserved from sale until hereafter directed by the Legislature.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The county or district Surveyors shall be allowed for all duties required of them by this act, three dollars per mile, for each mile actually run, but they shall in no case be allowed pay for the same line more than once, and said compensation shall be paid out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. It shall be the duty of the Governor to cause to be lo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated, and surveyed, an amount of land sufficient with that already located and surveyed, to make up the fifty leagues of University lands, appropriated by said act of 26th of January, 1839, in such tracts as he may think it advisable, at a cost not exceeding the regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lar fees of surveying, which shall be paid out of any money in the Treasury, not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 12. Each, settler upon any of said tracts of land offered for sale, shall have the right to take the tract upon which his improve<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ments, or the greater part thereof, shall be situated, at the highest and best bid that may be offered for the same. Provided that such bid shall not be less than three dollars per acre.</p>
<p>Sec. 13. That parties purchasing under the provisions of this act, shall have the right to sell the land purchased by him or her, under the provisions of this act, at any time, but the land so sold shall in all eases be held liable for the principal and interest unpaid under any sale in favor of the State, and a first lien or mortgage is hereby declared to exist in favor of the State, as a security for the payment of principal and interest to all lands sold as above pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act prescribing the manner of entering Land Certificates or Scrip, and to prohibit the lifting and floating the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter each county and district Surveyor in the <pb n="493" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="75" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>State, shall keep in his office a well bound book as a register of entries, in which he shall register entries or applications for land in his county or district. He shall also, before registering an entry or application, require the applicant to file his land certificate or scrip, or other legal evidence of title to land, together with a written entry or application particularly describing the claim to be surveyed, the date of the entry or application, and the land applied for in his of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fice, which he shall not allow to be taken from thence, until the same is returned, together with the field notes, to the General Land Office; but the survey shall be made by a copy of the entry, and strictly in accordance with the same; Provided, that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to prevent holders of certificates or scrip from having the same surveyed without entry. But such survey shall not have a preference, or give any right over a location or entry of the same land previously made in the proper office.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall not be lawful for such surveyor to allow the holder of any land certificate or scrip, or other legal evidence of title to land to lift or float the same after entry, location, file or survey, when the same is not made upon land previously appropriated. But when a conflict of entries, files, locations or sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys occur, upon a proper showing of the facts, which may be by the certificate of one of his deputies or from his own knowledge, he shall allow the party having his entry, file, location, or survey of sub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sequent date to lift so much thereof as shall be affected by such conflict.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That whenever an entry is made by virtue of a genuine certificate, upon any land which appears to be appropriated, deeded or patented, by the books of the proper Surveyor&#8217;s office, or records of the County Court or General Land Office, the party making such entry shall abide by the same. And in the event that judgment final shall be rendered against the right of the party making such entry to hold such land, he shall not have the right to lift or re-enter said certificate. But the same shall be forfeited, and so declared to be by the judgment of the Court. Provided, that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to effect entries or location heretofore made.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="494" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="76" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Ast seting aside and appropriating land for the benefit of Asylums.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That one hundred thousand acres of land be, and the same is hereby set apart for the benefit of a Lunatic Asylum, and a like amount of land fox the benefit of a Deaf and Dumb and Blind and Orphan Asylum.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor shall employ a competent person to locate and survey the same, from any of the vacant and unappro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated domain of the State; and the sum of ten thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, is hereby appropriated out of the Treasury to carry into effect the provisions of this act. And that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act fixing the compensation for saving Cotton found in any of the Waiters of this State, or on the Coast thereof, in the Gulf of Mexico.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be the duty of persons taking up Cotton afloat, abandoned in rivers, or in the waters of the Gulf of Mexico, on the coast of this State, or in the bays or bayous thereof, to place the same in a secure place out of the weather, and give early notice by advertisement or by other means at the Port to which said cotton was destined, if within this State, and if without the limits of the State, or its destination be unknown to the finder, then at the nearest port of entry in this State to the locality where it may be taken up, of the finding of the same, giving a description of the marks or brands on said cotton, together with the place of finding, and the name of the finder.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, It shall be the dirty of the person finding, or other per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sons having said cotton in his or their possession, to deliver the same to the owner, insurer, or consignee thereof on demand upon being paid the expenses of advertisement, and five dollars upon each bale so saved and delivered up.</p>
<pb n="495" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="77" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3, If no owner, insurer or consignee of the cotton appear within three months after the time of such advertisement, the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son finding shall cause the same to be sold at auction by a legal wreck-master of the county in which said cotton is deposited, to the best bidder therefor; and the said wreck-master shall deduct from the proceeds of said sale, five per cent upon the dollar upon the amount thereof, for his fees and trouble; and shall also pay the ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cessary expenses attending the storage, advertising and sale of said cotton, and to the finder the salvage of five dollars for each bale as aforesaid, the remainder he shall hold intrust for the benefit of owner or others concerned. If, at the expiration of one year there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after no legal claimant appears therefor; said proceeds shall by said wreck-master be paid over to the treasurer of the county in which the sale took place, and said county Treasurer shall immediately pay the same over to the Treasurer of the State, who shall pay the same over to the person entitled thereto on proof being made of the right of the claimant in the manner provided for the recovery of money paid into the Treasury of the State by executors or adminis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trators of estates, whenever no heirs, devisees or legatees of the es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tate appear to claim the fund of the estate on the final settlement thereof.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, In case there shall be no wreck-master in the county in which the cotton is deposited, then it shall be the duty of the County Clerk of the county to perform all the duties required of wreck-masters by this act, and such clerks shall be entitled to receive the same compensation for his services as is allowed to wreck-masters under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. Any person finding a bale or bales of cotton afloat or lodged by the water on the banks of any river, bay, or bayou, or on the beach of the Gulf within this State, who shall secrete the same, or appropriate the same to his own use, or who shall refuse to deliver up the same when required as aforesaid, or who shall having found any cotton afloat without the limits of this State, bring the same into this State, and not comply with the requirements of this act, as in case the same had been found within the State, shall be liable to fine or imprisonment or both, in the discretion of the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Court for the county in which the said cotton may be found, or stored, in any sum not exceeding five hundred dollars, and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment not exceeding one year.</p>
<p>Sec. 6, Upon affidavit being made before any Justice of the Peace that the affiant has good reason to believe, and <pb n="496" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="78" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>does believe that certain cotton within his county has been so found, or having been found without the same has been brought therein, and that -a reasonable time has elapsed, and that the finder has ne<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />glected to comply with the requisitions of this act, it shall be the duty of such Justice of the Peace to issue his warrant and cause said cotton or its proceeds, to be seized by a legal officer, and deliver to the wreck-master of said county, to be disposed of according to the provisions of this act.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act providing for the payment of the Companies of mounted Volunteers, Commanded by Captains William Tom, Jr., Levi Inglish and William G. Tobin, organized for the temporary pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tection of the Western Frontier of Texas.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the sum of one thousand seven hundred and two dollars and sixty-four cents, be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of Captain Tom&#8217;s Company, for one month, from the eighteenth day of October, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, to the eighteenth day of November, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, which company consist of one Captain, one First and one Second Lieuten<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ant, four Sergeants, four Corporals, and forty-four privates.</p>
<p>And that the sum of four hundred and eight dollars and ninety-seven cents be paid to E. Jones, Chairman of the committee of vigil<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance of San Antonio, to reimburse the citizens of that place, for money furnished by them to purchase supplies for said company.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That the sum of one thousand four hundred and eighty-three dollars and thirty-nine cents, be and the same is hereby appro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />priated for the payment of Captain Levi Inglish&#8217;s Company, for one month, which is to cover the whole time for which he claims in his roll, dating the discharge on the thirteenth of November, eight<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />een hundred and fifty-five, which company consists of one first and one second lieutenant, three sergeants, three Corporals, and forty-two privates, and that the sum of three hundred and sixty dollars be paid to the non-commissioned officers and privates for their forage and subsistence.</p>
<pb n="497" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="79" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3, That the sum of seven hundred and fifty-five dollars and sixty-seven cents, be, and the same is hereby appropriated for the payment of Capt. W. G. Tobin&#8217;s company for one month, ending on the fifteenth day of November, eighteen hundred and fifty-five, which company consists of one second lieutenant, two sergeants, two corporals and twenty-one privates, and that the sum of one hundred, and eighty-seven dollars and fifty cents be paid to the non-commissioned officers and privates for their forage and subsistence.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, That the Governor be authorized and required to appoint some suitable person to pay the companies of Captain Tom, Cap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tain English and Captain Tobin, as well as the amount to be paid E. Jones, whose duty it shall be to make payment at three places. One at Seguin, one at San Antonio and one at Peter Tumlinson&#8217;s on the Atascosa, at such times as the Governor may direct, and that be shall give due notice of the times and places of payment, by ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vertising in one paper at San Antonio, and one paper at Seguin for twenty days before the payments are to be made; and said payments, to be made to the officers, non-commissioned officers and privates, shall be made strictly in accordance with the regulations of the pay department of the United States, and that said paymaster so appointed by the Governor, shall be required to give bond for double the amount of this appropriation, with security to be ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved by the Governor, for the faithful performance of his duty under the provisions of this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 5, That one hundred dollars be allowed, and paid to the paymaster, provided for in the fourth section of this act as compen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sation in full, for his services in making said payment with all other expenses and labors incident to the same, in any manner whatever.</p>
<p>Sec. 6, That the Treasurer of this State is hereby authorized, and required to pay the sum of four thousand nine hundred and ninety-eight dollars and twenty-seven cents, over to the paymaster appointed by the Governor out of any money in the treasury not otherwise appropriated, upon the presentation of the order of the Governor therefor under the seal of the State&#8212;and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="498" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="80" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CXLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of certain Pre-emption Settlers within the Houston Land District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Whereas, The Book of Records of Pre-emption Claims for the Hous<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ton Land District, including the counties of Houston, Trinity, and part of the county of Henderson, has been lost or destroyed, by which it is placed out of the power of many bona fide pre-emp<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion settlers within said district to obtain their patents. There<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore,</p>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all persons who settled upon the public domain within said district as a pre-emptor and had his land surveyed by the sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyor of said district, may make oath before some officer having a seal. That the land he claims as a pre-emptor was actually sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veyed by a surveyor of said district, together with the date of said survey as near as he can in accordance with the laws in force, at the date thereof, and prove the same facts by one or more witnesses, and may have his said claim re-surveyed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That said re-survey shall relate back to the date of said original survey and pre-emption location.</p>
<p>Sec. 3, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office shall issue patents to said claimants for the amount of land they may be entitled to, upon the applicant making the proof hereinbefore required in addition to the proof now required by law to be made.</p>
<p>Sec. 4, That in ease the original settler may be dead, his heirs or legal representatives may make the proof herein required of the settlement and survey.</p>
<p>Sec. 5, That said pre-emption settlers shall have the further time of eight months from the passage of this act, to return their field notes to the General Land Office, and shall in all respects be entitled to the benefits of the pre-emption laws under Which they settled, and also those in force in this State, provided that nothing in this act shall be so construed as to legalize the settlement of sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veys of patents within the reserve known as the Mississippi and Pa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cific Railroad reserve, made after the twenty-first of December, eigh<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />teen hundred and fifty-three. And that this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="499" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="81" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CL.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act requiring the return of Unconditional Certificates to the General Land Office.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That all owners or holders who have conditional certificates now located, or surveys, upon lands shall return to the General Land Office the unconditional certificates, together with the field notes of the same, on or before the first day of August, 1857, and all unconditional certificates which are not returned by that time, the said locations and surveys shall be null and void, and all such loca<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tions and surveys made by virtue of such conditional certificates shall become public domain and subject to be located upon as other vacant lands.</p>
<p>Sec. 2, That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning the School Lands of Navarro County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patents for the School Lands of Navarro County, embraced in the surveys made by J. P. Philpot, District Surveyor of Robertson Land District. That this Act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prevent slaves from carrying guns or other dangerous weapons.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no slave shall carry a gun or other deadly weapon upon the premises of his master, mistress, or employer, without a written permit from his owner or employer, so to do.</p>
<pb n="500" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="82" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That no slave shall be permitted to carry a gun or other deadly weapon beyond the premises of his owner or employer, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />less accompanied by his owner, employer, or some white person, au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized by his owner, or employer to have charge of said slave, during the time that he carries said gun or other deadly weapon.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any gun or other weapon, found in the possession of any slave, contrary to the provisions of the previous sections of this act, may be seized and taken from said slave, by any white person, and said property forfeited to the person seizing and taking the same, provided the same shall not exceed, in value, the sum of twen<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty dollars. But any such property may be reclaimed, by the owner paying the sum of twenty dollars to the person or persons who may have taken the same.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the sixth section of an act, approved 5th February, A. D., 1840, be, and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to repeal an act to provide for the issuance of bounty and donation land warrants to persons entitled to the same.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That an act to provide for the issuance of bounty and dona<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion land warrants to persons entitled to the same, approved Janu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary 31st, 1854, be and the same is hereby repealed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the Treasurer of the State to col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lect from the United States, the money upon certain Public Debt certificates, therein named.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State, as receiver and <pb n="501" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="83" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>keeper of all funds belonging to estate, by virtue of the laws of the late republic and State of Texas, &#8220;relative to the estates of deceased persons,&#8221; that may be in the possession of administrators, upon a final settlement of an estate when no heirs, devisees or legatees ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pear and claim the same, is hereby authorized and required to pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sent to the Treasury of the United States for payment, the following 1st class Public debt certificates of the late republic of Texas, now in the Treasury of the State to the credit of certain estates, to wit: certificate No. 2479, issued to the heirs of John Jones, dec&#8217;d; No. 2480, issued to the heirs of Joel Hill, dec&#8217;d; No. 2481, issued to the heirs of Warren Abom, dec&#8217;d; No. 2482, issued to the heirs of John L. Monks, dec&#8217;d, and No. 2483, issued to the heirs of Peter Aldrich, dec&#8217;d, and to draw for the benefit of said estates or heirs, the pro rata amount due upon each certificate, and to sign all necessary re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceipts and releases that may be required, to the United States or the State of Texas; and such amounts, when received by said Treasurer, shall be placed by him upon the books of his office to the credit of the respective estates or heirs, in lieu of the Public debt certificates surrendered.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act relating to the duties of Assessors and Collectors of Taxes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no Assessor and Collector of taxes, Shall, either di<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rectly or indirectly, speculate in any county paper or other fund whatever, made receivable by law for the payment of taxes, nor in any manner invest or use for his own benefit or profit any monies, or funds, received by him in payment of taxes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That every Assessor and Collector of taxes, Shall keep one or more books, containing printed or written blank receipts, as well as corresponding marginal summaries and be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the delivery of any receipt for taxes, he shall fill up a blank therefor, as well as the corresponding marginal summary in said book, with the dates, name of the person and amount <pb n="502" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="84" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>and character of the fund paid, whether money, county paper or other fund receivable for State and county taxes, and shall sever said receipt from said book, leaving therein the corresponding mar<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ginal summary as a permanent register of his office, which shall be produced before the County Court of his county when required, and shall also be subject to public inspection.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That each Assessor and Collector of taxes shall pay to the Treasurer of his county, all monies collected by him for county taxes, in the same funds as received by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That every Assessor and Collector of taxes who shall vio<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />late any of the provisions of this act, shall for the first offence be punished by a fine of not less than fifty, nor more than one hundred dollars, to be recovered in the name of the State of Texas, before any court having jurisdiction thereof; of which fine the informer shall re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive the one-half and the other half shall be paid info the county Treasury for county purposes, and for the second offence, he shall be liable to indictment by a Grand Jury, and on conviction, he shall be fined in any sum not exceeding two hundred dollars, and shall be removed from office.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing and requiring the Governor of the State to have surveyed the unlocated balance of the University Lands.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to cause to be surveyed, as soon as possible, on any vacant or unappropriated lands belonging to the State, twenty-two thousand two hundred and fifty acres of land, or the unlocated balance do<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />nated and set apart by the late Republic of Texas, for the endow<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment and establishment of two Universities.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to draw upon the Treasurer of the State, for such sum or sums of money as may be necessary for defraying the expenses incurred by locating and surveying said lands.</p>
<pb n="503" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="85" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to legalize the official acts of David P. Fearris, Notary Pub<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lic of the county of Ellis.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the notarial acts of David P. Fearris be, and the same are hereby declared as legal as though he had been a naturalized citizen, previous to his appointment as Notary Public of Ellis coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the protection of the lands that have been or may here<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />after be granted for purposes of Education.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no statute of limitation shall run in favor of any one who has heretofore, or may hereafter settle upon or occupy any of the lands that have heretofore been granted or may hereafter be granted by the State, for purposes of Education. And this act shall take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of the Coshattee Indians.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That six hundred and forty acres of meant and un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />appropriated land situated in Liberty, Polk, or Tyler counties, or any of them, to be selected by the Chiefs of the Coshattee tribe of Indians and the Commissioners hereinafter named, be and the same is hereby set apart for the sole use and benefit <pb n="504" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="86" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of, and as a dome for the said tribe of Indians; and that the District Surveyor of the District of Liberty, or his legal deputy, be authorized and required, upon the application of said Commissioners, to sur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vey the same and to return the field notes thereof, duly authenti<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cated, to the Commissioner of the General Land Office, who shall thereupon issue a patent to said tribe of Indians for the same; and that said Surveyor shall, fox such service, receive the usual fees of office and no more.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That should said Chief and Commissioners be unable to select a suitable home for said Indians, on vacant and unappropri<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ated land, then and in that case, the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to purchase six hundred and forty acres of land from the owner or owners thereof, situated in any of the aforesaid coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties, at a price not to exceed two dollars per acre, and shall take from the owner or owners of such lands, deeds with warranty, con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />veying the same to said tribe of Indians; which deeds of conveyance shall be acknowledged or proven, and admitted to record in the county in which the land or the greater part thereof is situated, be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fore the purchase money or any part thereof shall be paid. And the said Commissioners are hereby authorized to draw on the Treasurer of the State in favor of the person or persons from whom said land or any part thereof may have been purchased, for a sum of money not to exceed twelve hundred dollars, the amount of which draft the Treasurer shall pay out of any money in the Treasury, not other<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />wise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That said Indians shall not alien, lease, rent, let, give, or otherwise dispose of said land, or any part thereof, to any person whomsoever. And should the State of Texas hereafter provide a different and permanent home for said tribe of Indians, and settle them thereon, then said six hundred and forty acres of land with its improvements shall become the property of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That Samuel Rowe and Milton A. Harden be, and they are hereby appointed Commissioners for the purposes contemplated in this act, and that they shall be entitled to a sum of money not to exceed one hundred dollars each for their services as Commissioners, as aforesaid. They shall return to the Treasury Department a cer<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tificate sworn to before any officer authorized to administer oaths, setting forth the quantity of land so purchased for said Indians, in what county situated, and at what price it was purchased.</p>
<pb n="505" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="87" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. Should any portion of the land selected by said Chiefs and Commissioners prove to be on the public domain and not amount to the said six hundred and forty acres, then and in that case, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorized and required to issue a patent to and in the name of said tribe of Indians, for such land as shall be so vacant upon the return of the field notes of the District Surveyor, of the amount surveyed of the public domain.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Supplementary to an act for the relief of the citizens of Mercer&#8217;s Colony, passed February 2d, 1850.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That section eight of the above mentioned act be so amend<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed that it shall only be necessary for the Colonists or citizens to prove by his, her or their own oaths, supported by the oaths of two respectable witnesses, that he, she or they emigrated to and was a resident citizen of the Territory commonly known as Mercer&#8217;s Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony, on or before the 25th day of October, A. D. 1848, and that he, she, or they, have never received any land from this Government by virtue of their emigration hither.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the proof required by the first section of this act shall be made before the District Court of the county in said Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ony, where the party resided in said Colony; and it shall be the duty of the District Court to hear and determine and award or refuse certificates to the parties applying under the provisions of this act, and the act to which this is supplementary, as in other cases.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That no petition shall be required and it shall only be necessary for the applicant to have the case docketed, and the same shall be heard in its order.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the certificates for the claims established under this act shall be issued by the Clerk, and be counter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />signed by the Judge of the Court issuing the same, and of the issues of said certificates, the clerk shall make annual re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="506" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="88" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>turns to the Commissioner of the General Land Office; and in no case shall the fee be more than three dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act authorizing the United States Marshal of the District of Texas, to use the jails of the various counties of the State and Penitentiary for certain purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be lawful for the United States Marshal, for the District of Texas, to use the county jails of the various counties and penitentiary of the State, for the confinement of such persons as may at any time be in his custody, under process from any lawful tribunal or authority, whenever it shall be necessary for him to do so in the discharge of his official duties; and it shall be the duty of the Sheriffs and Jailors of the respective counties, having jails there<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />in to receive such prisoners as may be delivered or tendered to them for safe keeping by the Marshal or his legal deputy, and to safely keep such prisoners until they shall he demanded by the Marshal or his deputy, or discharged by due course of law.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Marshal shall be directly and personally liable to the Sheriff and Jailors for the jail fees, to which they may be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled for keeping such prisoners as may be committed to their cus<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tody by the Marshal or his deputy, under the provisions of this act; provided, that no Sheriff or jailor shall be entitled to charge or re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceive any greater compensation for keeping prisoners committed to their custody by the Marshal or his deputy, than they may be en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled to charge and receive, for receiving and keeping prisoners under other laws of the State&#8212;except when a guard or guards may be necessary, in which case the Marshal shall pay all such additional expenses.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That any Sheriff or Jailor, in whose county there is a jail, who shall refuse to receive into the jail of his county any prisoner tendered to him by the Marshal or his deputy, as con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />templated by the provisions of this act, not having the excuse for such refusal, that there is not room in such jail for the confinement of such prisoner or prisoners, shall be consid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="507" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="89" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ered guilty of a misdemeanor and on conviction thereof in the Dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict Court, shall be subject to a fine of not less than fifty dollars.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act attaching a portion of Falls County, including Elm Creek, to Bell County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That a strip of territory six miles wide on the southwest side of Falls county, adjoining Bell county, including Elm Creek, be, and the same is hereby attached to and made part of Bell county for all county purposes.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That it shall be the duty of the County Court of Bell county to cause the lines of said county to be run and marked as es<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tablished by this act, after giving notice of the time and place, twenty days previously thereto, to the Chief-Justice of Falls county. And that this act take effect and be in force after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act for the relief of Robertson County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue a patent for one league of land to the county of Robertson, located and surveyed in the county of Ellis, as school land for the said county of Robertson; pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that said survey does not conflict with any previous location or survey.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="508" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="90" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXIV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act creating the office of Weigher of Cotton for certain Ports in this State.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That there shall be appointed by the Governor, at Indianola and La Vaca, in the county of Calhoun, and at Houston in Harris county, and at Richmond, in Fort Bend county, and at Galveston, in the county of Galveston, respectively, one fit and competent per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son to superintend the weighing, with his own scales or balances, of such cotton brought to market in the usual bales or packages, as he may be required to weigh. He shall hold his office for three years subject to removal at any time for gross and palpable misconduct. When a vacancy may occur, by death, resignation, removal from office, or from the county; it shall be filed by the Governor, and the person receiving the appointment, shall hold said office three years from the date of his commission. The Governor may make similar appointments, at his discretion, under the provisions of this act, in any other port or ports of this State.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. Every person so appointed, before entering upon the duties of his office, shall take an oath before any officer in the county, authorized to administer oaths, faithfully and impartially to execute the duties of his office, and to make true returns; he shall be in readiness at all times, in business hours, to discharge the duties of his office; he shall have power to appoint and employ one or more deputies, who shall be sworn to perform the duties, and for whose acts, the principal shall be liable. He shall keep a memorandum record of all cotton weighed by him, shall certify the weight in de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tail, and at the request of purchaser or seller, the merchantable con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dition of cotton weighed by him.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. He shall be liable to indictment and conviction in any court of competent jurisdiction for malfeasance in office, and for fraud, and on conviction shall be removed from office, and be fined in the discretion of the jury, not less than one hundred nor more than one thousand dollars; he shall also be liable in damages, to the patty injured.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. He shall keep accurate and well adjusted scales or bal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ances, and acucrate weights, and shall mark with ink, in legible characters, on each bale the weight thereof, and the initials of his name and office.</p>
<pb n="509" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="91" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 5. He shall be allowed, for each bale weighed, marked and certified by him, eight cents, and shall not be obliged to deliver the cotton so weighed, marked and certified, until said charge be paid and satisfied.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. It shall not be lawful for any person other than a regu<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />larly appointed Weighmaster to weigh any cotton offered for sale in said ports, and any person so offending shall be liable to indict<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment by the Grand Jury of the county, and on conviction, to a fine of one dollar for each and every bale so unlawfully weighed, and im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />prisonment in the county jail, not less than ten nor more than ninety days, either or both of which punishments may be inflicted at the discretion of the jury; provided, that nothing herein shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />strued to prevent any person weighing his or her or their own cotton.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That this act shall take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the Commissioner of the General Land Office to issue patents upon certain surveys made on the Islands of Mustang, Matagorda, St. Joseph and Hog.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby authorized and required to issue patents upon surveys made upon the Islands of Mustang, Matagorda, St. Joseph and Hog, by virtue of Land scrip issued by the proper authorities, of the Re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />public of Texas, to Thomas Toby, William Bryan, and under the provisions of an act for the relief of James Irwin and others, ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proved June 3d, 1837, provided such surveys were made in accord<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ance, with the laws governing surveys; and further provided that such surveys do not conflict with the rights of other parties.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Commissioner of the General Land Office be, and he is hereby required to issue patents to such lands on the Islands herein named, upon the same class of Land Scrip described in this act, whenever the claimants shall prove by the records of the Surveyor&#8217;s offices of the dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trict in which the same may be situated, duly certified and sworn to by the Surveyor, and also by the evidence of the per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son acting as legal Surveyor at the time, if living, or if not liv<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="510" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="92" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ing, by the testimony of two respectable witnesses, as to the genuineness of the entries in said Surveyor&#8217;s book, that such scrip was located by entries in said Surveyor&#8217;s office, before the institution of the suit in Galveston county, in the case of &#8220;The State vs. Deles<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dernier,&#8221; and that said locations or entries have not since been raised or cancelled by the claimants, provided, that in addition to said proof, the land shall be surveyed, and the scrip and field notes re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turned to the General Land Office, according to the laws of this State.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act concerning the Public Printing.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Public Printer be, and he is hereby required to print, for the use of the State, fifteen hundred Copies of the General Laws of the State Legislature, in addition to the number now re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired by law to be printed.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the Public Printer shall print the laws and journals of the sixth Legislature, up to the 4th day of February, 1856, as though the Legislature had adjourned sine die on that day.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the Governor, to contract for and have printed on good paper, and bound in half leather binding, five thousand copies, in one volume, of the Penal Code and Code of Criminal Procedure; which, when completed and delivered, shall be disposed of as is required in the distribution of the general laws; and be may also, if necessary, appoint some suitable and competent per<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />son to correct the proof sheets as issued from the press, and to make an index thereto. And this act take effect from and after its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="511" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="93" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to prevent the sale of vinous, spirituous or other intoxi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cating liquors, within one mile of Jamestown and Starrville, in Smith county.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall not be lawful for any person or firm to engage in the sale of spirituous, vinous or other intoxicating liquors within one mile around the town of Jamestown and Starrville, in Smith county; and any person or firm guilty of a violation of the provisions of this act, shall be punished according to the fifth section of an act, en<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />titled &#8220;an act to authorize the County Courts of this State to grant license for the retail of spirituous, vinous, and (other) intoxicating liquors, in quantities less than a quart, and imposing a license tax, for such privilege, &#8220;approved 2d February, 1856.&#8221; And that this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize the county court of Rusk county, to grant let<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ters of administration on the estate of Bolling Hall, deceased, late of Cherokee County.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That it shall be lawful for letters of administration to be granted in the county of Rusk, on the estate of Bolling Hall dec&#39;d, late of Cherokee county, to any person authorized by law to receive the same, in the Same manner and under the same rule&#39;s and regulations, as if the said Bolling Hall, dec&#8217;d, had resided in the said Rusk county alt the time of his decease, instead of said county of Cherokee.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That letters of administration granted on said estate, by the County Court of said county of Rusk, shall be as valid, to all intents and purposes, as if the same had been granted by the County Court of Cherokee county. All laws, and parts of laws to the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />trary notwithstanding. And that this act shall take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="512" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="94" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act making provision for the translating and printing of certain general laws, into the Spanish and German languages.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Governor be, and he is hereby authorized to hare such of the general laws of the present Legislature, translated and printed in the Spanish and German languages as he may deem advisable.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the sum of three thousand dollars is hereby appropriated for the purpose of carrying into effect the first section of this act, out of any money in the State Treasury not otherwise appropriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That after the translating and printing of the laws aforesaid, the Governor shall draw his warrant or warrants on the Treasury for the amount thereof, in favor of the person or persons employed to perform said work. And the Treasurer is hereby re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />quired to pay such warrants out of the appropriation above men<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tioned. Provided, that said warrant or warrants shall not exceed the sum of three thousand dollars.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to define the time of holding the District Courts of the third Judicial District.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That from and after the time at which this act takes effect, the District Courts of the third Judicial District shall be held at the times following, to wit: In the county of Washington, on the second Monday of March and September, in each year, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session three weeks; in the county of Burleson, on the third Monday after the second Monday in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Milam, on the fourth Monday after the second Monday in March and September and may continue in session one week; in the county of McLennan, on the fifth Monday after the second Monday in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember and may continue in session two weeks; in the county <pb n="513" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="95" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>of Bosque on the seventh Monday after the second Monday in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Coryell, on the eighth Monday after the second Monday in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Bell, on the ninth Monday after the second Monday in March and September, and may continue in session until the business of the court is disposed of.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. All writs and other process which may be issued before the time at which this act takes effect, and Which may be made re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turnable at the times now fixed by law for holding the District Courts in said District, shall be construed to be returnable at the times herein established.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. This act shall take effect and be in force from and after the first day of January, A. D. 1857, and from and after that time all laws and parts of laws conflicting herewith shall stand repealed.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>August 30th, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to permit the County of Brazoria to levy a special tax for purposes of Internal Improvements.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the county of Brazoria shall have the power to levy and collect a tax for the purposes hereinafter specified upon all persons and property, real, personal and mixed, within the limits of said county; provided, the same shall not for any one year exceed one-fourth of one per cent ad valorum on property; they may also levy and collect a tax on all Taverns, Groceries, Bar rooms, Tippling Houses, Nine and Ten Pin Allies and Billiard Tables in the county, for the same purpose; provided, said tax shall not exceed double the tax now levied on the same by law in said county; said taxes shall be assessed and collected as other taxes are now assessed and collected for the county of Brazoria, and under such further regulations as may be prescribed by the County Court of Brazoria, and if any person shall fail or refuse to pay the taxes assessed against him or his property, within the time prescribed by the County Court, Iris property shall be subject to be sold in the same manner as for other taxes levied and collected by said county.</p>
<pb n="514" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="96" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 2. That no such tax shall be levied unless a majority of two-thirds of all the votes cast at an election to be ordered for that pur<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />pose by the Chief-Justice of said county at such time as may be fixed upon by the County Court after twenty days notice; in the manner prescribed for the notice of general elections for said county, shall have approved of such tax; said election shall be conducted by the same officers and in the same manner as other county elections, and the ballots shall read for or against the tax that may be pre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed for ballot; it shall be lawful at any subsequent time, upon the petition of fifty voters of the county, again to take the sense of the voters in the same manner as at the first election, and at inter<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vals of not less than six months upon the same or other internal improvements.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That after the vote in favor of laying the tax aforesaid, for the improvement aforesaid, the county of Brazoria may issue its bonds in such manner and for such amounts, payable at such times and with such interest as the County Court may deem necessary; provided, that the amount of said bonds shall not be for more than the special tax levied, will pay the annual interest upon which bonds may be used by said county in the construction of any Railroad or Canal, running into or from Brazoria County, or in taking stock or subscription in any such Road or Canal or for the purpose of im<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />proving the navigation of the Brazos river from its mouth, (which includes the Bar) to Richmond in Fort Bend county, and it shall not be necessary to renew the order for said tax from year year, but the same may be regulated by the County Court of said county, from time to time, so as to raise a sufficient amount to pay the in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />terest annually on said bonds, and such instalments of the principal as may be deemed necessary to provide for; provided, that said tax shall not at any time be more than one-fourth of one per cent ad valorem, on property. And this act shall take effect from its pass<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />age.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act amending an act to create the County of Erath.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That said act be so amended that a part of the bound<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ary line of said county of Erath, shall run as follows: begining <pb n="515" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="97" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>at the North-East corner of Comanche county; thence South 60 degrees West with the Worth boundary of Comanche county, five miles; thence North 30 degrees West to a point five miles South 60 degrees West from the present North-West corner of Erath coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty; thence direct to said North-west corner.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. And that this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Supplementary to an act making appropriations for the use and support of the State Government for the years 1856 and 1857, passed 4th February, 1856, and for other purposes.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the following sums be, and they are hereby appropriated in addition to appropriations heretofore made for the use and support of the State Government for the years 1856 and 1857.</p>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">JUDICIARY&#8212;SUPREME COURT.</head>
<p>For increased salary of three Judges of the Supreme Court. Each one thousand dollars, annually, three thousand dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">DISTRICT COURT.</head>
<p>For increase salaries of fourteen Judges, of the District Court, five hundred dollars each, annually.</p>
<p>For salaries of four Judges of the District Court, two thousand two hundred and fifty dollars each, annually.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">COURT OF CLAIMS.</head>
<p>Salary of Commissioner of Court of Claims, annually, two thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand two hundred and fifty dollars, four thousand five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>Salary of Clerk of Court of Claims, one thousand dollars annual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly, two thousand dollars. Salary of one assistant Clerk, nine hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars annually, or so ranch thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For the purchase of books and stationery, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For furniture for office of Commissioner of Court of Claims, three hundred dollars.</p>
<pb n="516" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="98" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For the purchase of books for General Land Office, under act and in connection with Court of Claims, one hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">STATE DEPARTMENT.</head>
<p>For the purchase of additional Furniture for State Department, five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For distributing Laws and Journals of sixth Legislature, two thousand five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of extra Clerks to copy laws in due time, one hundred dollars.</p>
</div3>
<div3 type="section">
<head type="main">MISCELLANEOUS.</head>
<p>For pay of Assessors and Tax Collectors for taking census of Scholastic population for years 1856 and 1857, annually, five thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary, ten thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of Members and officers of 6th Legislature, five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of contingent expenses of 6th Legislature, five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For balance pay to James Willie and John W. Harris as Com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />missioners in preparing Code, revising Statutes, &#38;c., from 11th of February to 21st of July, 1856, at one thousand five hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars per annum, each six hundred and sixty-six dollars and sixty-six cents&#8212;one thousand three hundred and thirty-three dollars and thirty-three cents.</p>
<p>Swenson and Swisher for Insurance and transportation of $120,424 35, in coin, from New Orleans to Austin, for State Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ury, being one and one-fourth per cent on amount&#8212;one thousand five hundred and five dollars and thirty-eight cents.</p>
<p>For rent of House for Governor of the State from the 21st De<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cember, 1855 to 14th June, 1856, being five months and 24 days, at $75 per month&#8212;four hundred and thirty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For pay and mileage of Electors of President and Vice-President, or so much thereof as may be necessary&#8212;five hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of salary of State Engineer and Superintendent&#8212;three thousand dollars annually.</p>
<p>For pay of Sub Engineers three thousand dollars annually, or so much thereof as may be required.</p>
<p>For Boats, hire of hands, &#38;c., in making the necessary examination of navigable rivers, Bayous, Lakes and Bays&#8212;<pb n="517" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="99" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>three thousand dollars, or as much thereof as may be necessary, all of which appropriations for said rivers and officers shall be taken from the funds set aside for the improvement of the rivers and other navigable waters of Texas.</p>
<p>For salary of Auditor from 1st of January to 24th of March 1856, being two months and 24 days, at one thousand five hundred dollars per annum&#8212;three hundred and fifty dollars.</p>
<p>For pay to W. L. Chalmers, for receiving shelving, marking, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dexing and acting as Librarian to Supreme Court Library for the year 1855&#8212;one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pay to Charles Rosignold and Samuel Earl for services as Librarian to the Supreme Court, during the year eighteen hundred and forty-five, at Galveston and Tyler respectively, each one hundred dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of J. M. Massie, as Clerk in the Adjutant Generals office &#8212;ne hundred dollars.</p>
<p>Tor Taylor and Murry, amount for pens and boxes&#8212;thirteen dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars and twenty-five cents.</p>
<p>For R. H. Peck, as per acct.&#8212;orty-five dollars and ninety-two cents.</p>
<p>For John Bremond, as per acct.&#8212;thirty-nine dollars and thirty-four cents.</p>
<p>For Sampson and Henricks, as per acct.&#8212;seventeen dollars and thirty cents.</p>
<p>For Spence and Tumey, as per acct.&#8212;eight dollars and ninety cents</p>
<p>For F. Dietrich, bal. acct. for furniture&#8212;nine dollars and eighty-nine cents.</p>
<p>Fox pay of two guards for Land Office, from the 17th of May, 1856, to the first of September, 1856, forty dollars per month each&#8212;two hundred and eighty dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of two guards for Land Office, from the first of Septem<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ber 1856 to the first of November 1857, at thirty dollars per month each, to be expended at the option of the Governor and Commission<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />er of the General Land Office&#8212;seven hundred and eighty dollars.</p>
<p>For pay for printing Laws and Journals of the 6th Legislature, including Code of Criminal Procedure and Penal Code, newspapers, bills, reports and other printing for adjourned session of the 6th Legislature, or so much as may be necessary, and this appropriation shall include the binding of Codes&#8212;twenty thousand dollars.</p>
<pb n="518" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="100" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>For purchase of books for State Library, to be expended under the direction of the Governor&#8212;five thousand dollars.</p>
<p>For purchase of books for the Supreme Court Library&#8212;five thou<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />sand dollars.</p>
<p>For pay to Joseph Harrel for expenditure on public building&#8212;one hundred and twenty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For pay to Moodie and Bohme, for Flaging side walk of public lot&#8212;one hundred and eighty-five dollars.</p>
<p>For pay of James S. Gillet, salary as Adjutant General, from January 1st to 4th February, one month and 4 days, at twelve hun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dred dollars per annum&#8212;one hundred and thirteen dolllars.</p>
<p>For one hundred dollars annually for H. M. Smith who was permanently disabled in the Cherokee fight, on the 16th day of July, 1839.</p>
<p>Three hundred and fifty-six dollars to F. R. Lubbock, for pay<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ment of 2d Class certificate of Public Debt, per. acct. approved Au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gust 12th, 1856.</p>
<p>For pay of B. F. Hollingworth for acting as Clerk of investigat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing committee, from the 8th of August to the 25th August, in<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />clusive, being 18 days at ($5) five dollars per day&#8212;ninety dollars.</p>
<p>Three thousand nine hundred and thirty-four dollars and seven<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty cents, to be paid to the heirs and legal representatives of Archi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />bald Fitzjerald.</p>
<p>For erecting a tomb over the grave of General E. Burleson, to be expended under the direction of the Governor&#8212;three thousand dollars.</p>
<p>The sum of one thousand dollars to aid in enclosing the graves and in erecting a monument over the remains of those who fell in the battle of San Jacinto anti were buried on the battle field; to be paid to the Treasurer of the San Jacinto Monumental Associa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, when he shall file with the Treasurer good and sufficient evi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />dence of the completion of the monument, and the enclosure of the graves, the said enclosure to be of substantial iron rails.</p>
<p>For salary of Chief Clerk of the House of Representatives and Secretary of the Senate, each annually, one thousand dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>For contingent fund, for purpose of buying books, repairing Capitol, &#38;c., annually three hundred dollars, or so much thereof as may be necessary.</p>
<p>The sum of five thousand dollars for the payment of the expenses attending the prosecutions for burning of the Adju<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="519" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="101" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>tant General&#8217;s office, and for forgeries committed in the Adjutant Generals office, to be paid on the warrant of the Governor and At<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />torney General and District Attorney of the District, in which such prosecutions were pending.</p>
<p>For pay to J. L. Haynes, for services as Clerk for twenty days, as Clerk of Board of Land Commissioners to investigate land titles, in certain counties therein named, eighty-three dollars and thirty-three cents.</p>
<p>For pay to Payne and Phillips for fitting up the Senate Chamber and Representatives Hall, two hundred and seventy-eight dollars and twenty-three cents; for work done in eighteen hundred and fifty-five.</p>
<p>For compensation to George J. Durham, for services as acting Comptroller, during the absence of James B. Shaw, and for services in the late Auditor&#8217;s office, from first of April to first of September, five months, at fifty dollars per month, two hundred and fifty dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars.</p>
<p>Two hundred and fifty dollars to be expended by the Governor in the purchase of Pressler&#8217;s new map of Texas, for the use and benefit of the State, and five hundred dollars, or so much thereof, as may be necessary, to pay for the surveying of Toby scrip, for years for which there is no appropriation. Which sums are authorized to be paid out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect from its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div3>
</div2>
<div2 type="section">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXX1V.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An act to prevent the sale of intoxicating drinks within the limits of the league of land, in Fayette county, granted to Franklin Lewis, on which the town of Rutersville is situated.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That no spirituous, or malt liquors, wine or cider, shall hereafter be sold or bartered, or exchanged within the limits of land in the county of Fayette, in said State, granted to Franklin Lewis, on which the town of Rutersville is situated, or (which shall be a sale within the meaning of this act) given away as a beverage, at a house or establishment on said league of land, where any other article is kept for sale; provided, <pb n="520" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="102" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>always, that if, within two months after the final passage of this act, any fifteen of the citizens of said county resident on said league of land, and qualified to vote for county officers in said county, being dissatisfied with this law, should petition the chief-justice of said county, for an election to test the will of the electors on said league upon this law, and represent their dissatisfaction in said petition, said Chief-Justice shall order an election to be held at said town of Rutersville, by a person and at a time named by him in his order, giving ten days notice by posting said order in three places on said league, and said election shall be held and conducted, and return thereof made in the manner provided by law for county officers, and if a majority of the electors resident on said league, who may vote at said election, should vote in favor of a sale and disposition of liquors, wine and cider as aforesaid, then it shall be lawful to sell and dispose of the same by paying license and doing every other act, provided by law, and not otherwise.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That any person violating the provisions of this act, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and on conviction thereof before any justice of the peace of said county, shall forfeit and pay a fine of not less than twenty, nor more than fifty dollars for each and every such offence, and shall by said Justice be committed to the jail of said county, until the fine and all costs be paid, and the prosecution shall be conducted in the manner [name] of said state on the affidavit of any resident of said county, that he or she has good reason to be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lieve that such offence has been committed, and all fines collected under the provisions of this act shall be paid over to the county Treasury, and form a part, of the jury fund of said county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXV.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to authorize and require the Clerks of the District Courts of the counties of Harrison and Rusk, to apportion the causes on the docket of said court.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That before the commencement of each and every <pb n="521" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="103" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>term of the District Court of the Counity of Harrison and Rusk, the District Clerks of said courts shall apportion the causes on the dock<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ets to so many days, and in such numbers to each day as may be deemed most expedient, and no cause shall be taken up (except by consent of parties) for trial or hearing at a day previous to that for which it may be set, and they shall issue the subpoenas for witnesses to attend on the days on which the causes stand for trial; and no witnesses shall be bound to attend in any cause unless specially sum<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />moned to each term, and it shall be the duty of the Clerks to keep a regular subpoena docket, and to issue subpoenas before every term of the court for all the witnesses in every case.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That this act take effect immediately.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXVI.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act granting certain real estate to the City of Austin.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1, Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Terns, That the State of Texas hereby authorizes and empowers the corporation of the city of Austin to take possession and have and exercise absolute control over the following property and real estate, to wit: Lots No. nine (9), ten (10), eleven (11) and twelve (12), in block No. ninety-eight (98), as the same is laid out on the original plat of said city of Austin, at present known and described as the old Capitol property with appurtenances; to have and to hold the same free of charge, for the full term and period of three years, from the date of the passage of this act, and at the expiration of said period of time, the Commissioner of the General Land Office is hereby authorized to relinquish and patent unto the said corpora<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion all her right, title and interest of, in and to the same, provided the said corporation, within said time, erect thereon a good and suf<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficient Market-House and City Hall, for the use of said city. Pro<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />vided, that Whenever the city of Austin shall convert the same for any other use than that mentioned in this act, the said property shall revert to the State; and further provided that the corporate au<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />thorities of the city of Austin, shall execute to the State of Texas, a relinquishment of all claim on the part of said city <pb n="522" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="104" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>to the ground marked on the map, of said city as a market square.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the State of Texas hereby relinquishes to the corpo<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ration of the city of Austin, all her right, title and interest in the following described property and real estate, to wit: all that certain tract or parcel of land, situated in division B and known and de<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />scribed on the original plat of said city, as the cemetery property.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect, and be in force, from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXVII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act changing a portion of the boundary of the counties of Cal<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />houn, Victoria arid Refugio.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That hereafter the boundaries of the county of Calhoun, shall be as follows, viz: Beginning and runing as heretofore to the west corner of the survey of Voluntine Garcia; thence to the north corner of a survey of a league known as the Juan Nepomocina Ses<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />eneros league; thence with the north west boundary of said survey to the Guadalupe river; thence down said river to its mouth; thence with the main channel of Espiritu Santo Bay to the Steamboat Dug<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />out; thence south-east to the gulf shore; thence with said shore to the beginning.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the portion of territory heretofore belonging to Calhoun county, lying south and west of this boundary, shall be<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />long to and make a pant of Refugio county.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That this act take effect from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<pb n="523" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="105" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXVIII.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to amend the 8th section of an act to encourage the con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />struction of Railroads in Texas by donation of land, approved January 30th, 1854.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 8th section of said act shall read as follows:</p>
<p>Section 8. That surveys under the provisions of this act shall be made by the Deputies or District surveyors of the District in which the land is situated, and the field-notes shall be recorded in such District, and returned to the General Land Office as other surveys.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXIX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act to organize the 17th and reorganize the 2d Judicial District, and define the time of holding Courts therein.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the 17th Judicial District shall be composed of the following counties, to wit: Williamson, Burnet, La Salle, Llano, San Saba, McCulloch, Brown and Lampasas.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. That the District Courts shall be held in said District at the following time and places, to wit: In the county of Williamson, on the first Mondays in March and September and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Burnet, on the third Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of La Salle, on the fourth Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Llano, on the fifth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week; in the county of San Saba, on the sixth Mondays after the first Monday in March and September and may continue in session one week; in the county of McCulloch, on the seventh Mondays after the first Mondays in March and Sep<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tember, and may continue in session one week; in the county of Brown on the eighth Mondays after the first Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days in March and September and may continue in session one week; in the county of Lampasas, on the <pb n="524" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="106" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>ninth Mondays after the first Mondays in March and September, and may continue in session one week.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That all writs and process of every kind that have been or hereafter may be issued from the District Courts of any of the counties named in this act, shall be returned to the said Courts as established by this act, and all of said process and writs shall have the same force and effect as if they had been originally returnable; that all cases of appeals from the Districts Courts named in this act, shall be to the branch of the Supreme Court at Austin.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That the Governor be and he is hereby required to order an election to be held in said 17th Judicial District, on the first Monday in October in the year 1856, for the election of a District Judge and District Attorney, and the said election shall be con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ducted in all respects according to law.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That all suits which may be now pending in any of the District Courts of this State for land situated in any of the counties specified in this act, the Clerks of the several District Courts in which said suits are pending, arc hereby required to return all of the original papers in said suits to the District Courts of the coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ties in which said lands are situated together with a full and com<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />plete transcript of all proceedings which may have been had in said suit; provided, that the returns of papers and transcripts, as provided in this section, shall be made by the first of March, 1857; and provid<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ed further, that suits pending as in the section aforesaid, may be dis<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />posed of before the first of March 1857, in the counties in which they were instituted.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the Second Judicial District shall be composed of the counties of Bastrop, Caldwell, Guadalupe, Hays and Travis.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. That the District Court for the county of Bastrop, shall be held on the first Mondays in April and October and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Caldwell, on the second Mon<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />days after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Guadalupe, on the fourth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October, and may continue in session two weeks; in the county of Hays, on the sixth Mondays after the first Mondays in April and October and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session one week; in the county of Travis, on the seventh Mondays of the first Mondays in April and October, and may con<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tinue in session until the business is disposed of.</p>
<pb n="525" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="107" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 8. That all laws and parts of laws heretofore enacted relat<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ing to the time of holding the several courts in the said Second Judicial District, be, and the same are hereby repealed, and that all process which has been issued and made returnable to the several courts of said District shall be and are hereby made returnable to the said courts respectively, at the periods of their session, as specified in this act, and that all recognizances and bonds entered into by any person or persons in said courts with reference to the periods of their respective sessions under the law heretofore in force, shall be and are hereby made obligatory upon the parties with reference to the terms of said courts respectively, as prescribed by this act</p>
<p>Sec. 9, That all process made returnable to the District Courts of any of the said counties at the present time, shall be returnable to the terms of said Courts, as herein prescribed.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. That all acts and parts of acts conflicting with this act, be, and they are hereby repealed, and that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Passed, <date>September 1st, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
<div2 type="act">
<head type="main">CHAPTER CLXXX.</head>
<opener>
<salute>An Act Providing for the Support of Schools.</salute>
</opener>
<p>Section 1. Be it enacted by the Legislature of the State of Texas, That the Treasurer of the State be authorized and required to transfer to the General or State account, the specie now in the Treasury, to the credit of the General School Fund account, and re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />place the same from the one million five hundred and seventy-five thousand dollars, United States Bonds, now standing to the credit of the State account; and it is hereby made the duty of the State Treasurer, annually on the first day of July, in each year, to trans<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fer the specie then standing to the credit of the School Fund, re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ceived from one tenth taxes to State account, and replace the same with United States bonds from the State account, unless otherwise provided by law; that the Special School Fund of two millions dollars, created by &#8220;An act to establish a system of schools,&#8221; passed January 31st, 1854, and that the General School fund, derivable from, one-tenth taxes, be, and the same are blended and made one, and the interest arising from the United States Bends, constituting said fund, and the interest arising from all <pb n="526" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="108" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>monies set aside for school purposes, be, and the Same is hereby ap<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />propriated to the respective counties, for the use and benefit of the children of said counties, between the age of six and eighteen years, as herein provided.</p>
<p>Sec. 2. It shall be the duty of true Assessor and Collector of each county in the State, during each and every year hereafter, to make out a list of all the free white population in his county, between the ages of six and eighteen years, and transmit the same under his official signature to the County Clerk of the county, and a certi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />fied copy to the Treasurer of the State, on or before the first day of July in each and every year.</p>
<p>Sec. 3. That it shall be the duty of the Clerk of the County Court to file and preserve in his office the list aforesaid, furnished by the Assessor and Collector. It shall be the duty of the Treasurer of the State to ascertain from the abstracts transmitted to him by the Assessor and Collector, the aggregate population between the ages of six and eighteen years. And the fund appropriated by this act shall be apportioned among the different counties in the State, according to the number of scholastic population in each Bounty, subject to the order of the County Courts, and payable to the re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective county treasurers, upon the order of the County Court, un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />der the hand of the Chief-Justice and seal of the Court, or such amount be placed to the credit of the Assessor and Collector of Taxes of such county, upon his payment into the Treasury of his county, the amount so appropriated to such county, and filing the receipt of the county Treasurer acknowledged by the said Treasurer before the Clerk of the County Court, and by the said Clerk, duly certified under his hand and the seal of his Court, with the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer of the State.</p>
<p>Sec. 4. That it shall be the duty of the County Court, annually, to apportion the said school fund among the children between the ages of six and eighteen years, who may attend any school in their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />spective counties, in proportion to the time that each child has been taught, upon the teacher&#8217;s filing with the County Clerk, an affidavit, signed and sworn to by himself, before some officer authorized to ad<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />minister oaths as to the number of children taught, and the time they received instruction. And said schools are hereby declared &#8220;free public schools;&#8221; provided, that, no child whose entire tuition has <pb n="527" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="109" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>been paid, shall receive any money under the provision of this sec<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion.</p>
<p>Sec. 5. That the teacher of each school shall be required to keep a day book, and at the close of his term of teaching shall furnish the County Court with a tabular statement of the names of all the patrons and pupils of the school, the number of pupils sent by each person, and the number of days each pupil attended school, which statement shall be supported by his affidavit, made before some of<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ficer authorized to administer oaths, that the same is true arid cor<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />rect. And he shall further make affidavit, supported by the certifi<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />cate of two responsible house-holding patrons of his school, that he has taught said school for a period of not less than three months. And upon his failure to make said report, he shall forfeit all claim for compensation for services rendered under this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 6. That the County Treasurer of each county shall give bond, with two or more securities, payable to the county in twice the amount of the school fund to which the county shall be entitled, so soon as the Chief-Justice shall be notified by the Treasurer of the State, of the amount to which his county is entitled, which bond shall be conditioned, that he will well, and faithfully keep an ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />count of the money to him committed, as a school fund for his coun<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ty, and pay over the same, only upon the order of the Chief-Justice of the county, under his hand and the seal of the County Court. He shall keep an accurate account of all monies received and paid out by him, to register and number all orders by him paid or accepted, to be paid. He shall, between the first and tenth of the fiscal month of the Treasury of each year, renew his bond; and all suits upon such bonds shall be in the name of the county, and in other respects they shall be governed by the laws regulating the bonds of county Treasurers. If any person or patron of any school is un<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />able to pay his tuition, and the teacher shall be satisfied of the fact, it shall be the duty of said teacher to make out a list of all such patrons together with the amount of money due from each for tui<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, and forward the same under oath to the Chief-Justice of the county.</p>
<p>Sec. 7. The Treasurer of the State shall be ex-officio Superintendent of schools. It shall be his duty, after the first day of the fiscal mouth, in each and every year, to record the abstracts of children of lawful age in different counties, apportion the monies as herein contemplated, distributing to the several counties the amount to which each is entitled, ac<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" /><pb n="528" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="110" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>cording to its scholastic population. And it shall be the duty of the Treasurer to keep a correct account of all the monies and matters appertaining to the school fund, and report to the Governor annual<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />ly, at the close of the heal year, the condition of the school fund, distribution of monies, and such suggestions in regard to the School System as may be deemed advisable. That the fiscal scholastic year shall commence and end upon the fiscal year of the State Treasury. That the County Court of each County, after ascertaining that the patrons returned are unable to pay the tuition, shall make a return of the same to the State Treasurer, who, upon the order of the County Court, under the seal of their offices, in favor of the county, shall pay over to said County Courts their distributive shares of the interest of the School fund; and the County Courts on receiving the same, shall proceed to distribute the same, as required by this act; first providing for those children whose tuition has not been paid from inability of the patrons; provided, that orphan children, and children of widows, who have no other or greater amount of prop<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />erty than is exempted from forced sale, be considered indigent.</p>
<p>Sec. 8. That the Assessor and Collector of each county, for the year 1856 and all succeeding years, shall receive for his compensa<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />tion, for discharging the duties imposed upon him by this act, twelve cents per child for two hundred children and less; eight cents per child for all less than three hundred and more than two hundred; six cents per child for all less than four hundred and more than three hundred; five cents per child for all lets than five hundred and more than four hundred; four cents per child for all less than a thousand and more than five hundred; three cents per child for two thousand and more than one thousand; two cents for all over two thousand. And should the Assessor and Collector refuse or fail to take and report the census of the children as required by this act, he shall forfeit the whole of the compensation allowed, and be fined not less than twenty-five nor more than one hundred dol<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lars, at the discretion of the County Court; and in case of failure from any cause whatever, of the Assessor and Col<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />lector, in making a report of the census of his respective county, to the County Clerk, on or before the first day of July, in each year, the County Court shall be authorized to appoint some suitable person to perform said labor, who shall be entitled to the same compensation as allowed to Assessors and Collectors, under this act; provided, he makes his returns by the first <pb n="529" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="111" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>day of September following. Assessors and Collectors, or other persons appointed to take the census of scholastic population, shall not be entitled to Compensation for their services, unless their re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns are made within the time prescribed by this act.</p>
<p>Sec. 9. That the counties which have not heretofore received their share of the Special School Fund for either years 1854 or 1855 from failure to make returns of their scholastic population, shall be entitled to receive the same upon the following basis, to wit: Those counties that made returns for the year 1854, but none for 1855, shall be allowed an addition of five per cent to the returns of 1854, and the result be placed to the credit of such counties as their share of the fund for 1855. Those counties that made re<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />turns for 1855, but failed for the year 1854, five per cent shall be deducted from the return of 1855, and the result be placed to the credit of such counties as their share of the fund for 1854. Those counties that have failed entirely to make returns, shall upon their making due returns for some present year, be allowed a credit for the years so failing, by deducting from the number of children for the year returned, such annual per centage of increase as the aggre<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />gate returns of all the counties shown to be increase back to the year 1854. When the Assessor and Collector, or person appointed under the provisions of the previous section, shall fail to make and have on file in the Treasurer&#8217;s office, by the first of the fiscal month of the Treasury, of each year, returns of the scholastic population of their respective counties, the census returns of such counties, for the previous year, shall be taken as the basis of distribution to such counties and the amount so set aside shall be paid to such counties without regard to returns that may be made to the Treas<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />urer&#8217;s office, after the date above mentioned.</p>
<p>Sec. 10. The Treasurer of the State shall send to each County Court and to each Assessor and Collector, a copy of this law, and require from each Court an annual report of the number of schools, the number of children, the disposition of the fund, and such other information as will give a Correct idea of the condition of the schools.</p>
<p>Sec. 11. The provisions of this act shall only extend to such children as are actually sent to schools of the State. That no school shall be entitled to the benefits of this act unless the English lan<pc force="weak">-</pc><lb break="no" />guage is taught therein.</p>
<pb n="530" ed="gammelslawsoftexas" /><pb ed="unknown" n="112" /><fw type="header" place="top">Laws of the State of Texas.</fw>
<p>Sec. 12. That all laws conflicting with the provisions of this act, be, and the same are hereby thus far repealed. And that this act take effect and be in force from and after its passage.</p>
<closer>
<dateline>Approved, <date>29th August, 1856</date>.</dateline>
</closer>
</div2>
</div1>
</body>
</text>
